<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/rss2full.xsl"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" xmlns:creativeCommons="http://backend.userland.com/creativeCommonsRssModule" xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" version="2.0">

<channel>
	<title>Goizueta Newsroom</title>
	
	<link>https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr</link>
	<description>News and notes from Emory's Goizueta Business School</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2011 14:55:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.1</generator>
		<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/GoizuetaNewsroom" /><feedburner:info uri="goizuetanewsroom" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" /><creativeCommons:license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.0/</creativeCommons:license><feedburner:emailServiceId>GoizuetaNewsroom</feedburner:emailServiceId><feedburner:feedburnerHostname>http://feedburner.google.com</feedburner:feedburnerHostname><item>
		<title>Analysts Might Herd, But Don't Trample</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/GoizuetaNewsroom/~3/PbbiUCx5IAY/</link>
		<comments>https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/2011/09/06/analysts-might-herd-but-don%e2%80%99t-trample-investors/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2011 14:50:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Goizueta Newsroom</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Academics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Faculty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Knowledge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[People]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Story]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Narasimhan Jegadeesh]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Review of Financial Studies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Warren Buffett]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Woojin Kim]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/?p=2846</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p> </p> <p> </p> <p> </p> <p></p> <p class="wp-caption-text">Stock analysts—especially those at large brokerage firms—are known for their herding tendencies. PHOTO: brian glanz/Flickr.com </p> <p></p> <p> </p> <p> </p> <p>Stock analysts — especially those at large brokerage firms — are known for their herding tendencies, but stock buyers need not be overly concerned at <span style="color:#777"> . . . &#8594; Read More: <a href="https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/2011/09/06/analysts-might-herd-but-don%e2%80%99t-trample-investors/">Analysts Might Herd, But Don't Trample</a></span>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em> </em></p>
<p><em> </em></p>
<p><em> </em></p>
<p><em></p>
<div id="attachment_2851" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/brianglanz/278923888/sizes/m/in/photostream/"><img class="size-full wp-image-2851 " style="margin: 10px" src="https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/files/2011/09/stockexchange082511.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Stock analysts—especially those at large brokerage firms—are known for their herding tendencies. PHOTO: brian glanz/Flickr.com </p></div>
<p></em></p>
<p><em> </em></p>
<p><em> </em></p>
<p><em>Stock analysts — especially those at large brokerage firms — are known for their herding tendencies, but stock buyers need not be overly concerned at the possible destabilizing effects on stock prices, argue <a href="http://www.goizueta.emory.edu/faculty/NarasimhanJegadeesh/">Narasimhan Jegadeesh</a>, Dean's Distinguished Chair of Finance at Emory University's Goizueta Business School, and colleague Woojin Kim of Korea University. Their research, presented in a paper titled "Do Analysts Herd? An Analysis of Recommendations and Market Reactions," shows that the market anticipates analysts' herding proclivities and "responds appropriately." Analyzing data from over two decades of stock price movements and analyst recommendations, the researchers found that investors seem to pay more attention to recommendations that go against the grain, compensating in part for any herding that pushes investors away from a true valuation of a stock based on company fundamentals. Their research suggests that market commentators should be wary of overstating the importance of herding as a major cause of market ills.</em></p>
<p><em> </em><br />
When the &#8220;dot.com&#8221; bubble started to burst in March 2000, those who'd been disbelievers in the high-flying sector <a href="http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/business/1217716.stm">pounced</a>. In his widely watched annual letter in April 2001, Warren Buffett <a href="http://www.berkshirehathaway.com/letters/2000pdf.pdf">wrote</a> that "it was as if some virus, racing wildly among investment professionals as well as amateurs, induced hallucinations in which the value of stocks in certain sectors became decoupled from the values of the businesses that underlay them." In the bubble's post-mortem, some suggested that what Buffett described as a virus might better be explained in terms of "herding"—the tendency for different agents making individual decisions to nonetheless take similar actions at roughly the same time. The theory was that many stock analysts had talked up dot.com stocks to keep pace with their peers, thereby stoking demand that ultimately resulted in excess volatility when the bubble burst.</p>
<p>But in a paper recently published in the <em>Review of Financial Studies</em>, <a href="http://www.goizueta.emory.edu/faculty/narasimhanjegadeesh/index.html">Narasimhan Jegadeesh</a> at Emory University's <a href="http://www.goizueta.emory.edu/">Goizueta Business School</a> argues that any ill effect from herding by analysts is usually blunted because investors are well aware of the tendency. In a paper titled "Do Analysts Herd? An Analysis of Recommendations and Market Reactions," Jegadeesh and colleague Woojin Kim of Korea University analyzed stock price movements and analyst recommendations for some 5,714 firms between 1993 and 2005. They found that investors seem to pay much more attention to analyst recommendations that go against the grain. That contrasts with changes that move toward the consensus viewpoint, which don't drive as much action by investors. Stock buyers, in other words, are careful not to get trampled by the herd.</p>
<p>"The market is smart enough not to blindly follow analysts," says Jegadeesh, who is the Dean's Distinguished Chair of Finance at Goizueta. "The market seems to understand that analysts have some incentives to herd, and the market responds appropriately."</p>
<p>There are two broad reasons that individuals might herd, Jegadeesh says. The first stems from information. An earnings announcement with positive news about a company's revenue or net income might prompt many analysts to up their earnings estimates for the firm at around the same time. Analysts who rationally incorporate the latest financial results from the same information source will come to similar conclusions about the company's direction. But a second reason for herding is not so benign. Individuals might herd because they are responding to incentives that encourage imitation. Previous research, for example, has suggested that analysts with low abilities often issue earnings forecasts that mimic those of superior analysts, all in hopes of winning more compensation.</p>
<p>"If agents act similarly only because of common information, then their actions result from rational and optimal use of information, and they are not influenced by extraneous incentives or biases," the researchers write. "On the other hand, if agents herd for any other reason, then their actions differ from the action that one would take if he or she uses available information rationally without any influence of extraneous incentives or biases . . . Non-information-driven herding could introduce noise in prices, and contribute to excess volatility that many view as undesirable."</p>
<p>Analysts typically rate stocks as "strong buy," "buy," "hold," "sell," or "strong sell." To investigate whether analysts herd when they make changes among these five recommendation levels, the researchers tracked 71,555 upgrades and downgrades issued by analysts on the stocks of 5,714 firms between 1993 and 2005. The sample included all firms that had at least two active recommendations from analysts during the time period, including at least one revision. The 6,588 analysts in the sample came from a variety of brokerages ranging from one-analyst shops to large players like Merrill Lynch and Morgan Stanley. The researchers looked companies' "abnormal returns," meaning the change in the stocks' value relative to changes in the value of the broader index, around recommendation changes.</p>
<p>Overall, the researchers found that analyst upgrades corresponded with a 1.97 percent abnormal returns on the day of the upgrade. Analyst downgrades corresponded with a 3.22 percent decline in abnormal returns on the day of the downgrade. The impact was significantly different when recommendation changes moved toward the consensus view relative to when they moved away from the consensus view. In the case of upgrades, the average abnormal returns was 1.75 percent when recommendations moved toward the consensus and 2.15 percent when the upgrade moved away from the consensus. The effect was more dramatic with downgrades. The average abnormal returns were –2.4 percent when the downgrade moved toward the consensus and –4 percent when the downgrade moved against the consensus.</p>
<p>The study also offers information about which analysts are more likely to herd, and when they are more likely to do so. There is no difference, for example, in the herding tendencies of all-star analysts, lead analysts, and other analysts, the researchers found. Analysts who make frequent revisions to their recommendations, however, were less likely to herd. And analysts were less likely to herd when evaluating stocks where there was a broad range of recommendations. Analysts from large, reputable brokerages were more likely to herd, the study suggests.</p>
<p>Regulation also had an influence. In the fourth quarter of 2002, ten major brokerages struck a global settlement with state and federal officials that erected barriers between the investment banking activities of brokerages and their stock research departments. In the time following the settlement, analysts were less likely to herd. This suggests that currying favor with potential investment banking clients might have contributed to herding incentives prior to 2002, the researchers write. Even so, the primary take-away as to the deleterious influence of herding on market prices is that the practice isn't that worrisome. The study found that a large part of the stock price response to recommendation revisions occurred on the day of the change, and market prices continued to reflect information in the revisions for up to six months into the future. If the revisions had been driven by an impulse to herd that pushed investors away from a true valuation of the stock based on the fundamentals of the company, the study results would have found corrections in market prices at some point following the changes, Jegadeesh says.</p>
<p>"Media accounts and some academic papers have suggested that analysts' herding tendencies could introduce noise into prices because the market could potentially overweight the common mistakes of the herd," the study authors write. "However, our results indicate that the market anticipates analysts' tendencies to herd, and the market price reaction on the revision date accounts for such herding tendencies. Therefore, we doubt that herding by analysts when they make recommendations would have any destabilizing effect on prices."</p>
<p>The study suggests that downgrades that go against the consensus amount to higher-profile acts that are more likely to significantly move the stock price. In general, analysts seem to be more reluctant to stand out from the crowd when they convey negative information, although it depends on who they work for, the research suggests. Analysts from less prestigious firms might be more willing to offer such recommendations because they are "underdog" players who want to attract attention in the market, Jegadeesh says. Such downgrades might be less common from large brokerage houses where analysts seem more risk averse and are more cautious about offering recommendation changes that could possibly make them look bad. But whatever the motives of analysts, the study suggests that commentators should not overstate the importance of herding when looking for the cause of market ills.</p>
<p>"It's not what analysts were saying that drove the tech bubble," Jegadeesh says. The study didn't set out to explain what caused the dot.com bubble, but Jegadeesh points out that "it could be that investors were looking at their neighbors who were buying those stocks and saying 'I want to do this' . . .  sometimes things turn out better than we expect, sometimes things turn out worse."</p>
<p><strong><br />
RELATED CONTENT:</strong></p>
<p><strong><a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052748704425804576220983131318962.html?KEYWORDS=herding">WSJ: Investment Strategy: All About the Benjamins<br />
</a><a href="http://blogs.forbes.com/martinzwilling/2011/03/25/avoid-startup-opportunity-bubbles-ready-to-burst/"><em>Forbes</em>: Avoid Startup Opportunity Bubbles Ready To Burst<br />
</a><a href="http://knowledge.emory.edu/article.cfm?articleid=1013">K@E: How Boldness and Accuracy Affect Analyst Credibility</a></strong></p>
<p><em><br />
</em></p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?a=PbbiUCx5IAY:8-axnkyBaxA:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?a=PbbiUCx5IAY:8-axnkyBaxA:F7zBnMyn0Lo"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?i=PbbiUCx5IAY:8-axnkyBaxA:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?a=PbbiUCx5IAY:8-axnkyBaxA:V_sGLiPBpWU"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?i=PbbiUCx5IAY:8-axnkyBaxA:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?a=PbbiUCx5IAY:8-axnkyBaxA:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?a=PbbiUCx5IAY:8-axnkyBaxA:gIN9vFwOqvQ"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?i=PbbiUCx5IAY:8-axnkyBaxA:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/GoizuetaNewsroom/~4/PbbiUCx5IAY" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/2011/09/06/analysts-might-herd-but-don%e2%80%99t-trample-investors/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/2011/09/06/analysts-might-herd-but-don%e2%80%99t-trample-investors/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Sharing Knowledge to Remain Agile</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/GoizuetaNewsroom/~3/h3l8awEUxFA/</link>
		<comments>https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/2011/09/06/sharing-knowledge-to-remain-agile/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2011 11:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Goizueta Newsroom</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Faculty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Knowledge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[People]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Benn Konsysnki]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[David Bennet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mountain Quest Institute]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nowledge Futures: The Agility Imperative]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/?p=2857</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Organizations trying to weather an increasingly multilayered and erratic environment must first evaluate how they manage and distribute information to promote collective intelligence.</p> <p>"Knowledge is the capacity to take effective action," says David Bennet, co-founder of the Mountain Quest Institute, a research and learning center in Frost, WV. "It is a critical part in <span style="color:#777"> . . . &#8594; Read More: <a href="https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/2011/09/06/sharing-knowledge-to-remain-agile/">Sharing Knowledge to Remain Agile</a></span>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Organizations trying to weather an increasingly multilayered and erratic environment must first evaluate how they manage and distribute information to promote collective intelligence.</p>
<p>"Knowledge is the capacity to take effective action," says David Bennet, co-founder of the Mountain Quest Institute, a research and learning center in Frost, WV. "It is a critical part in dealing with uncertainty and complexity. You can share knowledge, you can leverage it, you can sculpt it, and you can apply it. Knowledge changes over time."</p>
<p>Speaking at the recent <a href="http://agilityimperative.com/blog/knowledge-futures-forum-2011-agility-imperative-march-18-19-2011">Knowledge Futures: The Agility Imperative</a> symposium held at <a href="http://www.goizueta.emory.edu/">Goizueta Business School</a>, Bennet joined executives from IBM and the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) to discuss "The Future of the Organization" in a panel moderated by <a href="http://www.goizueta.emory.edu/">Benn Konsynski</a>, George S. Craft Professor of Information Systems &amp; Operations Management.</p>
<p>Time-strapped managers can improve productivity and responsiveness through knowledge sharing, intuitive reasoning, and the application of diverse skills, Bennet explains.</p>
<p>Other panelists advocated for bottom-up agility, particularly when projects span multiple time zones. Uniform project delivery standards for global partners, for instance, must be tweaked to reflect cultural conditions on the ground, explains Steve DelGrosso, director of the Project Management Center of Excellence at IBM Global Business Services.</p>
<p>"Our biggest target for agility is how we apply resources within IBM," he says.</p>
<p>Mark White, deputy director of the CDC's Division of Public Health Capacity Development, says the CDC has gained valuable public health information by partnering with local ministries of health in training and data collection methods.</p>
<p>"One of the core issues from an agility standpoint is, how do I amplify a weak signal as quickly as possible and decide an effective pattern of response to a problem?" notes Konsynski. "It extends to the extra-organizational level. The tools for sensing and responding are not always owned or controlled by the organization."</p>
<p><strong>To view the video of the discussion, click <a href="http://www.learnitlive.com/event/789/Agility-Imperative">here</a>.</strong></p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?a=h3l8awEUxFA:P28kitOA6Ok:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?a=h3l8awEUxFA:P28kitOA6Ok:F7zBnMyn0Lo"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?i=h3l8awEUxFA:P28kitOA6Ok:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?a=h3l8awEUxFA:P28kitOA6Ok:V_sGLiPBpWU"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?i=h3l8awEUxFA:P28kitOA6Ok:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?a=h3l8awEUxFA:P28kitOA6Ok:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?a=h3l8awEUxFA:P28kitOA6Ok:gIN9vFwOqvQ"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?i=h3l8awEUxFA:P28kitOA6Ok:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/GoizuetaNewsroom/~4/h3l8awEUxFA" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/2011/09/06/sharing-knowledge-to-remain-agile/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/2011/09/06/sharing-knowledge-to-remain-agile/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Creating "Living Standards" in Uncertain Climate</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/GoizuetaNewsroom/~3/dIqDRDpxH9k/</link>
		<comments>https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/2011/09/05/creating-%e2%80%9cliving-standards%e2%80%9d-in-uncertain-climate/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2011 17:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Goizueta Newsroom</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Faculty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Knowledge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[People]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Story]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dominic Thomas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Knowledge Futures: The Agility Imperative]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/?p=2859</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Standards help frame our world, from organizing labor pools, to fostering trade relations, to opening up communication channels. Blind allegiance to standards, however, can compromise collaboration, cripple innovation, and cause business leaders to temporarily forget why they adopted the protocol in the first place.</p> <p>In a recent Q&#38;A, Dominic Thomas, adjunct assistant professor of <span style="color:#777"> . . . &#8594; Read More: <a href="https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/2011/09/05/creating-%e2%80%9cliving-standards%e2%80%9d-in-uncertain-climate/">Creating "Living Standards" in Uncertain Climate</a></span>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Standards help frame our world, from organizing labor pools, to fostering trade relations, to opening up communication channels. Blind allegiance to standards, however, can compromise collaboration, cripple innovation, and cause business leaders to temporarily forget why they adopted the protocol in the first place.</p>
<p>In a recent Q&amp;A, <a href="http://www.goizueta.emory.edu/faculty/dominicthomas/index.html">Dominic Thomas</a>, adjunct assistant professor of information systems and operations management at Emory University's <a href="http://www.goizueta.emory.edu/">Goizueta Business School</a>, discusses the breakdown of the organizational status quo in uncertain environments, prompting companies to craft and use standards that enable agile coordination. Thomas recently moderated a panel discussion, "Crossing Barriers: Coordination and Standards," as part of the <a href="http://agilityimperative.com/blog/knowledge-futures-forum-2011-agility-imperative-march-18-19-2011">Knowledge Futures: The Agility Imperative</a> symposium held at Goizueta. Joining him in the talk were senior decision makers from the government and private sectors, including the Federal Aviation Administration, CARE, and The World Bank.</p>
<p><strong>Newsroom: </strong>The process of leveraging collective intelligence to respond to crisis situations can be tremendously inefficient but also tremendously effective. Can too much consensus building lead to inaction, and if so, what can an organization do to counterbalance this?</p>
<p><strong>Thomas: </strong>Yes. People need to only <em>block</em> a consensus process when there is a legitimate "blocking concern," yet many fail to recognize the distinction between blocking concerns and any concern. I serve on a board that uses a formal consensus process, and I have seen the impact of making individuals commit to explicitly naming their blocking concerns. I believe the process works efficiently as a result. That said, I have not seen the process carried out in this manner anywhere else. As technologies and norms for using them evolve, we have new opportunities to identify patterns through collective intelligence, with less energy required during crisis situations. Businesses can implement such ideas internally, too, and they are beginning to do so. As they do, they will benefit from identifying methods to collaborate and cooperate in a timely manner.</p>
<p><strong>Newsroom:</strong> What steps should an organization take to draft standards that are more responsive and relevant to changing environments?</p>
<p><strong>Thomas: </strong>During our discussion, we heard several good suggestions about creating <em>living</em> standards. First of all, allow for multiple drafts of a standard from the start, so that people expect it to evolve, as in the PDF standard used for portable, digital documents. Second, govern standards in an open format with the participation of those impacted. Third, make the context of the standard explicit and provide a process for overriding the standard. Finally, as a standard evolves, be careful to distinguish compatible and incompatible versions of that standard. In organizational cooperation memoranda, these distinctions are rarely identified. As a result, I suspect we see a proliferation of policies not clearly linked to any history or organizational need.</p>
<p><strong>To view the video of the "Crossing Barriers: Coordination and Standards" panel discussion, click <a href="http://www.learnitlive.com/event/789/Agility-Imperative">here</a>.</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?a=dIqDRDpxH9k:XYQ1Iu3qSr0:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?a=dIqDRDpxH9k:XYQ1Iu3qSr0:F7zBnMyn0Lo"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?i=dIqDRDpxH9k:XYQ1Iu3qSr0:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?a=dIqDRDpxH9k:XYQ1Iu3qSr0:V_sGLiPBpWU"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?i=dIqDRDpxH9k:XYQ1Iu3qSr0:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?a=dIqDRDpxH9k:XYQ1Iu3qSr0:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?a=dIqDRDpxH9k:XYQ1Iu3qSr0:gIN9vFwOqvQ"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?i=dIqDRDpxH9k:XYQ1Iu3qSr0:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/GoizuetaNewsroom/~4/dIqDRDpxH9k" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/2011/09/05/creating-%e2%80%9cliving-standards%e2%80%9d-in-uncertain-climate/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/2011/09/05/creating-%e2%80%9cliving-standards%e2%80%9d-in-uncertain-climate/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Indian Ambassador Examines 'Why India Matters'</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/GoizuetaNewsroom/~3/2_f1omcyI6g/</link>
		<comments>https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/2011/09/01/indian-ambassador-examines-why-india-matters/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 17:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Goizueta Newsroom</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Current Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Knowledge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Benn Konsynski]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Emerging India Summit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Halle Institute]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jagdish Sheth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Meera Shankar]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/?p=2839</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Meera Shankar, India's ambassador to the U.S., recently delivered the keynote address at Emory University's Emerging India Summit, offering a panoply of reasons for why India matters—to the U.S. and to the global economic order. It is the world's largest democracy, with an electorate of more than 700 million people, a rapidly expanding market, <span style="color:#777"> . . . &#8594; Read More: <a href="https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/2011/09/01/indian-ambassador-examines-why-india-matters/">Indian Ambassador Examines &#8216;Why India Matters&#8217;</a></span>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em><a href="http://halleinstitute.emory.edu/eis/images/shankar.jpg"><img class="alignright" style="margin: 10px" src="http://halleinstitute.emory.edu/eis/images/shankar.jpg" alt="Meera Shankar" width="124" height="167" /></a>Meera Shankar, India's ambassador to the U.S., recently delivered the keynote address at Emory University's Emerging India Summit, offering a panoply of reasons for why India matters—to the U.S. and to the global economic order. It is the world's largest democracy, with an electorate of more than 700 million people, a rapidly expanding market, a land of astonishing diversity and enterpreneurial energy, and the world's second-fastest growing economy. "India is confident and aware of its capabilities," says Shankar. "Our key national priority is to have sustained rapid and inclusive economic growth while ensuring that the fruits of our economic development reach all sections of society." Quoting U.S. President Barack Obama, Shankar emphasized that "increased economic interaction between India and the United States can be a win-win proposition."</em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>India, capitalizing on expanding domestic demand and an increasingly skilled, innovative workforce, is poised to become an anchor of stability and opportunity in the global economy.</p>
<p>"The choices that Indians make or do not make, the products they consume, the ideas they embrace will not only have significance within India but in the wider world, "says <a href="http://www.indianembassy.org/ambassador.php">Meera Shankar</a>, India's ambassador to the U.S.</p>
<p>Speaking at the recent Emerging India Summit held at <a href="http://www.goizueta.emory.edu/">Goizueta Business School</a> and Emory's <a href="http://www.law.emory.edu/">School of Law</a>, Shankar discussed "<a href="http://www.casttv.com/video/aay2sv3/emerging-india-summit-2011-meera-shankar-why-india-matters-video">Why India Matters</a>" in her <a href="http://www.indianembassy.org/prdetail1685/keynote-address-by-ambassador-meera-shankar-at-emory-universityandrsquo%3Bs-emerging-india-summit-on-24th-february-2011-andquot%3Bwhy-india-mattersandquot%3B">keynote address</a> exploring the country's demographics, strategic alliances, market potential and workforce development. Other speakers at the two-day event, including <a href="http://www.goizueta.emory.edu/faculty/bennkonsynski/index.html">Benn Konsynski</a>, George S. Craft Professor of O&amp;M; <a href="http://www.goizueta.emory.edu/faculty/jagdishsheth/index.html">Jagdish Sheth</a>, Charles H. Kellstadt Professor of Marketing; and <a href="http://halleinstitute.emory.edu/Visiting%20Scholars/vivek.html">Vivek Wadhwa</a>, Distinguished Visiting Scholar for Emory's <a href="http://halleinstitute.emory.edu/">Halle Institute</a>, reflected on India's <a href="http://www.emory.edu/EMORY_REPORT/stories/2011/03/soundbites_emerging_india_summit.html">comparative economic advantages</a> and disadvantages, military strategies, market innovations and the future of Indo-U.S. relations.</p>
<p>"India is defying gravity and becoming a global R&amp;D hub," says Wadhwa. "Its entrepreneurs are beginning to build world-class companies with innovative breakthrough technologies."</p>
<p>Organized by the student-led Emerging India Forum, the Halle Institute, and Goizueta and Emory College faculty, the summit strengthens Emory's brand name recognition in India while encouraging dialogue on campus about Indian affairs.</p>
<p><strong><br />
India's Growth Story</strong></p>
<p>If India's current growth rate continues, income levels will nearly triple and India will represent the world's fifth-largest consumer market by 2025, says Shankar, citing a recent McKinsey &amp; Company <a href="http://www.mckinsey.com/mgi/publications/india_consumer_market/slideshow/main.asp">study</a>.</p>
<p>"Businesses that can meet the needs of India's aspiring middle class, keep price points low to reflect the realities of Indian incomes, and adapt to the fast-changing market environment will find substantial rewards in India's rapidly growing consumer market," she adds.</p>
<p>India's cellular phone market, for instance, has exploded over the last decade to nearly 800 million subscribers, penetrating remote areas and lowering customer costs. Through cyber kiosks, farmers can now research weather information and evaluate produce prices in local markets.</p>
<p>The services sector has propelled India to become a solutions hub, a base for conducting sophisticated R&amp;D and technology innovation, notes Shankar. Indian pharmaceutical companies are providing affordable vaccines, and telemedicine allows patients from every corner of the world to access top-notch medical facilities.</p>
<p>The multinational IT sector has effectively leveraged India's large pool of skilled workers to increase profitability and competitiveness, she continues.</p>
<p>At the same time, India has an increasing stake in ensuring a stable global order.</p>
<p>"We see our relationship with the U.S., which is one of our largest trade, investment and technology partners, as a vital element of our endeavor to transform our socioeconomic conditions," Shankar says. "The highly successful visit of President Obama to India last November has significantly expanded and deepened our cooperation."</p>
<p>Similarly, both countries have committed to improving agricultural productivity in several African nations. Nourishing the Indo-U.S. relationship are the nearly 3 million Indian Americans who serve as an important bridge, Shankar says.</p>
<p><strong><br />
India in 2025</strong></p>
<p>Sheth notes that India's impressive growth record will not only provide burgeoning consumer markets but will also expand the country's significant role as an economic engine and geopolitical player by 2025.</p>
<p>Some of the largest global enterprises will be of Indian origin, predicts Sheth, including basic industries such as copper, steel, aluminum, and cement. This will be accomplished not by exports but through large global acquisitions.</p>
<p>Second, India will become the second-largest consumer market in certain products and services, such as motorcycles, appliances, beverages, and agricultural and dairy products, surpassing the U.S., Japan, and Germany.</p>
<p>Citing India's business dealings with Bolivia, Peru, Iran, and other countries, Sheth expects that India will continue to "partner with strange bedfellows in search of industrial, agricultural, energy, and talent resources around the world."</p>
<p><strong><br />
Challenges Ahead</strong></p>
<p>India's vibrant secular democracy and development go hand in hand, Shankar says. Rather than adopt an export-driven strategy, the country has benefited from rising urban and rural incomes and a sharp increase in savings and investment rates.</p>
<p>"Today, the fact that we have a <a href="http://presidentofindia.nic.in/profile.html">woman head of state</a>, a <a href="http://www.thecommonwealth.org/YearbookInternal/172024/head_of_government/">Sikh head of government</a>, and a <a href="http://india.gov.in/govt/biodata.php">Muslim vice president</a> is perhaps the best statement of the multi-ethnic and multi-religious nature of our state," she says.</p>
<p>When India gained its independence in 1947, two centuries of foreign rule had reduced the country from one of the world's largest economies to one of its poorest. Today, a large percentage of the population continues to live below the poverty line, and agricultural incomes are not keeping pace with other economic sectors. The agriculture industry employs more than half of the population, but only generates 16 percent of the GDP.</p>
<p>With the majority of India's population under age 65, it is estimated that the country will require an investment of nearly $1.7 trillion over the next decade to upgrade public infrastructure and educational and training facilities, says Shankar.</p>
<p>"This represents a huge opportunity for our international partners," she adds.</p>
<p>Mark Twain once described India as the "cradle of the human race, the birthplace of human speech, the mother of history, the grandmother of legend, and the great-grandmother of tradition."</p>
<p>"Allowing for some literary exaggeration," says Shankar, "he got the big picture right."</p>
<p><strong><br />
RELATED CONTENT:</strong></p>
<p><strong><a href="http://money.cnn.com/2011/02/17/news/international/india_growth_challenges.fortune/index.htm">CNNMoney: India Won&#8217;t Outpace China without a Few Miracles<br />
</a><a href="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/72cfefca-553a-11e0-87fe-00144feab49a.html#axzz1HjsdjEWy"><em>Financial Times</em>: Powerhouse Economies Lure Staff<br />
</a><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VkGqbnGoRLI">Emerging India Summit: Video of Panel on India&#8217;s Regional and Global Challenges<br />
</a><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2nxbwADUIiA">Emerging India Summit: Video of Lecture on Future of Indo-U.S. Cooperation</a></strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?a=2_f1omcyI6g:vsgRwbx7Ulg:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?a=2_f1omcyI6g:vsgRwbx7Ulg:F7zBnMyn0Lo"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?i=2_f1omcyI6g:vsgRwbx7Ulg:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?a=2_f1omcyI6g:vsgRwbx7Ulg:V_sGLiPBpWU"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?i=2_f1omcyI6g:vsgRwbx7Ulg:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?a=2_f1omcyI6g:vsgRwbx7Ulg:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?a=2_f1omcyI6g:vsgRwbx7Ulg:gIN9vFwOqvQ"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?i=2_f1omcyI6g:vsgRwbx7Ulg:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/GoizuetaNewsroom/~4/2_f1omcyI6g" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/2011/09/01/indian-ambassador-examines-why-india-matters/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/2011/09/01/indian-ambassador-examines-why-india-matters/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>AT&amp;T and T-Mobile Consolidation: Bane or Boon?</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/GoizuetaNewsroom/~3/sNZ52Y8lIrQ/</link>
		<comments>https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/2011/08/31/att-and-t-mobile-consolidation-bane-or-boon/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2011 11:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Goizueta Newsroom</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Current Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Faculty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Knowledge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[People]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AT&T]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jag Sheth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[merger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ram Chellapa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[T-Mobile]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/?p=2815</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p class="wp-caption-text">What can consumers expect with the AT&#38;T and T-Mobile merger? PHOTO: MrVJTod/Flickr.com</p> <p>Telecommunications giant AT&#38;T's $39 billion acquisition of T-Mobile USA Inc.— which is expected be completed in 2012 pending regulatory approvals and other issues — has sparked concerns over market competition and regulatory issues, chiefly centering on the question of whether the <span style="color:#777"> . . . &#8594; Read More: <a href="https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/2011/08/31/att-and-t-mobile-consolidation-bane-or-boon/">AT&#38;T and T-Mobile Consolidation: Bane or Boon?</a></span>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_2818" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/mrvjtod/322984903/sizes/m/in/photostream/"><img class="size-full wp-image-2818" src="https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/files/2011/08/att082511.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">What can consumers expect with the AT&amp;T and T-Mobile merger? PHOTO: MrVJTod/Flickr.com</p></div>
<p>Telecommunications giant AT&amp;T's $39 billion acquisition of T-Mobile USA Inc.— which is expected be completed in 2012 pending regulatory approvals and other issues — has sparked concerns over market competition and regulatory issues, chiefly centering on the question of whether the loss of a key company—leaving Verizon and Sprint Nextel Corp. as the only big-player alternatives—will mean higher prices for consumers.</p>
<p>But if the deal goes through its significance could go far beyond that issue, according to faculty from Emory University's <a href="http://www.goizueta.emory.edu/">Goizueta Business School</a>.</p>
<p>"I have my doubts about whether or not regulators will approve it," says <a href="http://www.bus.emory.edu/ram/">Ramnath K. Chellappa</a>, an associate professor and area doctoral coordinator in information systems and operations management at Goizueta. "There would be too much market concentration. Right now, things are all right with the big four of AT&amp;T, Verizon, T-Mobile and Sprint."</p>
<p>He acknowledges that federal regulators gave their blessing to significant consolidation in another big industry, airlines, but says the Obama administration might not be so comfortable with limiting the market.</p>
<p>"Clearly there would be some issues," Chellappa notes. "Anytime you reduce competition, there's a reduction in social welfare."</p>
<p>The collateral damage wouldn't be limited to residential customers, he adds.</p>
<p>"Business customers might be at risk," says Chellappa. "Right now T-Mobile's data rate tends to be higher than AT&amp;T's, so business customers have some choice. If AT&amp;T takes over T-Mobile, the odds are that the data rates would be raised to T-Mobile's level."</p>
<p>Some equipment manufacturers might also be hurt, Chellappa adds,</p>
<p>"T-Mobile and AT&amp;T both use GSM carrier technology, while Verizon and Sprint use CDMA technology," he observes. "If AT&amp;T gets a monopoly, they could probably squeeze the equipment manufacturers who specialize in GSM."</p>
<p>But another Goizueta professor thinks the transaction will likely be completed.</p>
<p>In fact will be followed by further consolidation, will actually mean more consumer choice, and in any case was almost inevitable in a world where more and more content is being transferred to wireless Internet, suggests<a href="http://www.goizueta.emory.edu/faculty/JagdishSheth/"> Jagdish N. Sheth</a>, a chaired marketing professor at Goizueta.</p>
<p>"On a global basis, telecommunications companies have been evolving as the convergence, or the unity, of telecom, cable and Internet, progresses," he says. "After the AT&amp;T and T-Mobile merger is completed, they will continue to evolve and expand to capture economies of scale."</p>
<p>AT&amp;T had to make a bid for T-Mobile, says Sheth, because if it didn't, "a non-U.S. carrier like Vodafone or Telefonica, or an investor like Carlos Slim, would have likely bought the company as a way to quickly gain significant market share in the U.S., boosting its global presence."</p>
<p>That move would have placed AT&amp;T, Verizon, and Sprint in jeopardy, according to Sheth, since U.S. carriers have been slow to expand their global capability.</p>
<p>"Right now, American consumers are being hurt because the U.S. carriers have not yet integrated their coverage with that of the global market," Sheth says. "That's why when Americans travel overseas and use their iPhones or other smartphone devices, they're usually saddled with a huge bill. A globally integrated company could avoid the roaming fees that are behind those kinds of big bills."</p>
<p>But in the telecommunications category, at least, consolidation isn't driven solely by issues of worldwide coverage—and that's why Sheth anticipates that the next big deal will involve two domestic companies: Sprint and Comcast.</p>
<p>"Increasingly, companies are placing more kinds of content on the Web," he says. "Print media has been forced to increase their Web content, and even television broadcasters are looking to stream more of their content on the Web and across mobile devices as a way to boost revenue. The pipeline, or means of getting it there, is irrelevant as long as the content is there and is reaching consumers across all channels of communication."</p>
<p>Thus, he says, "the real race among telecommunications firms is not simply who can provide the best and most extensive wireless coverage but is instead a struggle to see who will emerge as the major content provider across industry lines."</p>
<p>That means the race will be between wireless and cable providers, Sheth adds.</p>
<p>"So if the AT&amp;T and T-Mobile deal was a defensive one to protect AT&amp;T's U.S. territory from a global competitor, the next logical deal will be between Comcast and Sprint, as an offensive move to become a stronger, more comprehensive provider of content."</p>
<p>The move among providers to deliver more content will benefit consumers, Sheth says, even though the pricing models may change.</p>
<p>"These developments all follow the Rule of Three," Sheth notes, referring to a theory he developed to help explain the rise and fall of companies. "During the early growth stage of just about any industry, there are many competitors. For example, there were close to three hundred automobile manufacturers in the U.S. by 1915."</p>
<p>But as an industry matures, three firms that are better able to adapt will survive and thrive, typically commanding 70 percent to 90 percent of the market share, according to the Rule of Three. In the U.S., Chrysler, Ford, and General Motors evolved to dominate the auto market.</p>
<p>"Three companies typically become the generalists that each have more than 10 percent market share," Sheth explains. "They co-exist with numerous product/market/niche specialists that each have no more than five percent of the market share."</p>
<p>He sees the telecommunications market maintaining a flat-rate pricing structure but believes it will evolve into a hybrid one that takes a page from the utilities model.</p>
<p>"As more content requiring greater bandwidth is generated, telecommunication providers will probably begin offering peak and off-peak rates, much as they did in the early days, to incentivize consumers to spread out their usage and reduce peak demand," Sheth says. "Utility companies, for example, have long provided day rates and night rates."</p>
<p>He also thinks that more telecommunications providers will enter the market as large companies lease out space on their broadcast spectrum.</p>
<p>"You'll see the big three engaging in more wholesale (or spectrum-lease) activity, as well as retail (direct delivery)," he says. "That will mean more consumer choice and will likely keep a lid on pricing. I believe that, as predicted by the Rule of Three, you'll also see more niche players like Jitterbug that market their products to a specific group, such as the elderly."</p>
<p>As more content is delivered through Web and mobile pipelines, the telecommunications landscape is likely to continue to change, Sheth adds.</p>
<p>"But consumers don't need to worry about the change," he advises. "In the long run they'll benefit from it."</p>
<p><strong><br />
RELATED CONTENT:</strong></p>
<p><strong><a href="http://newsroom.t-mobile.com/articles/more-information-att-acquires-tmobile">Q&amp;A: More Information About AT&amp;T Acquisition of T-Mobile USA<br />
</a><a href="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/46eab1de-58a9-11e0-9b8a-00144feab49a.html#axzz1HuJKl2wl"><em>Financial Times</em>: Optimism over U.S. Spectrum Crunch<br />
</a><a href="http://tech.fortune.cnn.com/2011/03/22/the-upstart-company-that-made-the-att-mobile-merger-possible/">CNNMoney: The Upstart Company that Made the AT&amp;T/T-Mobile Merger Possible<br />
</a><a href="http://www.businessweek.com/news/2011-03-21/vodafone-european-operators-soar-on-at-t-s-t-mobile-valuation.html"><em>Businessweek</em>: Vodafone, European Operators Soar on AT&amp;T's T-Mobile Valuation<br />
</a><a href="http://news.consumerreports.org/electronics/2011/03/the-attt-mobile-merger-five-issues-for-consumers.html"><em>Consumer Reports</em>: The AT&amp;T/T-Mobile Merger: Five Issues for Consumers<br />
</a><a href="http://www.cbsnews.com/video/watch/?id=7360411n">CBSNews Video: AT&amp;T, T-Mobile Merger&#8217;s Impact on Consumers</a></strong></p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?a=sNZ52Y8lIrQ:TG0TcKdbz7k:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?a=sNZ52Y8lIrQ:TG0TcKdbz7k:F7zBnMyn0Lo"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?i=sNZ52Y8lIrQ:TG0TcKdbz7k:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?a=sNZ52Y8lIrQ:TG0TcKdbz7k:V_sGLiPBpWU"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?i=sNZ52Y8lIrQ:TG0TcKdbz7k:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?a=sNZ52Y8lIrQ:TG0TcKdbz7k:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?a=sNZ52Y8lIrQ:TG0TcKdbz7k:gIN9vFwOqvQ"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?i=sNZ52Y8lIrQ:TG0TcKdbz7k:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/GoizuetaNewsroom/~4/sNZ52Y8lIrQ" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/2011/08/31/att-and-t-mobile-consolidation-bane-or-boon/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/2011/08/31/att-and-t-mobile-consolidation-bane-or-boon/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Goizueta Mourns Loss of Two BBA Students</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/GoizuetaNewsroom/~3/Qg02XaYL2Hc/</link>
		<comments>https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/2011/08/30/goizueta-mourn-loss-of-two-bba-students/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2011 00:53:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>J. Michael Moore</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[BBA Program]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[People]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Programs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Students]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andrea Hershatter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Evan Lounsbury]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Joshua Busch]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/?p=2785</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>UPDATE AND EDITOR&#8217;S NOTE: A Service of Thanksgiving And Remembrance for the life of Evan Douglas Lounsbury will be held  at 4 p.m. Sept. 1 in Cannon Chapel (Emory University Campus) Details on memorial services or other actions to honor Busch will be posted when they become available.</p> <p>The Goizueta Business School community begins the <span style="color:#777"> . . . &#8594; Read More: <a href="https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/2011/08/30/goizueta-mourn-loss-of-two-bba-students/">Goizueta Mourns Loss of Two BBA Students</a></span>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>UPDATE AND EDITOR&#8217;S NOTE: A Service of Thanksgiving And Remembrance for the life of Evan Douglas Lounsbury will be held  at 4 p.m. Sept. 1 in Cannon Chapel (Emory University Campus) Details on memorial services or other actions to honor Busch will be posted when they become available.</em></p>
<p>The <a href="http://goizueta.emory.edu"> Goizueta Business School</a> community begins the academic year with a heavy heart. Two undergraduate students, <strong>Evan Lounsbury</strong> and <strong>Joshua Busch</strong>, died days before the start of Fall classes.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.goizueta.emory.edu/faculty/AndreaHershatter/">Andrea Hershatter</a>, Associate Dean and Director of the BBA Program, said memorials are being planned for each student &#8212; both in the Class of 2012.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.emorywheel.com/detail.php?n=29901" target="_blank">Lounsbury died after an automobile accident Aug. 19</a>. A finance and accounting major, Lounsbury was a native of Lexington, Ky. and a member of  Pi Kappa Alpha (Pike) fraternity at Emory.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.emorywheel.com/detail.php?n=29930" target="_blank">Busch passed away early last week</a>. An Emory Lacrosse player, Busch was also active in Alpha Kappa Psi and the Alternative Investments Group at Goizueta.</p>
<p>Grief counseling is available through the BBA office.</p>
<p><em><br />
</em></p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?a=Qg02XaYL2Hc:ZwJiMvRvV74:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?a=Qg02XaYL2Hc:ZwJiMvRvV74:F7zBnMyn0Lo"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?i=Qg02XaYL2Hc:ZwJiMvRvV74:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?a=Qg02XaYL2Hc:ZwJiMvRvV74:V_sGLiPBpWU"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?i=Qg02XaYL2Hc:ZwJiMvRvV74:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?a=Qg02XaYL2Hc:ZwJiMvRvV74:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?a=Qg02XaYL2Hc:ZwJiMvRvV74:gIN9vFwOqvQ"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?i=Qg02XaYL2Hc:ZwJiMvRvV74:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/GoizuetaNewsroom/~4/Qg02XaYL2Hc" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/2011/08/30/goizueta-mourn-loss-of-two-bba-students/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/2011/08/30/goizueta-mourn-loss-of-two-bba-students/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Who Decides Corporate Culture?</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/GoizuetaNewsroom/~3/EZeKcgmhJtg/</link>
		<comments>https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/2011/08/30/who-decides-corporate-culture/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2011 17:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Goizueta Newsroom</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Corporate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Knowledge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[People]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chi Chi Okezie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Diversity Leadership Conference]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Julius Pryor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Michael Johnson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rhonda Mims]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sara Buchanan]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/?p=2833</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Cultures are living, evolving entities, and corporate cultures are no exception. But who defines a given company's work habits, policies, values, and priorities? Those occuping the C-suite or those in the cubicles? It's not an either-or answer, according to several panelists at the 6th Annual Diversity Leadership Conference, held at Emory University's Goizueta Business <span style="color:#777"> . . . &#8594; Read More: <a href="https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/2011/08/30/who-decides-corporate-culture/">Who Decides Corporate Culture?</a></span>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Cultures are living, evolving entities, and corporate cultures are no exception. But who defines a given company's work habits, policies, values, and priorities? Those occuping the C-suite or those in the cubicles? It's not an either-or answer, according to several panelists at the 6<sup>th</sup> Annual Diversity Leadership Conference, held at Emory University's Goizueta Business School and sponsored by the school's Black MBA Association. Corporate culture is negotiated space where employees and leaders meet halfway to create a professional atmosphere that satisfies company goals and employee expectations, with the end result playing a significant role in the company's performance and successes.</em></p>
<p>&#8212;&#8211;</p>
<p>Should you adapt to a corporation's culture or should it adapt to you? Or is this a shared responsibility? That was one of several questions discussed at the 6<sup>th</sup> Annual Diverse Leadership Conference, held on April 1, 2011, and sponsored by Emory University's <a href="http://www.goizueta.emory.edu/">Goizueta Business School</a> and Black MBA Association.</p>
<p>During a session on "Global Diversity in a Digital World: Leveraging Human Capital," facilitators Julius Pryor, senior vice president at Your Talent Bridge, a diversity talent management firm, and Michael Johnson, vice president of HR at UPS, asked the audience about corporate culture. Can you change a corporate culture or must you assimilate to it?  Johnson offered his own company as an example.</p>
<p>"At UPS, you used to have to wear a suit and tie; you had to put on your coat to have a cup of coffee and put the cup on a tray, no coffee on your desk," he said. "Now, we have business casual and dress-down days. Who influenced that change? The employees."</p>
<p>But this doesn't mean employees should expect a company to adapt to their habits or preferences without some negotiation. "I want to be clear: Yes, companies should meet you halfway to help you assimilate and you should meet them halfway to assimilate. But a culture, while it can be influenced to change, cannot be changed by one individual," stressed Johnson.</p>
<p>People define diversity by the differences among people rather than the similarities, said Pryor. "But you can't create a corporate strategy unless you're thinking about both."</p>
<p>So what kinds of things do many companies look for in employees these days? Workers who are bilingual, transnational (have lived in other countries), data-driven, comfortable in fast-changing environments, and who can move in and out of teams. "Now, a leader has to be able to get in front of a team at one point and then fall back into the middle the next," said Pryor.</p>
<p>These strategies explained the eventual success of UPS in Germany. In the beginning, the mentality was, "We're going to teach the Germans how to be UPS people," said Johnson.  After making no money between 1975 and 1990, the company decided, "maybe we should hire some Germans so they can help us be successful!" After the German operation began to flourish, UPS changed overseas strategies. Their current strategy is geared toward joint partnerships with local companies already in the delivery business, and after understanding the way of doing business in a specific location, UPS converts the company and staff into a UPS operation.</p>
<p>"We try to reduce our numbers of expats — U.S. folks going over there to impose their will on people," said Johnson. "The shift we made accelerated our success — and that in itself was a diversity exercise," said Johnson.</p>
<p>This theme of corporate culture and diversity was echoed in the panel called "Break through the Glass Ceiling: Strategies for Successful Women in the Corporate Realm &amp; Entrepreneurship."</p>
<p>"If you notice that you and your corporate culture are at odds, I would strongly suggest looking for an organization that really matches up to the things that are important to you," said panelist Sara Buchanan, founder and CEO of Your Talent Bridge. By way of example, she described her years of working at BellSouth, which had a conservative, unionized culture, and her realization that she needed to work in a more entrepreneurial atmosphere. She advised job-hunters to seek out employees of prospective companies to get a feel for the corporate culture before signing on.</p>
<p>Willingness to learn more about another culture can be multifaceted. "A lot of my colleagues are white, middle-aged men," noted Chi Chi Okezie, owner and producer of SIMPLEnetworking, a company that teaches people how to network. "For them, recreation is not going to the movies or sitting home watching <em>Girlfriends</em>. So in order to interact with them and understand how my industry is moving, I had to learn to play golf. I wasn't compromising my beliefs; you just have to learn the skills you need to move to the next level."</p>
<p>When asked about strategies for breaking the glass ceiling, Rhonda Mims, president of ING Foundation and senior vice president of corporate responsibility and multicultural affairs at ING, a financial services firm, said she made sure she reached out to people who would help her, based on previous successes. "If I worked with someone to acquire a university as a client, I would get that person to be my advocate because they knew what my skill set was. And they became my sponsor," she noted. "A sponsor is not someone you go up to and ask, 'Hey will you be my sponsor?' but rather someone who knows what you can bring to the table and will speak up for you in those talent management meetings to get you that promotion."</p>
<p>But make sure your work is exemplary before you ask people to be your mentor or sponsor, added Buchanan. When you're a top performer, "what often happens is you start to be tapped, to be asked, 'How did you accomplish that?' From that I ended up meeting with people individually over lunch and asking them, 'What have you done to be successful?' It was a strategic move on my part."</p>
<p>You need to have a career plan, she added. "Start with your end goal and ask yourself,  'What are things I need to do—in bite-sized chunks, year by year or month by month—to achieve that? If your goal is to become part of the leadership ranks, seek out female leaders in your organization and ask them, 'What did it take to be successful? What do I need to do to increase my game?'"</p>
<p>Just be sure that this mentorship is a two-way street, so that you are offering something in addition to asking for help. Mims mentioned that one of her mentors is a much younger woman who gives her advice on social media.</p>
<p>Of course, all this advice is meaningless if not put into action. Pryor concluded his presentation with this African proverb: "Every morning, a gazelle wakes up. It knows it must run faster than the fastest lion or it will be killed. Every morning a lion wakes up. It knows it must outrun the slowest gazelle or it will starve to death. The moral? It doesn&#8217;t matter whether you are a lion or a gazelle; when the sun comes up, you&#8217;d better be running!"</p>
<p><strong>RELATED CONTENT: </strong></p>
<p><strong><a href="http://blogs.hbr.org/bregman/2009/06/the-best-way-to-change-a-corpo.html">HBR: A Good Way to Change Corporate Culture<br />
</a><a href="http://www.multiculturaladvantage.com/recruit/diversity/global-diversity/Corporate-Culture-Shock-in-America.asp">The Multicultural Advantage: Corporate Culture Shock in America<br />
</a><a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB120370822092186297.html"><em>Wall Street Journal: </em>On Diversity, America Isn't Putting Its Money Where Its Mouth Is<br />
</a><a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052748703280904576247131232952542.html"><em>Wall Street Journal</em> Women in the Economy: Recommendations for Moving Forward</a></strong></p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?a=EZeKcgmhJtg:Q0pIgQoCMxw:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?a=EZeKcgmhJtg:Q0pIgQoCMxw:F7zBnMyn0Lo"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?i=EZeKcgmhJtg:Q0pIgQoCMxw:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?a=EZeKcgmhJtg:Q0pIgQoCMxw:V_sGLiPBpWU"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?i=EZeKcgmhJtg:Q0pIgQoCMxw:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?a=EZeKcgmhJtg:Q0pIgQoCMxw:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?a=EZeKcgmhJtg:Q0pIgQoCMxw:gIN9vFwOqvQ"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?i=EZeKcgmhJtg:Q0pIgQoCMxw:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/GoizuetaNewsroom/~4/EZeKcgmhJtg" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/2011/08/30/who-decides-corporate-culture/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/2011/08/30/who-decides-corporate-culture/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>What Does the Future Hold for Gas Prices?</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/GoizuetaNewsroom/~3/EO3558u7Rhc/</link>
		<comments>https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/2011/08/29/what-does-the-future-hold-for-gas-prices/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2011 11:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Goizueta Newsroom</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Current Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Faculty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Knowledge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[People]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Story]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gas prices]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jag Sheth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ray Hill]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/?p=2825</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p class="wp-caption-text">Goizueta experts check in with causes of gas price peaks and valleys. PHOTO: futureatlas.com/Flickr.com</p> <p>Gasoline prices in the U.S. and elsewhere reached record highs earlier this year, prompted to a degree by unrest in the Middle East. But some faculty at Emory University's Goizueta Business School say that even after things calm among <span style="color:#777"> . . . &#8594; Read More: <a href="https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/2011/08/29/what-does-the-future-hold-for-gas-prices/">What Does the Future Hold for Gas Prices?</a></span>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_2826" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/87913776@N00/460375914/sizes/m/in/photostream/"><img class="size-full wp-image-2826 " style="margin: 10px" src="https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/files/2011/08/gaspump082511.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Goizueta experts check in with causes of gas price peaks and valleys. PHOTO: futureatlas.com/Flickr.com</p></div>
<p>Gasoline prices in the U.S. and elsewhere reached record highs earlier this year, prompted to a degree by unrest in the Middle East. But some faculty at <strong><a href="http://goizueta.emory.edu">Emory  University's Goizueta Business School</a> </strong>say that even after things calm among oil producing nations, gas prices are likely to stay high.</p>
<p>"Events in the Middle east have exaggerated the price rises," says Goizueta chaired marketing professor <a href="http://www.goizueta.emory.edu/faculty/JagdishSheth/">Jagdish Sheth</a>. "But they're not responsible for the longer term rise."</p>
<p>The major cause is the comeback in manufacturing, he notes, citing the most recent <em>Institute of Supply Management Report on Business</em>, which indicates that "economic activity in the manufacturing sector expanded in June for the 23rd consecutive month, and the overall economy grew for the 25th consecutive month," in the U.S. through June.</p>
<p>"Manufacturing is also growing in Germany, India, and especially in China where ambitious public works projects are driving an intensive need for energy," Sheth adds, while rising worldwide demand for consumer electronics, pharmaceutical and chemical products are also spurring a rise in energy costs.</p>
<p>"Pharmaceutical and chemical products are heavily petroleum-based, while many plastic and other components in PCs and smart phones also draw on petroleum products," he reports. "Oil is the ultimate raw material— everything else from agricultural to fragrance products all represents value added activity."</p>
<p>U.S. energy conservation activity is likely to have a limited impact on oil usage since the demand is global, Sheth notes. Despite that, the U.S. may be able to exert some downward pressure on pricing.</p>
<p>"America is still a leader in strategic assets like oil exploration and processing technology," he explains. "If the federal government treated this competitive advantage the way it governs arms shipments, we could offer long-term contracts to oil producers in exchange for long-term price and delivery contracts for oil."</p>
<p>The U.S. is also a leader when it comes to building refineries, and "it can insert itself as a nation downstream, offering its knowhow in exchange for long-term contracts at fixed prices," according to Sheth. "We can also offer military technology against insurgents who attack oil pipelines and other assets. Finally, as a quick, but limited solution, the U.S. can build up its strategic reserves and release them as needed, much as the Federal Reserve tweaks the money supply by releasing or withdrawing funds in response to specific situations. Of course, it's a lot easier to print money than it is to get oil."</p>
<p>Goizueta assistant finance professor <a href="http://www.goizueta.emory.edu/Faculty/RayHill/">Ray Hill</a> says the current price spikes stem from concern about the turmoil in Libya and other countries, rather than any significant changes in world oil supply.</p>
<p>"Some Libyan shipments have been disrupted, he says, but they amount to less than one percent of world daily consumption," he observes. "Fear of more significant disruption in Libya and unrest spreading to other big producers like Iran has certainly led to speculative pressure on oil prices."</p>
<p>"If political events in the Middle East do not lead to any cuts in production, (an important 'if') then the speculative price increase will be temporary," according to Hill. "Unlike gold, oil is dirty and bulky so it is difficult to store. Speculation cannot drive oil prices for very long.  Notwithstanding all the talk of financial speculators 'driving' the market, spot market demand and supply for physical oil must clear the market every day.&#8221;</p>
<p>He says tapping the U.S. strategic oil reserve, as President Obama has done, is a bad idea.</p>
<p>"Why should we make ourselves more vulnerable to a truly strategic interruption in oil supply (as we had in 1973) by using the reserve to counteract a temporary increase in price?" Hill asks. "And if events in the Middle East result in persistent cuts in production, rising prices may mean some unpleasant shocks to the economy in the short run, but long-term they're likely to spur searches for new, more effective methods of extraction and usage, not to mention efforts aimed at establishing alternative energy sources. Releasing oil from the strategic reserve blunts this important price signal to the market."</p>
<p>If the U.S. wanted to put downward pressure on oil prices, it could ease its restrictions on drilling in its off-shore waters like the Gulf of Mexico, he suggests.</p>
<p>"However, the effect of easing these restrictions would probably not show up in oil supply for some time so it would not be an immediate antidote," he adds. "And, of course, there are environmental concerns which must be taken into account as well."</p>
<p>Apart from the recent spike in prices driven by political events, the global economic recovery will drive demand higher and continue to exert so pressure on price increases over the longer run.</p>
<p>"Energy prices have tended to rise in the long run, but we've seen a lot of bounces down as well as up during the past 30 to 40 years," he observes. "The fact is that people are bad at forecasting this trend, and no one can say exactly where prices will be 'X' years from now."</p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?a=EO3558u7Rhc:ZXOPizX3PZw:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?a=EO3558u7Rhc:ZXOPizX3PZw:F7zBnMyn0Lo"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?i=EO3558u7Rhc:ZXOPizX3PZw:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?a=EO3558u7Rhc:ZXOPizX3PZw:V_sGLiPBpWU"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?i=EO3558u7Rhc:ZXOPizX3PZw:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?a=EO3558u7Rhc:ZXOPizX3PZw:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?a=EO3558u7Rhc:ZXOPizX3PZw:gIN9vFwOqvQ"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?i=EO3558u7Rhc:ZXOPizX3PZw:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/GoizuetaNewsroom/~4/EO3558u7Rhc" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/2011/08/29/what-does-the-future-hold-for-gas-prices/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/2011/08/29/what-does-the-future-hold-for-gas-prices/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>MBA Students Add a "Keystone"</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/GoizuetaNewsroom/~3/ik861uOeM6U/</link>
		<comments>https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/2011/08/26/mba-students-add-a-keystone/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2011 11:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>J. Michael Moore</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Faculty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MBA Program]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[People]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Programs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Staff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Students]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Story]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brian Mitchell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ray Hill]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Volunteer Emory]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/?p=2789</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p class="wp-caption-text">MBA students in the Class of 2012 returned to campus for the first &#34;Keystone&#34; week, building on first-year experiences and setting goals for their final year and beyond. PHOTO: Tony Brenner</p> <p>The Roman Arch was one of the most important architectural innovations of the ancient world.</p> <p>Renowned for strength and style, the structure remains practical today <span style="color:#777"> . . . &#8594; Read More: <a href="https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/2011/08/26/mba-students-add-a-keystone/">MBA Students Add a &#8220;Keystone&#8221;</a></span>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_2790" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 510px"><a href="https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/files/2011/08/keystone082511.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-2790 " style="margin: 10px" src="https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/files/2011/08/keystone082511.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="316" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">MBA students in the Class of 2012 returned to campus for the first &quot;Keystone&quot; week, building on first-year experiences and setting goals for their final year and beyond. PHOTO: Tony Brenner</p></div>
<p>The <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arch">Roman Arch</a> was one of the most important architectural innovations of the ancient world.</p>
<p>Renowned for strength and style, the structure remains practical today thanks to the "Keystone" &#8212; a centerpiece that strengthens the arch by allowing the two sides to work together.</p>
<p>In similar fashion, the <a href="http://www.goizueta.emory.edu/degree/fulltimemba/">Full-Time MBA Program</a> at <a href="http://goizueta.emory.edu">Emory&#8217;s Goizueta Business School</a> developed "Keystone Week" &#8212;  an innovative program designed to marry the learning in a student&#8217;s first year and internship with long-term goals and application formed in the second, and last, year of study.</p>
<p>During Keystone (<a href="http://twitter.com/#!/search?q=gbsks" target="_blank">Twitter</a>), students socialize, participate in community service and complete structured exercises designed to encourage strategic thinking about their final year in the program and the careers that follow.  The week-long program, in its first year, began Sunday evening and concludes Friday with an alumni speaker challenging the class of 2012 to begin thinking about their legacy. One objective of Keystone is to formally merge returning second-year students with their classmates from  the one-year MBA program preparing to enter the Fall semester.</p>
<div id="attachment_2794" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/files/2011/08/keystone082511a.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-2794 " style="margin: 10px" src="https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/files/2011/08/keystone082511a.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="204" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">A Keystone improv show was key in team-building activities that bring the one-year and two-year MBA classes together. PHOTO: Tony Brenner</p></div>
<p><strong>Brian Mitchell</strong>, <a href="https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/2011/01/12/associate-deans-named-for-twomba-programs/">Associate Dean of the Full-Time MBA Program</a>, said Keystone acts as the critical link between the first and second year of study and brings together the full Class of 2012 (two-year and one-year students). He also encourages community service and coordinated with <a href="http://www.volunteer.emory.edu/">Volunteer Emory</a> to offer 11 sites around Atlanta for MBA students to do volunteer work Monday morning.</p>
<p>Keystone objectives also include personal growth goal setting by students. The newly introduced "Keystone Lecture"  was delivered by renowned faculty member Ray Hill and focused on the current economic landscape and career advice for the soon-to-be MBA grads.  Professor Hill was recently recognized by <em>Businessweek</em> as one of the "<a href="http://www.businessweek.com/bschools/blogs/mba_admissions/archives/2011/08/most_popular_profs_at_top_business_schools.html" target="_blank">Most Popular Professors at Top Business Schools</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p>"I don't want Goizueta students thinking of their MBA experience as a linear journey," Mitchell said.  "When the first part is complete, you shouldn't put it behind you and simply move on to the next thing.  The pieces should work together, giving the entire experience more power and more meaning.  That's why the Keystone is so important."</p>
<p>The Dean said Keystone creates the opportunity for students to &#8220;take the time to be strategic&#8221; about their next moves.</p>
<p>In a larger sense, it&#8217;s about legacy.</p>
<p>MBA students close Keystone week by hand-writing personal, five-year goals and sealing them in an envelope. Envelopes will be saved and displayed in the Goizueta building &#8212; not to be opened until the students return for their five-year class reunion.</p>
<p>&#8220;How are you going to apply what you've just experienced?&#8221; Mitchell says, referring to the knowledge gained by many MBAs in a fast-paced first year.  &#8221;We&#8217;re taking the time to work through how they've been impacted, what they've learned and how they will implement those lessons at Goizueta and in their post-MBA careers.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s sharpening the saw at a very important point in their journey.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>RELATED CONTENT</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>TWITTER: </strong><a href="http://twitter.com/#!/search/gbsks" target="_blank">Students talk about the week (#gbsks)</a></li>
<li><strong>PROGRAM INFORMATION: </strong><a href="http://goizueta.emory.edu/degree/fulltimemba/two-year_program.html">Two-Year MBA</a> | <a href="http://goizueta.emory.edu/degree/fulltimemba/one-year_program.html">One-Year MBA</a></li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: center">&nbsp;</p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?a=ik861uOeM6U:jE5kNdUXdkU:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?a=ik861uOeM6U:jE5kNdUXdkU:F7zBnMyn0Lo"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?i=ik861uOeM6U:jE5kNdUXdkU:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?a=ik861uOeM6U:jE5kNdUXdkU:V_sGLiPBpWU"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?i=ik861uOeM6U:jE5kNdUXdkU:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?a=ik861uOeM6U:jE5kNdUXdkU:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?a=ik861uOeM6U:jE5kNdUXdkU:gIN9vFwOqvQ"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?i=ik861uOeM6U:jE5kNdUXdkU:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/GoizuetaNewsroom/~4/ik861uOeM6U" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/2011/08/26/mba-students-add-a-keystone/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/2011/08/26/mba-students-add-a-keystone/</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
		<title>Goizueta in the News: Aug. 25, 2011</title>
		<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/GoizuetaNewsroom/~3/PIygZ389N94/</link>
		<comments>https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/2011/08/25/goizueta-in-the-news-aug-25-2011/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2011 13:32:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Goizueta Newsroom</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Media Update]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AJC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bloomberg Businessweek]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dashon Catlett]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Emory Report]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eric Seti]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Evan Lounsbury]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Matt Schwartz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NBC.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Orlando Bulletin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sarah Neher]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Emory Wheel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Marriage Ref]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tom Smith]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/?p=2768</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Notable comments from Goizueta staff, faculty and students will be shared each week along with news on alumni, programs and rankings. Click here to review previous media updates. You can also inform Goizueta Newsroom of media postings (email).</p> <p>The Emory Wheel: Lounsbury, 23, Bright and Committed &#8220;Evan Douglas Lounsbury, an enthusiastic and dedicated Goizueta <span style="color:#777"> . . . &#8594; Read More: <a href="https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/2011/08/25/goizueta-in-the-news-aug-25-2011/">Goizueta in the News: Aug. 25, 2011</a></span>]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Notable comments from Goizueta staff, faculty and students will be shared each week along with news on alumni, programs and rankings. </em><em><a href="https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/2011/08/category/news/media-update/">Click here to review previous media updates</a></em><em>. You can also inform Goizueta Newsroom of media postings </em><a href="mailto:joseph.m.moore@emory.edu"><em>(email)</em></a><em>.</em></p>
<p><strong><a href="http://www.emorywheel.com/detail.php?n=29901" target="_blank"><em>The Emory Wheel</em>: Lounsbury, 23, Bright and Committed</a></strong><br />
&#8220;<strong>Evan Douglas Lounsbury</strong>, an enthusiastic and dedicated Goizueta Business School student, died on Friday. He was 23.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://www.emorywheel.com/detail.php?n=29889" target="_blank"><em>The Emory Wheel:</em> Commemorating Evan Lounsbury</a></strong><br />
&#8220;<em>The Wheel</em> would like to offer its condolences to all those who have been affected by the loss of 23-year-old <strong>Evan Lounsbury</strong>, who would have been a fifth-year student in the Goizueta Business School this fall. Now more than ever, it is crucial for the entire Emory community to come together in support of one another.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://www6.lexisnexis.com/publisher/EndUser?Action=UserDisplayFullDocument&amp;orgId=574&amp;topicId=100020422&amp;docId=l:1485265031" target="_blank"><em>Atlanta Journal-Constitution</em>: Georgia Works eyed for potential national job model</a></strong><br />
&#8220;&#8216;Maybe,&#8217; said <strong>Tom Smith</strong>, a finance professor and economist at the Goizueta Business School at Emory University. He said the program has real national promise because it strips away the fears some employers cite as reasons for not hiring, while also saving them money.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://orlandobulletin.com/orlando-fl/nfl-commissioner-roger-goodell/" target="_blank">Orlando Bulletin: NFL's labor strife ends; all sides appear satisfied</a></strong><br />
&#8220;After a rambling and at times belligerent three-hour teleconference call, the NFL Players Association voted 32-0 to approve a comprehensive settlement agreement on Monday in Washington.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://www.11alive.com/news/local/story.aspx?storyid=202619" target="_blank">11Alive.com: Southwest begins booking Atlanta flights</a></strong><br />
&#8220;While this will likely add pressure and create a more competitive environment, <strong>Jeff Rosensweig</strong>, an associate professor of finance at the Goizueta Business School at Emory University, said differentiation will be key for Delta. &#8221;</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://www.nbc.com/the-marriage-ref/video/the-refs-weigh-in-suchetas-travels/1346894" target="_blank">NBC.com: The Refs Weigh In &#8211; Sucheta&#8217;s Travels</a></strong><br />
&#8220;Ali Wentworth, Bill Maher and Patti LaBelle decide if [Goizueta alum] <strong>Sucheta&#8217;s </strong>world traveling is justified.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://www.emory.edu/EMORY_REPORT/stories/2011/08/back_to_school_class_of_2015.html" target="_blank">Emory Report: Class of 2015 hits campus</a></strong><br />
&#8220;Students who complete the first two years of the Emory bachelor&#8217;s degree in Oxford&#8217;s liberal arts intensive program are automatically enrolled as juniors in Emory College, or they may compete with others to enter the Goizueta Business School or the Nell Hodgson Woodruff School of Nursing.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://www.emorywheel.com/detail.php?n=29898" target="_blank"><em>The Emory Wheel</em>: Student-Created Emory Anthem is a 'Big Deal'</a></strong><br />
&#8220;Though making it into the Wheel isn't a big deal for Goizueta Business School senior<strong> Eric Seti</strong>, B-school junior <strong>Matt Schwartz</strong> and College junior<strong> Dashon Catlett</strong>, their Emory Anthem has become well-known among the Emory community.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://www.businessweek.com/business-schools/admissions-qampa-university-of-virginia-08242011.html" target="_blank">Businessweek.com: Admissions Q&amp;A</a></strong><br />
&#8220;<strong>Sara Neher</strong>, Darden's assistant dean of admissions, studied at UVA as an undergraduate and received her MBA from Emory&#8230;&#8221;</p>
<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?a=PIygZ389N94:xdaCx4Tzzd4:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?a=PIygZ389N94:xdaCx4Tzzd4:F7zBnMyn0Lo"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?i=PIygZ389N94:xdaCx4Tzzd4:F7zBnMyn0Lo" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?a=PIygZ389N94:xdaCx4Tzzd4:V_sGLiPBpWU"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?i=PIygZ389N94:xdaCx4Tzzd4:V_sGLiPBpWU" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?a=PIygZ389N94:xdaCx4Tzzd4:qj6IDK7rITs"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?d=qj6IDK7rITs" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?a=PIygZ389N94:xdaCx4Tzzd4:gIN9vFwOqvQ"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/GoizuetaNewsroom?i=PIygZ389N94:xdaCx4Tzzd4:gIN9vFwOqvQ" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/GoizuetaNewsroom/~4/PIygZ389N94" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/2011/08/25/goizueta-in-the-news-aug-25-2011/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		<feedburner:origLink>https://newsroom.goizueta.emory.edu/gnr/2011/08/25/goizueta-in-the-news-aug-25-2011/</feedburner:origLink></item>
	</channel>
</rss>

