<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><!--If you see this error message then you do not support RSS v2.0.--><rss version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Carter Center]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org]]></link><description><![CDATA[Carter Center News & Press Releases]]></description><item><title><![CDATA[Oct. 17, 2011: Carter Center Calls for Urgent Steps by DRC's Election Commission to Prepare for Nov. 28 Elections]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/drc-101711.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[In a pre-election report released today, The Carter Center called for urgent steps by the Democratic Republic of the Congo's (DRC) election commission in order to be credibly prepared for Nov. 28 elections. The report is based on findings from the Center's long-term observers, who have been deployed throughout the DRC since August.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Oct. 16, 2011: Former Mauritius President Cassam Uteem to Co-Lead Carter Center Delegation to Observe Tunisia's Oct. 23 Elections]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/tunisia-101611.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center announced today that former President of Mauritius and Club of Madrid member Cassam Uteem and Carter Center President and CEO Dr. John Hardman will co-lead the Center's international election observation delegation to Tunisia's National Constituent Assembly elections on Oct. 23. Former First Lady Rosalynn Carter will also participate in the delegation.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Oct. 14, 2011: The Carter Center Congratulates the Cherokee Nation on the Completion of the Vote Counting Process]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/cherokee-nation-101411.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center commends the Cherokee Nation Election Commission (CNEC) on the completion of the extended special election for Principal Chief.   Voting took place over 10 days and counting over three (Oct. 9-11, 2011).  The extra days of voting and the counting process were conducted transparently.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Oct. 13, 2011: Preliminary Statement:  Carter Center Reports Open and Transparent Voting Process; Encourages Liberians to Await Final Results]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/liberia-prelim-101311.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Oct. 11, 2011, presidential and legislative elections mark an important test for Liberia's transition from civil war to democratic, constitutional government.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Oct. 12, 2011: The Carter Center Calls For an Inclusive Solution to Conflicts in Southern Kordofan and Blue Nile]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/sudan-101211.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center calls on all stakeholders to work for a sustainable solution to the conflicts in Southern Kordofan and Blue Nile states. The popular consultations could facilitate a long-term settlement in both states if implemented in a credible way. However, this requires a security environment conducive to open dialogue and the inclusion of all stakeholders in the process.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Oct. 12, 2011: Carter Center Group to Visit Nicaragua During Nov. 6 Elections(En Espa&#241;ol)]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/nicaragua-101211.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[A small delegation from The Carter Center will visit Nicaragua during the upcoming presidential and legislative elections in Nicaragua on Nov. 6. The delegation of five persons consists of members and advisers to the group of Friends of the Inter-American Democratic Charter, an informal group of eminent persons from the hemisphere, with secretariat at The Carter Center in Atlanta, Ga., who advocate for constructive international support to strengthen all democracies in the hemisphere.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Oct. 10, 2011: Trip Report by Former U.S. President Jimmy Carter to the Netherlands, Belgium, United Kingdom, and Norway, October 2-6, 2011]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/trip_reports/europe-oct2011.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Thanks to the fine work of John Hardman, Phil Wise, Don Hopkins, David Carroll, Hrair Balian, Larry Frankel, Nicole Kruse, Curtis Kohlhaas, and others, I completed an interesting and successful series of visits with leaders in these four countries and in the United Nations, the European Union, and other international organizations.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Oct. 6, 2011: General Yakubu Gowon to Lead Carter Center Delegation to Observe Liberia's Oct. 11 Elections]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/liberia-100611.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center announced today that His Excellency General Dr. Yakubu Gowon, Nigeria's former head of state, will lead the Center's international election observation delegation to Liberia.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Oct. 5, 2011: Britain to Help Carter Center Secure Worldwide Eradication of Worm Disease]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/dfid-100511.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Britain today announced it will provide major support to a new project that will make Guinea worm the second human disease ever to be eradicated in human history.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Oct. 3, 2011: The Carter Center Calls on Tunisian Election Authorities to Finalize Critical Procedures and Intensify Voter Outreach ]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/tunisia-100311.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[With the launch of the electoral campaign period on Oct. 1, Tunisia has entered the final leg of the National Constituent Assembly elections, scheduled for Oct. 23, 2011. While electoral preparations are progressing, key issues such as the allocation of voters to polling stations and the system for the tabulation of results require final decisions and publication by election authorities.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Oct. 3, 2011: Carter Center Reports Vibrant and Generally Peaceful Campaigning in Liberia; Urges Steps to Level Playing Field]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/liberia-100311.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Liberia's upcoming 2011 presidential and legislative elections represent a critical test for the country's transition from war to democratic and constitutional government]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Oct. 3, 2011: On the Ground in Northwest Tunisia: Rural Voters Hope Elections Bring Much-Needed Change]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://blog.cartercenter.org/2011/10/03/on-the-ground-in-northwest-tunisia-rural-voters-hope-elections-bring-much-needed-change/]]></link><description><![CDATA[Marwa Alkhairo, Carter Center long-term election observer, blogs from northwest Tunisia and Bizerte.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sept. 27, 2011: Carter Center Commends Successful Cherokee Nation Voting Day and Highlights the Need for Patience and Transparency as Process Unfolds]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/cherokee_nation-092711.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center congratulates the election commission, candidates, and voters of the Cherokee Nation on a successful election day. Sept. 24 was the only day for voters to cast ballots at 38 precincts in the Nation, but there will be additional opportunities for citizens to cast a ballot at the election commission and for Freedmen to vote by absentee ballot to determine who will be the next principal chief.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sept. 27, 2011: The Carter Center Rejects Fake Opinion Poll]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/liberia-092711.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[An opinion poll currently circulating in Liberia by email is being falsely attributed to The Carter Center. We reject such efforts to mislead the public and call on all stakeholders to be vigilant in assessing information about the electoral process.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sept. 22, 2011: Statement From Former U.S. President Jimmy Carter on Troy Anthony Davis]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/davis-092211.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Rosalynn and I are deeply saddened by the execution of Troy Anthony Davis by the State of Georgia.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sept. 20, 2011: Statement from President Jimmy Carter and The Carter Center on the Passing of George Price]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/george-price-092011.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[We lament the passing of George Price, founding father of Belize and good friend of The Carter Center. His humble personality belied the stature of his statesmanship.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sept. 15, 2011: Carter Center Announces Election Observation Mission to Liberia]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/liberia-091511.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center today deployed teams of long-term observers to launch an international election observation mission for Liberia's presidential and legislative elections on Oct. 11, 2011.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sept. 14, 2011: Carter Center Announces Election Observation Mission to Cherokee Nation]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/cherokee-nation-091411.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[At the invitation of the Cherokee Nation Election Commission, The Carter Center will deploy a small observation mission for the Sept. 24, 2011, special election for principal chief. Carter Center observers will interview the election commission, political contestants, and others to assess the electoral process. In addition, the Center will observe early voting, as well as election day polling, counting, and tabulation processes.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sept. 13, 2011: After the U.N. Vote on Palestine]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/editorials_speeches/palestine-091311.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[This op-ed by former U.S. President Jimmy Carter was published Sept. 13, 2011, by the International Herald Tribute and NYTimes.com. In September 1978, Anwar Sadat and Menachim Begin signed the Camp David Accords, following four Arab-Israeli wars in which Egypt had provided the overwhelming military force that threatened the existence of Israel.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sept. 9, 2011: Carter Center Statement on the Nov. 6 Elections in Nicaragua]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/nicaragua-090911.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[In light of the Nicaraguan Supreme Electoral Council's (CSE) publication of the Electoral Accompaniment Regulations on Aug. 16, 2011, The Carter Center wishes to explain its conditions for observing the Nicaraguan elections in 2011.  They are the same conditions under which we were invited and agreed to observe the elections in 1990, 1996, 2001, and 2006.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sept. 1, 2011: The Carter Center Welcomes Completion of Tunisia's Voter Registration; Highlights Additional Steps Needed to Ensure Successful Polling ]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/tunisia-090111.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[A Carter Center statement released today noted that Tunisia's voter registration process was conducted smoothly, but important operational challenges remain for the High Independent Authority for the Elections (ISIE), particularly the allocation of voters to polling stations and a campaign to disseminate voter information to the public. The Center recommends intensified public outreach by the ISIE and other bodies to assist Tunisians in the electoral process.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Aug. 26, 2011: The Carter Center Calls for a Peaceful Resolution of the Stalemate in the Blue Nile Popular Consultations]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/sudan-082611.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center calls on stakeholders in Blue Nile to use dialogue and inclusive negotiations to solve the current standstill around the popular consultations and to recommit to the spirit of the Comprehensive Peace Agreement (CPA) by reaching a peaceful settlement.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Aug. 17, 2011 : Carter Center Announces Election Observation Mission to DRC (En fran&#231;ais - PDF)]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/drc-081711.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[At the invitation of the Independent Electoral Commission (CENI) and the welcome of political parties, The Carter Center has launched an international election observation mission for the Democratic Republic of the Congo (DRC) elections on Nov. 28, 2011.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Aug. 12, 2011: The Carter Center Congratulates Liberia on Graduation of Inaugural Class of Mental Health Clinicians]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/liberia-mh-081211.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Today, during a ceremony attended by Liberian government officials, community and religious leaders, and other partners, The Carter Center celebrated the graduation of Liberia's first class of locally trained mental health clinicians.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Aug. 10, 2011: What Is A Superpower?]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/editorials_speeches/tikkun-082011.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[This article by former U.S. President Jimmy Carter was published in the Winter 2011 issue of Tikkun Magazine. American military expenditures are now equal to those combined for all other nations, and it is good to know that our nation's defenses against a conventional attack are impregnable. It is also imperative that America remain vigilant against threats from terrorists. But the admirable characteristics of a nation are no more defined by its size and physical prowess than are those of a human being.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Aug. 4, 2011 : Carter Center Announces Election Observation Mission to Tunisia (English, Arabic, and French)]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/tunisia-080411.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[In response to an invitation from the Tunisian electoral commission, The Carter Center formally launched an international observation mission to monitor preparations for the country's Constituent Assembly elections anticipated on Oct. 23. The mission is supported by an office in Tunis, which is led by Field Office Director Sabina Vigani.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Aug. 4, 2011: Political Space in Nepal has Improved Since Constituent Assembly Election but Challenges Remain, Sustainability Still in Question]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/nepal-080411.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[In a report released today, Carter Center observers found broad consensus that political space has opened across Nepal since the 2008 Constituent Assembly election. Improvements in the behavior of Unified Communist Party of Nepal (Maoist) cadres at the local level and a decline in armed group activity in parts of the Tarai were frequently cited as the main reasons for this change.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[July 28, 2011: Former U.S. President Jimmy Carter Congratulates People of Ghana for Halting Guinea Worm Disease Transmission, Urges Remaining Endemic Countries to Wipe Out Ancient Affliction as Soon as Possible]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/ghana-072811.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Former U.S. President Jimmy Carter and The Carter Center congratulate Ghana on becoming the world's newest country to stop transmission of Guinea worm, a water-borne parasitic disease poised to be the second human disease in history to be eradicated.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[July 15, 2011: Sudan:  The Carter Center Calls for Formal Extension of the Blue Nile Popular Consultations]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/sudan-071511.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[In a report issued today, The Carter Center recognized the announcement of Sudan President Omar al-Bashir to extend the Blue Nile and Southern Kordofan popular consultations, and urged the National Assembly to formalize this extension, creating a specific timetable to consider issues raised in public hearings and opening discussions on a national level as deemed necessary. ]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[July 15, 2011: The Carter Center Awards 2011-2012 Rosalynn Carter Fellowships for Mental Health Journalism]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/mhj-2011-2012.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center announced the recipients of the 2011-2012 Rosalynn Carter Fellowships for Mental Health Journalism today, one of the only journalism fellowship programs exclusively focused on mental health issues. Selected from a highly competitive pool of applicants, the 15th annual class of fellows includes six from the United States and two from Romania. (See below for a full list of fellows and their project topics.)]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[July 13, 2011: Remarks by Former First Lady Rosalynn Carter at the Funeral of Betty Ford]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/editorials_speeches/rc-remarks-betty-ford-funeral.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[This eulogy was delivered by former First Lady Rosalynn Carter at the National Tribute to Former First Lady Betty Ford, held July 12, 2011, at Saint Margaret Episcopal Church in Palm Desert, Calif. Betty Ford was my friend and I'm honored to be here today to help celebrate the life of this truly remarkable woman.  I never imagined when we first met 40 years ago that we would develop such a close and personal friendship.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[July 8, 2011: Statement From President and Mrs. Carter on the Passing of  Former First Lady Betty Ford]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/betty-ford-070811.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Rosalynn and I are saddened by the passing of Betty Ford, a close personal friend and our frequent partner in bipartisan efforts to improve mental health and substance abuse care in our nation. ]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[July 7, 2011: Carter Center Commends Election Commission of Nepal on Progress in Voter Registration, Encourages Efforts to Increase Citizen Turnout]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/nepal-070711.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[In a report released today, The Carter Center commended the Election Commission of Nepal (ECN) for registering nearly eight million Nepali citizens to date and encouraged the ECN to undertake additional efforts to reach out to millions more who have yet to participate in the process.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[July 2, 2011: The Carter Center Urges Meaningful Deliberation of Draft Transitional Constitution]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/sudan-070211.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[As Southern Sudan prepares for independence in the face of recent armed conflict with the North, it is critically important that the Government of Southern Sudan (GoSS) and the ruling Sudan People's Liberation Movement (SPLM) take steps to demonstrate a strong commitment to inclusive and participatory governance. In the short time remaining before independence on July 9, the GoSS should make efforts to review previous citizen input on the draft transitional constitution, and both before and after its entry into force take greater steps to inform citizens about the transition process.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[June 17, 2011: Call Off the Global Drug War]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/editorials_speeches/global-drug-war-061711.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[This op-ed by former U.S. President Jimmy Carter was published June 17, 2011, by The New York Times. In an extraordinary new initiative announced earlier this month, the Global Commission on Drug Policy has made some courageous and profoundly important recommendations in a report on how to bring more effective control over the illicit drug trade.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[May 31, 2011: Carter Center Appoints New Members to Board of Councilors]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/boc-053111.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center, a not-for-profit organization advancing peace and health worldwide, recently appointed 18 new members to the Board of Councilors, bringing its total membership to 233.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[May 30, 2011: Statement by The Carter Center on the Extension of Nepal's Constituent Assembly (कृपया नेपालीमा पढ्नुहोस्)]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/nepal-053011.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center welcomes the recent agreement by Nepal's political parties as well as their decision to extend the Constituent Assembly tenure by three months.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[May 25, 2011: The Unchanged Path to Mideast Peace]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/editorials_speeches/jc-nyt052511-UnchangedPathtoMideastPeace.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[This op-ed by former U.S. President Jimmy Carter was published May 25, 2011, by the International Herald Tribune and NYT.com. It was not a new U.S. policy concerning the borders of Israel, nor should it have been surprising to Israeli leaders, when President Obama stated: "The borders of Israel and Palestine should be based on the 1967 lines with mutually agreed swaps, so that secure and recognized borders are established for both states."]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[May 23, 2011: Carter Center, American College of Physicians, and Health Experts Release Report Detailing Solutions for Reinvigorating Primary Care System: Five Prescriptions for Ensuring the Future of Primary Care]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/ReinvigoratingPrimaryCareSystem.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[A new report from The Carter Center and the American College of Physicians (ACP), "Five Prescriptions for Ensuring the Future of Primary Care," argues that an overhaul of the primary care education system&#151;including adopting more rigorous training in mental illness diagnosis and treatment&#151;is necessary to fully implement reform of the U.S. health care system.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[May 18, 2011: Vote in South Kordofan is Peaceful and Credible, Despite Climate of Insecurity and Some Irregularities]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/sudan-051811.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Despite a climate of heightened insecurity and instances of procedural irregularities that removed an important safeguard of the process, South Kordofan's elections were generally peaceful and credible. The voting, counting, and results aggregation processes were conducted in a nonpartisan and transparent manner under intense scrutiny from leading political parties.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[May 10, 2011: Carter Center: Local Peace Committee Functioning Has Improved, But Overall Effectiveness Remains Unclear]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/nepal-051011.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[In a report released today, Carter Center observers found that although the overall functioning of Local Peace Committees (LPCs) has improved since November 2009, their effectiveness remains unclear and they continue to face serious challenges.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[May 9, 2011: Carter Center Calls For Calm As Parties Await Electoral Results - South Kordofan Gubernatorial And State Legislative Elections]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/sudan-051011.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center urges calm during the aggregation of results for the South Kordofan gubernatorial and legislative elections. The Carter Center calls on all contesting parties and candidates to continue to observe the results aggregation peacefully, to ask their supporters to remain calm and to seek recourse to potential electoral disputes through established legal channels.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[May 3, 2011: Support The Palestinian Unity Government]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/editorials_speeches/palestinian-unity-govt-050311.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[This op-ed by former U.S. President Jimmy Carter was published May 3, 2011, in The Washington Post. This is a decisive moment. Under the auspices of the Egyptian government, Palestine's two major political movements &#151; Fatah and Hamas &#151; are signing a reconciliation agreement on Wednesday that will permit both to contest elections for the presidency and legislature within a year.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[May 2, 2011: Trip Report by Former U.S. President Jimmy Carter to Korean Peninsula, April 22-29, 2011]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/trip_reports/korean-peninsula-042211.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Report by Former U.S. President Jimmy Carter on trip to China, North Korea, and South Korea from April 22-29, 2011.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[May 1, 2011: Maltra Success Measured in Millions]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/h/maltra/MaltraSuccessMeasuredinMillions.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Twice a year, thousands of health workers and volunteers walk the countryside of Amhara region, Ethiopia, for a week. Their quest: treat every person at risk for the potentially blinding eye infection trachoma and screen as needed for malaria. In this Q&A, Paul Emerson, director of the Center's Trachoma Control Program, explains the remarkable results of these "Maltra"&#151;malaria and trachoma&#151;weeks.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[May 1, 2011: Michael Biesecker: Journalism Fellow Chronicles Abuse, Fraud in North Carolina]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/h/mental_health/rlrc-MichaelBiesecker.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Reporter Michael Biesecker's coverage of mental health issues began with a high-speed car chase following a robbery. In the course of Biesecker's investigation, he found that although the driver was in a psychotic state two weeks before the crime, he had been turned away from the state's psychiatric hospital.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[May 1, 2011: Thon Mayom: Case Containment Center Offers Hope, Relief for Boy]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/h/guinea_worm/rlrc-thon-mayom.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[At bedtime, under a blue mosquito net, two boys lie on a mat and whisper secrets from the day just passed. Six-year-old Thon Mayom falls asleep quickly. He is exhausted from two sessions that day to treat a worm emerging from his knee. His 5-year-old brother, Mawut, drifts off to sleep too. His job is to look after his big brother during the difficult treatment.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[May 1, 2011: Jozefa Ortiz Rosa: Medication Restores Sight, Brings Hope to Grandmother]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/h/river_blindness/rlrc-jozefa-ortiz-rosa.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[When Jozefa Ortiz Rosa of Tarrales, Guatemala, started losing her vision, she worried about her future. Her husband had died years before, leaving her with six children to raise and a coffee crop to tend. Her older children had taken over the farming, but she still needed to care for her younger children and grandchildren.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[April 2011: Read the latest issue of The Carter Center News (Spring 2011 PDF)]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/resources/pdfs/news/carter_center_news/spring2011.pdf]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center News is the official newsletter of the peace and health organization founded by Nobel Peace Prize laureate and former U.S. President Jimmy Carter and former First Lady Rosalynn Carter.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[April 29, 2011: Carter Center Statement on Palestinian Reconciliation ]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/palestinian-reconciliation-042911.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Report by Former U.S. President Jimmy Carter on trip to China, North Korea, and South Korea from April 22-29, 2011.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[April 28, 2011: The Carter Center Notes Concerns With Security in South Kordofan, Progress in Polling Preparations]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/sudan-042811.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center is concerned by recent deteriorations in South Kordofan's security environment and calls on all sides to promote a genuine and credible polling process for the state. Although the recently concluded candidate nomination period was largely conducted transparently, efficiently, and peacefully, there have been worrying developments during the campaign period. In particular, The Carter Center is concerned about the armed conflict that broke out in El Faid and reportedly resulted in dozens of casualties. Continuing tensions between rival candidates in certain areas could negatively affect voter turnout, impact the results, and therefore reduce the credibility of the electoral process.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[April 19, 2011: Summary of Observation Findings on the Election Commission of Nepal's "Voter Registration with Photograph" Program (PDF)]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/resources/pdfs/news/pr/Nepal-FindingsSummar-VoterReg-PhotoProgram-041911-ENG.pdf]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Election Commission of Nepal (ECN) is conducting a nationwide voter registration process to create a new computerized voter register. Following an invitation from the ECN and as part of broader efforts to observe the peace and constitutional processes at the local level, Carter Center observers were deployed to 13 districts in February and March 2011 to gather information about the voter registration process.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[April 19, 2011: First Interim Statement on the Election Commission of Nepal's "Voter Registration with Photograph" Program (PDF)]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/resources/pdfs/news/pr/Nepal-First%20InterimStatement-VoterReg-PhotoProgram-041911-ENG.pdf]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Election Commission of Nepal (ECN) is conducting a nationwide voter registration process to create a new computerized voter register. Following an invitation from the ECN and as part of broader efforts to observe the peace and constitutional processes at the local level, Carter Center observers were deployed to 13 districts in February and March 2011 to gather information about the voter registration process.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[April 19, 2011: Carter Center Notes Progress in Nepal's Ongoing Voter Registration Process, Offers Suggestions to Address Key Challenges Ahead]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/nepal-041911.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[In a report released today, Carter Center observers found that overall the Election Commission of Nepal's (ECN) voter registration process is moving forward, despite delays.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[April 11, 2011: Return Visit Confirms Family's Continued Vigilance Against Trachoma]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/h/trachoma/HaymanotShibabow.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Paul Emerson entered the modest hut unannounced, knowing what he was hoping to find, but ready for anything.Emerson &#151; director of the Carter Center's Trachoma Control Program &#151; had visited this family before. In 2005, he had accompanied President and Mrs. Carter to Mosebo village, northwest Ethiopia, to help launch a comprehensive trachoma initiative in the region. A 3-year-old girl had charmed the Carters when she showed them her very own latrine, which would help keep the flies that transmit trachoma from breeding.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[April 6, 2011: Human Rights and Religious Leaders Call on Religious Leadership to Stand for Equal Rights for Girls and Women]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/hrd-forum-2011.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[A group of human rights defenders and religious leaders representing more than 20 countries gathered at The Carter Center today called on faith leaders to reassess the role religions play in continuing discrimination against women worldwide.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[April 1, 2011: Trip Report by Former U.S. President Jimmy Carter to Cuba, March 28-30, 2011]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/trip_reports/cuba-march2011.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[At the invitation of President Raul Castro, Rosalynn and I visited Havana on behalf of The Carter Center, accompanied by John Hardman, Jennifer McCoy, Robert Pastor, Melissa Montgomery, John Moores, and Diane Rosenberg.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[March 31, 2011: The Carter Center Celebrates Transfer of Ethiopia Public Health Training Initiative to Ethiopia Ministry of Health and Federal Ministry of Education]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/ephti-033111.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[After 13 years training more than 26,000 public health workers to help fill the gap in rural health services for 75 million Ethiopians, The Carter Center- assisted Ethiopia Public Health Training Initiative (EPHTI) officially has been transferred to Ethiopia's  Federal Ministries of Health and Education. Established in 1997 at the invitation of Prime Minister Meles Zenawi, EPHTI worked in partnership with seven Ethiopian universities and the Ethiopian government to improve the public health education system.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[March 28, 2011: The Carter Center Notes Concerns with Low Voter Registration Turnout in South Kordofan, Highlights Steps Needed for Credible Polling Process]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/sudan-032811.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[In a statement released today, The Carter Center welcomed the completion of the voter registration process in South Kordofan. The process was conducted in a generally peaceful environment and the majority of registration centers operated without major problems. However, the Center notes several shortcomings that hurt the inclusiveness and integrity of voter registration and resulted in low turnout.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[March 25, 2011: Former U.S. President Jimmy Carter and Former First Lady to Visit Cuba]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/carter_cuba_032511.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Former U.S. President Jimmy Carter and his wife, Rosalynn, will arrive in Havana, Cuba, Monday, March 28, for a visit, at the invitation of the Cuban government.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[March 21, 2011: Carter Center Urges Political Parties and Blue Nile Popular Consultation Commission to Ensure Genuine  Dialogue on Key Issues in Blue Nile State]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/sudan-032111.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[In a statement issued today, The Carter Center reports that the first phase of the popular consultation in Blue Nile produced notable accomplishments, but that state legislative assembly members, political parties, and consultation authorities should work collaboratively to ensure a more transparent and genuine dialogue on the key issues in remaining phases of the process in Blue Nile.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[March 17, 2011:Carter Center Urges Inclusive Transition Process in Southern Sudan]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/sudan-031711.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Distrust between the Sudan People's Liberation Movement (SPLM) and opposition parties is a critical challenge that undermines the unity of Southern Sudan on the eve of its independence.  To ensure a successful transition, The Carter Center urges all Southern Sudanese political leaders to agree on genuinely inclusive processes for reviewing and adopting the transitional constitution and planning for the transition.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[March 14, 2011: As River Blindness Declines, Health Education Intensifies]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/h/river_blindness/health-ed-intensifies.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Standing in the courtyard of his school in El Xab, Guatemala, his eyes blindfolded, a boy swings a large pole toward a flyshaped pi&#241;ata. Schoolmates cheer for the boy, who looks about 9 years old. His friends hope that one well-placed strike will smash the fly, releasing oodles of candy. The adults in charge hope the children leave with something more than a handful of treats.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Feb. 28, 2011: Carter Center: Clashes Between Nepal's Political Party Youth Wings Have Decreased But YCL and UML Youth Force Continue to Seek Financial Gain]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/nepal-022811.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[In a report released today, Carter Center observers found that overall clashes between Nepal's political party youth wings appear to have decreased. However, many activities of the Maoist-affiliated Young Communist League (YCL) and, to a lesser extent, the CPN-UML Youth Force remain targeted toward financial gain, and youth wing activity continues to have a negative impact on security in many districts.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Feb. 28, 2011: Forum Identifies Solutions to Improve Cooperation Among Andean Countries and the United States (English and En Espa&#241;ol)]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/andean-US-022811.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Andean-U.S. Dialogue Forum, a citizens' forum created to identify and contribute solutions to multilateral problems and tensions among the Andean countries (Bolivia, Colombia, Ecuador, Peru, and Venezuela) and the United States, issued a report today outlining a common agenda to improve cooperation among the nations]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Feb. 27, 2011: Winter Weekend Auction Raises $841,750 for Carter Center Peace and Health Programs]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/winter-weekend-2011-results.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center's annual Winter Weekend auction, held Feb. 26 at Port St. Lucie, Fla., raised $841,750.00 to benefit the not-for-profit Center's initiatives to advance peace and health worldwide.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Feb. 17, 2011: Former U.S. President Jimmy Carter Announces Three Countries Left in Guinea Worm Eradication Campaign: Nigeria and Niger Honored as Most Recent Nations to Halt Disease Transmission (En anglais et en fran&#231;ais)]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/three-countries-guinea-worm-eradication.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Former U.S. President and Carter Center Founder Jimmy Carter announced today that only three endemic countries remain in the fight against Guinea worm disease, poised to be only the second disease in history&#151;after smallpox&#151;to be eradicated.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Feb. 17, 2011: Guinea Worm Disease Campaign Nears Eradication Goal]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/h/guinea_worm/guinea-worm-disease-campaign-nears-goal.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Former U.S. President and Carter Center Founder Jimmy Carter announced today that only three endemic countries remain in the fight against Guinea worm disease, poised to be only the second disease in history&#151;after smallpox&#151;to be eradicated.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Feb. 16, 2011: Two Vital Steps on Path to Democracy in Egypt]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/editorials_speeches/stremlau-two-vital-steps-democracy-egypt.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[This op-ed by Dr. John Stremlau was published Feb. 16, 2011, by CNN. The resignation of President Hosni Mubarak was only the first step on what will be a long, difficult path toward genuine democratic governance -- one that will need the support of the international community.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Feb. 14, 2011: Carter Center Congratulates Success of Southern Sudan Referendum, Encourages Steps to Strengthen Future Elections]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/sudan-021411.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center congratulates the Southern Sudan Referendum Commission, the Southern Sudan Referendum Bureau, the Comprehensive Peace Agreement partners, and the Sudanese people on the announcement of the final results of the referendum on the self-determination of Southern Sudan. The results indicate overwhelming popular support for the secession of Southern Sudan, and their announcement marks the successful conclusion of the referendum process. The Center's observation mission finds that the referendum provided a credible expression of the will of the Southern Sudanese people and has been broadly consistent with international standards.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Feb. 14, 2011: Ann Cramer Appointed Chair of Carter Center Board of Councilors]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/boc-cramer-appt-021411.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Ann Cramer, director for IBM Corporate Citizenship & Corporate Affairs for the Americas, has been appointed chair of the Carter Center's Board of Councilors for 2011. The board is comprised of 212 members, who serve as a leadership advisory group that promotes understanding among opinion leaders and the broader community of The Carter Center and its activities.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Feb. 14, 2011: Nigerian Family Fights Malaria With Carter Center Help]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/h/malaria/tcc-helps-family-fight-malaria.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The 2010 launch of a new Carter Center-supported initiative is helping the Azi family and millions of other Nigerians receive greater access to malaria control and prevention, building the opportunity for a healthier future for the entire nation.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Feb. 11, 2011: Statement From The Carter Center on Democratic Transition in Egypt]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/egypt-021111.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center congratulates the people of Egypt on their courageous steps toward a new era of democratic legitimacy and respect for human rights.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Feb. 11, 2011: Credible Elections for Egypt]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/editorials_speeches/nytimes-021111.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[This op-ed by former U.S. President Jimmy Carter was published Feb. 11, 2011, by The New York Times/International Herald Tribune. Even at this point, after the dramatic announcement by the armed forces, no one can predict the ultimate outcome of the Egyptian drama. But there is a clear picture of the existing situation and a few obvious options for the future.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Feb. 10, 2011: Rare Presidential and Sports Memorabilia to Be Auctioned to Benefit Carter Center - General Public Invited to Bid Online]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/winter-weekend-2011.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Original artwork by former U.S. President Jimmy Carter, a baseball signed by four presidents, a behind-the-scenes tour of Delta Air Lines, and historic memorabilia from the Carter presidential campaign and White House years are among more than 150 items up for public auction in Port St. Lucie, Fla., on Feb. 26, 2011, during the Carter Center's annual Winter Weekend event. The auction, held for the past 18 years, is a critical source of support for the not-for-profit Center's international work advancing peace and health.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Feb. 7, 2011: Applications Being Accepted for the 2011-2012 Rosalynn Carter Fellowships for Mental Health Journalism]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/mhj-applications-2011.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Applications from U.S. residents are now being accepted for six one-year journalism fellowships with the Carter Center's Mental Health Program. These fellowships aim to enhance public understanding of mental health issues and reduce stigma and discrimination against people with mental illnesses through balanced and accurate reporting.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Jan. 24, 2011: Carter Center Observers Witness Southern Sudan's Referendum on Self-Determination]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/p/elections/sudan/referendum-012411.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Carter Center observers witnessed the birth of what is expected to be the world's newest nation, following Southern Sudan's Jan. 9-15 referendum on self-determination, with an overwhelming majority--a reported 98.9 percent--voting for secession from Sudan.  The final results will be announced in February.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Jan. 19, 2011: Carter Center and JPC Expand Liberian Community Legal Advice Services Into Nine Counties ]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/liberia-011911.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center, in partnership with the Catholic Justice and Peace Commission (JPC), is expanding its Community Legal Advisor (CLA) program to provide legal support services in nine rural Liberian counties.  With support from USAID and Humanity United, the services will be continued and expanded for the next two years.  The program gives rural Liberians access to free community-based legal services and knowledge of their rights. Since 2007, more than 3,000 cases have been opened by community legal advisors.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Jan. 18, 2011: Trip Report by Former U.S. President Jimmy Carter to Sudan, Jan. 5-16, 2011]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/trip_reports/sudan-011811.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The primary purpose of our trip was to lead the monitoring team for the referendum among South Sudanese to determine whether to remain part of a united Sudan or to form a new independent nation. In addition, we wished to learn as much as possible about ongoing efforts to establish permanent accord in the region, based on the Comprehensive Peace Accord (CPA) of 2005, to enhance progress on our Center's health programs in Sudan, and to make plans for future projects.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Jan. 17, 2011: Carter Center Finds Sudanese Referendum Peaceful and Credible]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/sudan-011711.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center observation mission congratulates the people of Sudan for the successful conduct of the historic referendum on self-determination, which was marked by an overwhelming turnout of enthusiastic voters during a peaceful and orderly seven-day voting period.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Jan. 15, 2011: Looking to the Future in Sudan: Dr. Donald R. Hopkins' Letter to the Editor, The New York Times]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/editorials_speeches/drh-looking-to-future-sudan-011511.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[This letter sent Jan. 11, 2011, by Carter Center Health Programs Vice President Donald R. Hopkins, M.D., M.P.H., is in response to an editorial published Jan. 8, 2011, by The New York Times. "Southern Sudan Votes" (editorial, Jan. 8) rightly notes that the government of southern Sudan has "set up more than two dozen ministries and built schools and roads" since the signing of the comprehensive peace agreement in 2005.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Jan. 13, 2011: New York Times "On The Ground" Blog: President Carter, Nicholas Kristof Answer Readers' Questions About Sudan, Referendum]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/p/elections/sudan/kristof-2011-referendum.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[New York Times columnist Nicholas Kristof posts answers to readers' questions for former U.S. President Jimmy Carter.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Jan. 10, 2011: Parasite-Fighting Medicine Brightens Nigeria's Future]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/h/schistosomiasis/parasite-fighting-medicine-nigeria.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[In the blistering heat of Nasarawa North, Nigeria, the cool waters of the River Uke beckon all. Women launder clothes, people bathe, girls fetch water, and children, especially boys, splash and swim for fun.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Jan. 3, 2011: Jimmy Carter, Kofi Annan, Joseph Warioba, and John Hardman to Lead Carter Center Delegation to Observe Referendum on Self-Determination of Southern Sudan ]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/sudan-010311.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Former U.S. President Jimmy Carter, former U.N. Secretary General Kofi Annan, former Tanzania Prime Minister Joseph Warioba, and Dr. John Hardman, Carter Center president and CEO, will lead the Carter Center's international observation delegation for the January 2011 referendum on the self-determination of Southern Sudan.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Dec. 21, 2010: Tutu, Carter: Time to Move on Mideast Peace]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/editorials_speeches/tutu-carter-mideast-peace-usatoday122110.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[This op-ed by Jimmy Carter and Desmond Tutu was published Dec. 21, 2010 by USA TODAY. For nearly two decades, there have been peace processes in the Middle East but no peace. In recent visits to the region &#151; including Israel and the occupied Palestinian territory &#151; we have heard a consistent message: People want peace but are skeptical about the process and have little faith in the international community to deliver.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Dec. 20, 2010: Miracle Medicine Mends Nigerian Tailor's Eyesight]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/h/river_blindness/zaki-baushe-nigerian-tailors-eysight.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[38-year-old Zaki Baushe holds a thin metal needle in his left hand as he deftly angles a thread through its eye. As a tailor in Akwanga local government area, Nasarawa State, Nigeria, it is an act that he has repeated thousands of times throughout his life. Yet several years ago, Baushe was in danger of losing this skill entirely.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Dec. 15, 2010: Carter Center Finds Southern Sudan Voter Registration Credible, Strong Step Toward Referendum Despite Some Weaknesses]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/sudan-121510.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[In a statement issued today, The Carter Center reported that although the voter registration for the Southern Sudan Referendum on self-determination faced several logistical, procedural, and security challenges, the process was generally credible and represents a strong step toward the successful conduct of the referendum.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Dec. 13, 2010: The Carter Center:  The Year In Review ]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/cc/2010-in-review.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[2010 highlights of the peace and health work of The Carter Center.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Dec. 9, 2010: Donor Contributions Critical to Success of Onchocerciasis Elimination Program for the Americas]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/oepa-donor-contributions.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Standing in his school's courtyard in El Xab, Guatemala, a blindfolded boy swings a large stick toward an enormous pi&#241;ata shaped like a fly. Though the scene is a cheerful one, the children are learning something meaningful about the power of their community and country to fight the debilitating disease river blindness (onchocerciasis), which is spread by the bites of black flies that breed in swiftly flowing rivers.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Dec. 6, 2010: Progress on Neglected Disease is Moot If We Neglect to Count (PDF)]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/resources/pdfs/news/health_publications/itfde/DRH-Progress-NTDs-Moot-if-Neglect-Count-120610.pdf]]></link><description><![CDATA[This op-ed, by Carter Center Health Programs Vice President Donald R. Hopkins, M.D., M.P.H., was published in the Dec. 6, 2010, edition of Nature Medicine. This shortened version of the full magazine is reprinted with permission. The complete issue can be viewed at: http://www.nature.com/nm/index.html. The recent global campaign launched against a select number of neglected tropical diseases is a welcome development. But we should be as careful about measuring progress toward the control or elimination of these diseases as we are about choosing which ones to target.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Dec. 4, 2010: Carter Center Statement on the Cote d'Ivoire Election (En anglais et en fran&#231;ais)]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/cotedivoire-120410.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center congratulates Alassane Ouattara on his election as president of Cote d'Ivoire.  The Center equally appreciates the efforts of Prime Minister Guillaume Soro to ensure the credibility of the entire electoral process. ]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Dec. 2, 2010: Statement by Former U.S. President Jimmy Carter on the Cote d'Ivoire Election (En anglais et en fran&#231;ais)]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/cotedivoire-120210.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[We at The Carter Center congratulate the people of Cote d'Ivoire for a successful presidential election, which now offers hope for a peaceful, prosperous, and democratic future.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Dec. 2, 2010: Final Statement on Run-off Election in Guinea and the Post-Election Period: Carter Center Commends Guineans on Successful Elections and Urges Peaceful Acceptance of Final Results (En anglais et en fran&#231;ais)]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/guinea-120210.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[In a statement released today, The Carter Center concluded that the conduct of Guinea's presidential electoral processes was broadly consistent with the country's international and regional obligations for genuine democratic elections.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Dec. 1, 2010: Jimmy Carter and Jim Kolbe Recommend the U.S. Congress to Renew and Extend the Andean Trade Promotion and Drug Eradication Act (English and En Espa&#241;ol)]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/andean-US-120110.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[In a letter to key people in Washington sent on Nov. 22, 2010, former U.S. President Jimmy Carter and former Representative Jim Kolbe requested the renewal and extension of the Andean Trade Promotion and Drug Eradication Act (ATPDEA), set to expire in December 2010.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Nov. 30, 2010: Cote d'Ivoire Presidential Run-Off Election: High Voter Turnout Amid Political Tension (En anglais et en fran&#231;ais)]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/cotedivoire-113010.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center found high voter turnout for the presidential run-off election in Cote d'Ivoire despite an often tense and sometimes violent political campaign.  The Center notes with special concern that several deaths occurred in election day violence and calls on the two presidential candidates, Laurent Gbagbo and Alassane Ouattara, to remind their supporters of the need to wait for the announcement of results without further incident.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Nov. 24, 2010: Carter Center Statement on Sudan Referendum: Strong Start to Registration But Urgent Action Needed to Ensure Broad Participation]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/sudan-112410.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center welcomes the successful opening of voter registration for the Southern Sudan Referendum on self-determination and congratulates the Southern Sudan Referendum Commission (SSRC) and Southern Sudan Referendum Bureau (SSRB) on their preparations for the first days of registration, particularly in Southern Sudan where the process is challenged by difficult logistics. The Carter Center urges the SSRC to deliver additional materials to the referendum centers , where high demand is rapidly depleting supplies.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Nov. 24, 2010: Carter Center Urges End to Negative Campaign Rhetoric in Cote d'Ivoire's Presidential Run-Off Election (En anglais et en fran&#231;ais)]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/cotedivoire-112410.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center urges Cote d'Ivoire's presidential candidates to refrain from the use of negative campaign rhetoric, including personal attacks made in a threatening tone, and reminds candidates and their supporters of the code of conduct and other rules governing electoral behavior.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Nov. 24, 2010: Listen to North Korea]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/editorials_speeches/jc-listen-to-north-korea.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[This op-ed by former U.S. President Jimmy Carter was published, Nov. 24, 2010, by The Washington Post. No one can completely understand the motivations of the North Koreans, but it is entirely possible that their recent revelation of their uranium enrichment centrifuges and Pyongyang's shelling of a South Korean island Tuesday are designed to remind the world that they deserve respect in negotiations that will shape their future. Ultimately, the choice for the United States may be between diplomatic niceties and avoiding a catastrophic confrontation.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Nov. 23, 2010: The Carter Center Urges Swift Resolution to Nepal's Political Deadlock, Issues Report on Local Political and Peace Process ]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/nepal-112310.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Mistrust among Nepal's political leaders, failure to implement previous commitments, and repeated unsuccessful efforts to form a new government pose threats to the peace process and constitutional drafting.  Swift resolution to the ongoing political deadlock is needed to get the process back on track. Meanwhile, key deadlines are approaching rapidly: the U.N. Mission in Nepal is scheduled to leave in January 2011 and the deadline for a new constitution is May 28, 2011.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Nov. 19, 2010: The Carter Center Urges Calm, Restraint in Guinea (En anglais et en fran&#231;ais)]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/guinea-111910.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center appeals to Guinea's political party leaders to allow the Supreme Court to resolve any disputes over election results and to reiterate their appeals for calm. At the same time, the Center welcomes pledges made by both candidates to constitute a government of national unity as a gesture of reconciliation regardless of who is declared winner by the Supreme Court.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Nov. 15, 2010: The Carter Center Deploys More than 50 Observers to Monitor Sudan's Voter Registration]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/sudan-111510.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center deployed more than 50 observers across Sudan and overseas on Nov. 12 to observe the voter registration process for the Southern Sudan referendum on self-determination. The current deployment significantly increases the size of the Center's international observation mission and expands its presence to out-of-country registration locations in eight countries during the registration process, which was formally launched today by the Southern Sudan Referendum Commission (SSRC). The 56 observers join the Center's team of 16 long-term observers and additional core staff in Sudan.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Nov. 11, 2010: Public Health Officials Confirm Significant Progress Toward the Goal of Elimination of River Blindness in Latin America by 2012 ]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/iaco-111110.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Public health officials at the 20th Inter-American Conference on Onchocerciasis in Antigua, Guatemala, confirmed that more than one-third of all Latin Americans who ran the risk of contracting river blindness (onchocerciasis), a leading cause of preventable blindness, are no longer at risk.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Nov. 10, 2010: Veterans and Mental Health Care - Op-Ed by Rosalynn Carter and Patrick Kennedy]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/editorials_speeches/veterans-111110.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[This op-ed by former First Lady Rosalynn Carter and U.S. Rep. Patrick Kennedy, D-R.I., was published in the Nov. 10, 2010 issue of the Atlanta Journal-Constitution. This Veterans Day, Americans will pay tribute to our military veterans, the men and women who have returned home from Iraq and Afghanistan. We will remember also those who still serve. However, truly honoring our armed forces means doing all we can to help address the disturbing trends of suicide, family violence, substance abuse, post-traumatic stress disorder, depression and other mental health conditions found among our troops as a result of combat. Although they often are invisible, combat-related neurological injuries are wounds of war nonetheless and should be treated with the same urgency as we would treat other injuries. ]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Nov. 9, 2010: Guinea's Transitional Elections Marked by Peaceful Voting; Commitment to Transparency in Final Results Is Important]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/guinea-110910.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center congratulates Guineans for the peaceful and orderly conduct of voting and the high-level of participation for the Nov. 7, 2010, presidential run-off election.  The successful voting process is an overwhelming testament of Guineans' profound desire to express their will at the ballot box and to complete their historic democratic transition.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Nov. 9, 2010: Conversations at The Carter Center, "After the War: Mental Health and a Veteran's Journey Home"]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/conversations-110410.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Reservations are still available for the Nov. 9 Conversations at The Carter Center event, "After the War: Mental Health and a Veteran's Journey Home." In addition, attendees now will have the chance to participate in a special book signing immediately following the panel discussion.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Nov. 3, 2010: 10 Million Ethiopians to Receive Free Antibiotic During Historic MalTra Week in Amhara Region]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/maltra-110310.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The largest single event in trachoma control history is underway. This week, the Lions-Carter Center SightFirst project, the Amhara National Regional State Health Bureau, and the International Trachoma Initiative will provide Pfizer-donated antibiotic treatment to 10 million Ethiopians at risk for blinding trachoma.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Nov. 2, 2010: Cote d'Ivoire Presidential Election Marks Historic Milestone in Peace Process (En anglais et en fran&#231;ais)]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/cotedivoire-110210.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Oct. 31 presidential election in Cote d'Ivoire was conducted in a calm environment with a high-level of voter participation. These elections marked a crucial step in Cote d'Ivoire's peace process and gave voters the opportunity to elect their next president in the country's first truly open contest.  The Ivoirian people have exercised their right to vote; they also have the right to have their vote accurately recorded and ultimately respected by all candidates.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Nov. 2, 2010: General Yakubu Gowon to Lead Carter Center Delegation to Observe Guinea's Nov. 7 Runoff Election]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/guinea-110210.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Former Nigeria Head of State General Yakubu Gowon and Carter Center Vice President for Peace Programs John Stremlau will lead the Carter Center's international observation of Guinea's Nov. 7 runoff election. The Center's mission will deploy throughout the country 30 observers representing more than 13 nations.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Oct. 29, 2010: Carter Center Notes Progress But Urges Critical Steps to Ensure Credible Voter Registration and Referenda Processes In Sudan]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/sudan-102910.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[In its latest statement on Sudan's referenda processes, The Carter Center noted important progress by the Southern Sudan Referendum Commission (SSRC) and Southern Sudan Referendum Bureau (SSRB) in establishing and swearing in nearly all of the county subcommittees of Southern Sudan and publishing a referendum calendar.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Oct. 29, 2010: Former First Lady Rosalynn Carter to Lead Two Major Forums on Veterans' Mental Health at The Carter Center]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/veterans-mental-health-2010-forums.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The unique challenges for mental health care and community reintegration faced by National Guard and reserve veterans returning from Iraq and Afghanistan will be the topic of two events being held by The Carter Center in the two weeks prior to Veterans Day.  Both events will be webcast live.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Oct. 27, 2010: Carter Center Urges Calm in Guinea Ahead of Run-off Election (En anglais et en fran&#231;ais)]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/guinea-102710.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center calls on all actors involved in Guinea's electoral process to contribute to a peaceful and orderly environment in the period before the presidential run-off election, while ensuring respect for the rights and safety of all individuals, no matter their conviction.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Oct. 27, 2010: John Kufuor to Lead Carter Center Delegation to Observe Cote d'Ivoire's Oct. 31 Election]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/cotedivoire-102710.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Former Ghana President John Kufuor will co-lead the Carter Center's international election observation delegation to Cote d'Ivoire along with Dr. John Stremlau, Carter Center vice president for peace programs. The Center's mission will also include 40 observers representing  23 different countries.  These presidential elections mark an important step in the country's peace process, as it seeks to put its civil war firmly in the past.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Oct. 25, 2010: Trip Report-Visit by the Elders to Gaza, Egypt, Syria, Jordan, Israel, and the West Bank, Oct. 15-23, 2010]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/trip_reports/middle-east-2010.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Led by Mary Robinson, former president of Ireland, a group of Elders visited Gaza, Egypt, Syria, Jordan, Israel, and the West Bank including East Jerusalem. The aim of our visit was to encourage a just and secure peace for Israel and its neighbors based on international law.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Oct. 20, 2010: Making Inventions Out of Necessity to Fight River Blindness]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/h/river_blindness/philippe-nwane-aspirator.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Dedicated to fighting river blindness in his native Cameroon, Carter Center epidemiologist Philippe Nwane employs creativity and innovation to monitor the debilitating parasitic infection.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Oct. 19, 2010: Carter Center Statement on Settlement Agreement on Georgia Mental Health Services]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/ga-mental-health-services-10192010.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[We applaud the hard work of the Department of Justice and the State of Georgia for reaching this groundbreaking settlement agreement, which will mean that thousands of people with disabilities in Georgia will receive services in their own homes and communities, instead of in the state hospitals.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Oct. 19, 2010: Statement by Former U.S. President Jimmy Carter on Guinea Elections]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/guinea-101910.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center welcomes Guinea's progress toward holding its historic runoff presidential election, and we urge both candidates, their supporters, and each CENI commissioner to ensure that the constitutional processes are respected to ensure that the will of the Guinean people can be freely expressed. ]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Oct. 12, 2010: Guinea Worm Eradication and River Blindness Elimination Receive Major Boost with U.S. $1 Million Donation from OPEC Fund: Signing Ceremony Takes Place at The Carter Center]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/ofid-101210.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Today, during a special ceremony in Atlanta, former U.S. President and Carter Center Founder Jimmy Carter received on behalf of The Carter Center two new pledges&#151;$500,000 toward the Guinea Worm Eradication Program and $500,000 toward the Onchocerciasis Elimination Program for the Americas (OEPA)&#151;from the OPEC Fund for International Development, represented by His Excellency Director General Suleiman Jasir Al-Herbish. ]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Oct. 5, 2010: Carter Center Deploys Election Observers to C&#244;te d'Ivoire]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/cotedivoire-100510.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center deployed 10 long-term observers to regions around C&#244;te d'Ivoire this week to assess preparations for the Oct.31, 2010, presidential election.  The observers will meet with government and election authorities, political parties, civil society organizations, and domestic observer groups, as well as the United Nations and the international community.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sept. 30, 2010: Carter Center Statement on Ecuador (English and En Espa&#241;ol)]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/ecuador-093010.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center is deeply concerned about recent events in Ecuador and expresses its support for the constitutional government of this country and its democratically-elected President Rafael Correa Delgado. ]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sept. 30, 2010: Update on Former U.S. President Jimmy Carter From MetroHealth Medical Center and The Carter Center]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/carter-update-093010.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[President Carter was discharged from MetroHealth Medical Center today at 1:15 p.m., after recovering from a gastric viral infection. He will resume his schedule with a meeting this week in Washington, D.C. ]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sept. 29, 2010: Update on Former U.S. President Jimmy Carter from MetroHealth and The Carter Center (6:40 p.m. EST)]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/carter-update2-092910.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Former President Jimmy Carter is continuing to recover from the stomach distress that was reported earlier. ]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sept. 29, 2010: Tea Party and Me]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/editorials_speeches/tea-party-092910.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[This op-ed by former U.S. President Jimmy Carter was published in the Sept. 29, 2010 issue of USA Today. A number of readers of my new book have noted parallels between today's frustrated and even angry mood and a similar mood in the mid-1970s. Indeed, in some ways my successful campaign for the presidency in 1976 resembled the Tea Party movement of today. ]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sept. 29, 2010: Update on Former U.S. President Jimmy Carter from MetroHealth and The Carter Center (11:50 a.m. EST)]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/carter-update-092910.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Former President Jimmy Carter will remain at MetroHealth Medical Center overnight.  His medical team continues to observe his progress.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sept. 29, 2010: Former U.S. President Jimmy Carter Resting Comfortably at MetroHealth (7:30 a.m. EST)]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/carter-statement-092910.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Former President Jimmy Carter is feeling normal this morning. H is doctors at MetroHealth Medical Center recommended additional observation during the day.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sept. 28, 2010: Carter Center Deploys International Referendum Observers in Sudan]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/sudan-092810.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center deployed 16 long-term observers from 12 nations this week to assess the referendum process in Southern Sudan and in the areas in the North where voting will occur. Four two-person observer teams have been deployed in Southern Sudan, three teams in Northern Sudan, and one team in Abyei.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sept. 24, 2010: Carter Center Heartened by Guinea's Election Date Announcement and Recent Progress Toward Organizing Runoff Election]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/guinea-092410.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center election observation mission in Guinea is heartened by the Independent National Electoral Commission's (CENI) announcement recommending that the country's delayed run-off presidential election should be held on Oct. 10.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sept. 16, 2010: North Korea Wants to Make a Deal]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/editorials_speeches/nkorea-nytimes-091610.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[This op-ed by former U.S. President Jimmy Carter was published in the Sept. 16, 2010, edition of The New York Times. During my recent travels to North Korea and China, I received clear, strong signals that Pyongyang wants to restart negotiations on a comprehensive peace treaty with the United States and South Korea and on the denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula. ]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sept. 13, 2010: Trip Report by Former U.S. President Jimmy Carter to China, Sept. 4-10, 2010]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/trip_reports/china-090410.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The purposes of our trip were to promote the expanding projects of The Carter Center in China, to enhance relations between the U.S. and the P.R.C., to fulfill our promises of last year to visit the World Expo in Shanghai, to ascertain opinions of South Korean and Chinese officials regarding North Korea, and to discuss other issues of mutual interest]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sept. 3, 2010: Carter Center Congratulates Liberia on Passage of Freedom of Information Bill]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/liberia-foi-090310.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center congratulates the Liberian National Legislature for its unanimous passage of the Freedom of Information (FOI) bill.  The Carter Center also commends the FOI Consortium, comprised of representatives of more than 10 civil society organizations and government agencies including the Ministry of Information, Culture, and Tourism, for its commitment to advancing the right of access to information in Liberia.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[August 27, 2010: State Department Statement on Release of American in North Korea]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/state-dept-082710-north-korea.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[We welcome the release of Aijalon Mahli Gomes and are relieved that he will soon be safely reunited with his family. We appreciate former President Carter's humanitarian effort and welcome North Korea's decision to grant Mr. Gomes special amnesty and allow him to return to the United States.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Aug. 27, 2010: Statement of the Family of Aijalon Gomes]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/family-statement-gomes.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The family of Aijalon Gomes feels blessed today to be able to welcome Aijalon home and into the arms of all those who love him.  This has been a long, dark and difficult period&#151;for Aijalon and for our family.  We are grateful to all the people who made today possible.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Aug. 26, 2010: Statement from The Carter Center on President Carter's Mission to North Korea]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/north-korea-mission-082610.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Former President Jimmy Carter announced that he is leaving Pyongyang, North Korea, this morning accompanied by Mr. Aijalon Mahli Gomes.  Mr. Gomes was imprisoned in January of this year and later sentenced to eight years of hard labor with a fine of about $600,000 for the crime of illegal entry into North Korea. At the request of President Carter, and for humanitarian purposes, Mr. Gomes was granted amnesty by the Chairman of the National Defense Commission, Kim Jong-Il.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Aug. 20, 2010: Journey to Liberia: Carter Center Staffer Reflects on Country's Mental Health Needs, New Initiative]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://blog.cartercenter.org/2010/08/20/journey-to-liberia-carter-center-staffer-reflects-on-country%27s-mental-health-needs-new-initiative/]]></link><description><![CDATA[Many Liberians suffer from trauma, depression, and other mental health issues following more than a decade of civil conflict. With only one psychiatrist in the entire country, and just a handful of nurses with mental health training, treating those who suffer from mental illnesses has been almost impossible. Jane Bigham, assistant program coordinator for the Carter Center's Mental Health Program, recently traveled to the West African country. Below, she reflects on her journey and what a new Carter Center mental health initiative will mean for the people of Liberia.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Aug. 19, 2010: Jimmy Carter Featured in Two Independent Documentaries Screening at The Carter Center on August 21]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/docufest-082110.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Former U.S. President Jimmy Carter is featured in two independently produced documentaries screening at The Carter Center as part of DocuFest Atlanta's 5th annual, five-day international film festival.  Beginning at 2 p.m. on Saturday, Aug. 21, take a rare inside look at the challenges facing Carter Center health workers in remote, impoverished areas as they eradicate an alien-like disease in the premier of "Foul Water / Fiery Serpent." ]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Aug. 19, 2010: Ugandan Man Helps Rid His Community of Onchocerciasis]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/publications/health/river_blindness_publications/profile-edirisa-wangwenyi.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[In the early 1990s, fear dominated the community of Jawe parish, found in Mbale district, Uganda. The Jawe clan's neighboring parishes, Buryango and Bulweta, were being plagued by an unknown ailment that attacked a person's skin and eyes. The disease left its victims unable to care for themselves or their families.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Aug. 19, 2010: Stadium Massacre Fuels Survivor's Commitment to Full Democracy for Guinea]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/publications/peace/democracy_publications/profile-bademba-diallo.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Quietly recalling the memory of people jumping from stadium walls to save their lives, and others falling like flies from the gunfire of soldiers, Bademba Diallo remembers thinking in the chaos of that afternoon: "you only die once."]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Aug. 16, 2010: As Nepal Struggles, Observers Keep Information Flowing]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/p/democracy/nepal-struggles-observers-provide-information.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[For Carter Center observer Antonia Staats, traveling by car in the Western Region of Nepal is a blessing and a curse. A car is necessary for reaching all of the region's 16 districts, where for six months last year, she monitored Nepal's challenging path to a new government and long-term peace. But with poor infrastructure in many parts of the country, Staats and the other observers on her team often encountered roads that were submerged or blocked by landslides from a monsoon.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Aug. 16, 2010: Carter Center Launches First of Its Kind Database to Support Democratic Elections]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/obligations-democratic-elections-database.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center this week launched the Database of Obligations for Democratic Elections, the first of its kind to consolidate more than 150 sources of international law related to human rights and elections that can be used by international and domestic election observers to assess elections. The database represents a critical step in building consensus toward a single common set of internationally accepted criteria for assessing democratic elections.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Aug. 4, 2010 : Public Radio International Highlights Judicial System in  Liberia]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://blog.cartaercenter.org/2010/08/04/public-radio-international-highlights-judicial-system-in-liberia/]]></link><description><![CDATA[Public Radio International's "The World" examines Liberia's struggle with land disputes, as citizens return home after the war to find others living on land they claim as their own, in a story aired Aug. 3. ]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Aug. 4, 2010: Carter Center Experts and Partners Chronicle "Nigeria's Triumph" Over Ancient Guinea Worm Disease in American Journal of Tropical Medicine and Hygiene Article]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/nigerias-triumph-080410.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[In the August 2010 issue of the American Journal of Tropical Medicine and Hygiene, a new paper co-authored by experts from the Nigeria Ministry of Health, The Carter Center, and the World Health Organization, details Nigeria's historic triumph over many challenges to successfully eliminate the ancient waterborne plague Guinea worm disease (also known as dracunculiasis).]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[July 26, 2010: Africa: World Losing the War on Virulent, Preventable Childhood Diseases]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/editorials_speeches/jimmy-carter-koffi-annan.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[This op-ed by Jimmy Carter and Koffi Annan appeared  in news outlets including AllAfrica.com, Nigeria's Business Day, and UAE National.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[July 24, 2010: The Carter Center Welcomes Preparation for Guinea's Presidential Run-off Election Despite Operational Flaws in Results Process (En anglais et en fran&#231;ais)]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/guinea-runoff-072410.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center congratulates all Guinean presidential candidates and commends that the settlement of election disputes brought to the attention of the Supreme Court has been]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[July 22, 2010: Carter Center Calls for End to East Jerusalem Deportations, Respect for International Law]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/palestine-072210.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center expresses deep concern about the revocation of Jerusalem residency rights for three members of the Palestinian Legislative Council (PLC): Muhammad Abu-Teir, Ahmad Attoun, and Muhammad Totah, as well as the former Palestinian Minister of Jerusalem Affairs Khaled Abu Arafeh.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[July 12, 2010: Journalism Fellow Kelly Kennedy Uncovers the Many Faces of Post-Traumatic Stress Disorder  ]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/h/mental_health/kelly-kennedy-pstd-study.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[A mortuary services soldier came home angry and suicidal, having processed the dead faces and body parts of numerous service members. A well-loved first sergeant killed himself in front of his men. A platoon that had just lost several soldiers refused to go back on patrol, fearful that their rage would lead to more death.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[July 9, 2010: The Carter Center Awards 2010-2011 Rosalynn Carter Fellowships for Mental Health Journalism]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/mhj-fellows-2010-2011.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[After a highly competitive selection process, the Carter Center's Rosalynn Carter Fellowships for Mental Health Journalism, one of the only journalism fellowships exclusively for mental health, announced today the winners of its 2010-2011 awards.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[July 7, 2010: Miracle Medicine Mends Nigerian Tailor's Eyesight]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/h/river_blindness/zaki-baushe-nigerian-tailors-eysight.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[38-year-old Zaki Baushe holds a thin metal needle in his left hand as he deftly angles a thread through its eye. As a tailor in Akwanga local government area, Nasarawa State, Nigeria, it is an act that he has repeated thousands of times throughout his life. Yet several years ago, Baushe was in danger of losing this skill entirely.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[July 7, 2010: Q&A With Pewee Flomoku:  Son of Liberia]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/p/conflict_resolution/pewee-flomoku-son-of-liberty.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[In 2003, Liberia began to emerge from 14 years of brutal civil war that ravaged the nation's physical, economic, and social foundations. A central challenge of reconstruction is to create a functional and accountable justice system, a prerequisite for lasting peace and democratic progress. While the nation's postconflict peace-building efforts have made remarkable progress, many challenges remain in the effort to ensure accountability and provide justice for all Liberians.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[July 7, 2010: Statement from former U.S. President Jimmy Carter on Juanita Kreps]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/juanita-kreps-statement.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Rosalynn and I were saddened to learn of Juanita Kreps' passing and extend our thoughts and prayers to her family. ]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[July 6, 2010: Fellows Uncover Whole Face of Mental Illness]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/publications/health/mental_health_publications/fellows-uncover-mental-illness.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[This week six U.S. and four international journalists will be chosen to participate in a yearlong fellowship to explore one of the most prevalent public health issues that is still shrouded in myth and mystery &#151; mental illness.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[June 22, 2010: General Yakubu Gowon to Lead Carter Center Delegation to Observe Guinea's June 27 Elections (En anglais et en fran&#231;ais)]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/guinea-062210.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center announced today that General Dr. Yakubu Gowon, Nigeria's former head of state, will co-lead the Center's international election observation delegation to Guinea along with Dr. John Stremlau, Carter Center vice president for peace programs. The Carter Center mission will also include more than 30 observers representing over 15 different nations deployed throughout the country.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[June 22, 2010: Carter Center: Land Commitments in Nepal's Peace Process Only Partially Fulfilled (कृपया नेपालीमा पढ्नुहोस्)]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/nepal-062210.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[In a report released today, The Carter Center has found that the Maoists and successive governments have each only partially fulfilled land commitments as outlined in the November 2006 Comprehensive Peace Agreement (CPA) and subsequent agreements. In those accords, the Maoists committed to return land seized during the conflict and the then-Seven Party Alliance government committed to formulate policies for scientific land reform.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[June 21, 2010: Nomadic Groups Pose Challenge in Push to Eliminate Guinea Worm Disease From Southern Sudan (Video Feature)]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/h/guinea_worm/cattle-camps-sudan.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The lives of an estimated 70 percent of the people living in Southern Sudan are intrinsically entwined with their cattle.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[June 21, 2010: Carter Center Appoints New Members to Board of Councilors]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/boc-062110.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center, a not-for-profit organization advancing peace and health worldwide, recently appointed 18 new members to its Board of Councilors, bringing its total membership to 228.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[June 21, 2010: Carter Center Encouraged by Electoral Campaign in Guinea;  Urges Steps on Electoral Preparations and Voter Education (En anglais et en fran&#231;ais)]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/guinea-062110.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center observation mission in Guinea is encouraged by the positive tone of the electoral campaign in Guinea, including candidates' messages promoting reconciliation and transcending ethnic boundaries, and by the National Electoral Commission's (CENI) commitment to inclusive elections.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[June 4, 2010: Carter Center Statement on the Death of Floribert Chebeya Bahizire]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/floribert-chebeya-bahizire-statement.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center is deeply saddened by the death of leading Congolese human rights defender Floribert Chebeya Bahizire and calls upon the U.N. Mission in the Democratic Republic of the Congo (DRC) to undertake an immediate and independent investigation of the circumstances surrounding his death on Wednesday, June 2.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[June 2, 2010: Carter Center Calls on the International Community to End the Siege of Gaza (English and Arabic)]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/gaza-siege-060210.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center expresses deep regret for the loss of life and condemns the unprovoked and illegal Israeli assault on the humanitarian Gaza aid flotilla in international waters.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[May 27, 2010: Helping Our Vets Here at Home]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/editorials_speeches/bornemann-ajc-052710.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[This op-ed by Thomas Bornemann was published May 27, 2010, by The Atlanta Journal-Constitution. On Memorial Day, families across Georgia recognize the bravery and sacrifices of men and women in the armed forces. Yet, as we remember the fallen, a disturbing trend has become apparent &#151; more and more of our military heroes are losing their lives not in combat, but from the often hidden, emotional wounds of war.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[May 25, 2010: Video Journal:  Pioneering Approach Brings River Blindness To Brink of Elimination In Sudanese Community]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/h/river_blindness/sudan-video-journal-2010.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Abu Hamad, a vast and isolated  desert community 500 kilometers from the Sudanese capitol Khartoum, is on the verge of disproving a long-held belief among public health professionals that river blindness (onchocerciasis) cannot be eliminated in Africa due to poor health care delivery and the disease's prevalence.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[May 24, 2010: Carter Center Launches Election Observation Mission to Guinea]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/guinea-052410.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center will deploy eight long-term observers throughout Guinea this week to formally launch its international election observation mission of the country's June 27 elections.  The mission is supported by an office in Conakry, which was established in mid-May and led by Field Office Representative John Koogler.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[May 21, 2010: "Anyak vs. the Guinea Worm," New York Times video]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/publications/health/guinea_worm_publications/kristof-052110.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Nicholas D. Kristof follows a young Sudanese boy with a parasite infection who is quarantined for treatment.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[May 17, 2009: Guinea Worm Eradication Efforts Gain Further Momentum With Significant Case Reductions in 2009]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/h/guinea_worm/2009_total.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center-led drive to eradicate Guinea worm disease gained significant momentum in 2009, with an all-time low of 3,190 total cases reported -- a 31 percent decrease from 2008.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[May 14, 2010: Carter Center Launches Local Dispute Management Program in Liberia]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/liberia-051410.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center is launching an 18-month USAID-funded project to strengthen the capacity of Liberia's local indigenous leaders to manage local disputes, as well as to provide the officers of the National Traditional Council enhanced ability to respond to major disputes.  The project is implemented in partnership with the Ministry of Internal Affairs and the National Traditional Council.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[May 11, 2010: Guinea Worm Village Volunteer Viviana Kolong Works to Protect Her Community from Debilitating Disease]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/h/guinea_worm/profile-viviana-kolong.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[It is early morning in Molujore village of Terekeka County in Southern Sudan, and Viviana Kolong, a 30-year-old mother of three, dresses carefully in a cool, yellow and white cotton dress and orange flip flops, adding a black bracelet and white beaded rosary to complete her outfit. As the wind picks up and the temperature starts its punishing rise, Kolong leaves her mud hut, passing by her home's empty grain stores. As usual, it will be a long day.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[May 11, 2010: Ghanaian ATI Conference Participant Coordinating Campaign for Country's Right to Information Law]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/p/access_to_information/profile-nana-oye-lithur.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[In Ghana, where the government is currently debating the passage of a right to information bill, Nana Oye Lithur coordinates the campaign to ensure the proposed law will conform to international standards and enhance transparency and accountability.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[May 10, 2010: Carter Center Reports Widespread Irregularities in Sudan's Vote Tabulation and Strongly Urges Steps to Increase Transparency]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/sudan-051010.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[In a statement released today, The Carter Center reported that based on its direct observations, Sudan's vote tabulation process was highly chaotic, non-transparent, and vulnerable to electoral manipulation. As a result, the Center is concerned about the accuracy of the preliminary results announced by the National Elections Commission (NEC), as procedures and safeguards intended to ensure accuracy and transparency have not been systematically applied and in some areas have been routinely bypassed.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[May 4, 2010: Join Brookings Institution Scholar Cheng Li in the Field to Study Progress in China's Rural Village Elections]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/p/china/brookings-scholar-studies-china-elections.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Cheng Li, director of research and senior fellow at the Brookings Institution's John L. Thornton China Center, was part of a small Carter Center delegation that traveled to China in March to advance the Center's programming efforts there.  These include working to help standardize the vast array of electoral procedures taking place in local communities and foster better governance, as well as rural and urban community building and civic education about rights, laws, and political participation.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[April 29, 2010: Former First Lady Rosalynn Carter Launches Tour for "Within Our Reach: Ending the Mental Health Crisis"]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/cc/rosalynn-carter-2010-book-tour.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Former First Lady Rosalynn Carter has been deeply invested in mental health issues since her husband's gubernatorial campaign when she saw firsthand the horrific, dehumanizing treatment of people with mental illnesses. Using stories from her 35 years of public service to discuss the larger issues at hand, Mrs. Carter crafts an intimate and powerful account of a subject previously shrouded in stigma and shadow that affects us all.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[April 28, 2010: Winning the Worm War]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/publications/health/guinea_worm_publications/kristof-winning-worm-war.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[This New York Times op-ed by Nicholas D. Kristof was published April 28, 2010. Former President Jimmy Carter's plan to eradicate Guinea worm worldwide is succeeding because local villagers are involved in the effort.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[April 28, 2010: Sudan's Imperfect But Important Elections]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/editorials_speeches/jc-latimes-sudan-elections-042810.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[This op-ed by Jimmy Carter was published April 28, 2010, by the Los Angeles Times. On Monday, the results of the April 11-15 elections in Sudan were announced: The ruling party's President Omar Hassan Ahmed Bashir won 68 percent of the vote.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[April 22, 2010: Friends of The Inter-American Democratic Charter Issue Statement on Crisis in Nicaragua (English and Spanish)]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/fdc-042210.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The decision last year by a part of the Nicaraguan Supreme Court to declare unconstitutional article 147 prohibiting consecutive re-election in the 1995 Constitution allowed President Daniel Ortega to propose his candidacy for reelection in 2011.  Equally troubling was the January 2010 executive decree which extended the terms of congressionally appointed state authorities, including members of the Supreme Electoral Tribunal and Supreme Court.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[April 21, 2010: Statement by Former U.S. President Jimmy Carter]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/dorothy-height-statement.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Rosalynn and I are deeply saddened to learn of the death of Dorothy Height.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[April 19, 2010: Trip Report by Former U.S. President Jimmy Carter to Sudan, April 7-18, 2010]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/trip_reports/sudan-april2010.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center has been deeply involved in Sudan since 1986, when we launched a program that increased the nation's annual wheat production from 160,000 to 1 million tons. Since then, we have had major health programs and efforts to promote peace and democracy. This current project is to monitor elections for local, state, and national offices throughout Sudan, plus separate ones for the ten states in South Sudan.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[April 17, 2010: The Carter Center Election Observation Mission in Sudan Presidential, Gubernatorial, and Legislative Elections, April 2010 ]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/sudan-041710.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center commends the Sudanese people for the generally peaceful polling process to date and urges that the remaining stages of counting, tabulation, and posting of results be carried out transparently and accurately. In addition, the limited political opening around the elections should be expanded to ensure respect for Sudan's constitutional human rights and fundamental freedoms, and leaders from all parties should engage in genuine dialogue to address the key challenges facing Sudan.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[April 16, 2010: Millions Mobilize April 17-23 in Amhara Region For Trachoma Treatments, Malaria Health Education]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/h/maltra/maltra-2010-millions-mobilize-video.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Impoverished communities in Amhara Region, Ethiopia&#151;the world's most trachoma-endemic area&#151;are harnessing an innovative and far-reaching approach to treating and preventing this blinding bacterial infection.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[April 16, 2010: Carter Center Successfully Integrates Antibiotic Distribution, Health Education During Intensive Weeklong Efforts Against Blinding Trachoma, Malaria]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/h/maltra/maltra-2010-update.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[With a population of approximately 17 million, the Amhara Region of Ethiopia is one of the most severely affected trachoma-endemic areas in the world. There are currently more than 15 million people at risk of infection and approximately 470,000 people visually impaired as a result of trichiasis, the blinding form of the disease. In addition, the region is susceptible to seasonal malaria epidemics, putting the majority of the population at risk for the potentially fatal disease.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[April 16, 2010: Meet Teshome Gebre: Lion of Disease Prevention in Ethiopia]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/h/maltra/profile-teshome-gebre.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Teshome Gebre, the Carter Center's country representative for health programs in Ethiopia, likes to joke that he has been in public health service for what seems like 100 years. Yet, it's impossible to ignore the great joy Teshome has received from a lifetime dedicated to fighting disease in his native Ethiopia.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[April 9, 2010: The Carter Center Calls on Cote d'Ivoire Political Leaders to Keep Election Preparations on Track (En anglais et en fran&#231;ais)]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/cotedivoire-040910.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center calls on political leaders in Cote d'Ivoire to renew their commitment to genuine democratic elections and ensure necessary steps are taken to realize that goal as soon as possible.  Cote d'Ivoire has made important strides to keep the peace process on track, but further delay could reverse those achievements.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[April 8, 2010: PBS's "NewsHour," CNN.com, and Public Radio International's "The World" Report on Southern Sudan, Last Bastion for Historic Campaign to Eradicate Guinea Worm Disease]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/h/guinea_worm/guinea-worm-southern-sudan-media-coverage.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[In early February 2010, a global health unit from PBS's "NewsHour," Public Radio International's "The World," and CNN.com visited Southern Sudan with former U.S. President Jimmy Carter and Center health staff to explore progress toward Guinea worm disease eradication in this last bastion for the parasitic infection.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[April 8, 2010: Jimmy Carter to Lead Carter Center Delegation to Observe Sudan Elections]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/sudan-040810.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center announced today that former U.S. President Jimmy Carter, former Algerian Foreign Minister and member of the Elders Lakhdar Brahimi, Judge Joseph Warioba, and Carter Center President and CEO Dr. John Hardman will lead the Center's international election observation delegation to observe Sudan's April 2010 elections.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[April 6, 2010: CNN.com Features Major Coverage of Guinea Worm Eradication Efforts in Southern Sudan]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/h/guinea_worm/cnn-sudan-fiery-serpent.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Join CNN.com, the world's leading news Web site, for its major coverage of Southern Sudan's final struggle to wipe out Guinea worm disease. ]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[April 6, 2010: Sudan Can Rid World of a Horrible Disease]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/editorials_speeches/jc-cnn-sudan-guinea-worm.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[This op-ed by Jimmy Carter was published April 6, 2010, on CNN.com. Oppressed by war and poverty for generations, the Sudanese have struggled with terrible hardships. But the people of this vast country have a narrow window of hope to achieve progress by ridding both their nation and the world of a horrible disease forever.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[April 1, 2010: Long-Term Sudan Observers Impressed with Enthusiasm, Mobilization of Communities Readying for Elections]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/p/democracy/sudan-long-term-observers.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Carter Center long-term observers in Sudan, who have been deployed since August 2009, will soon be joined by a full delegation to observe the country's April elections. In teams of two, long-term observers have assessed pre-election developments, including voter registration in December. They face many challenges in their work but also have a unique opportunity to get to know the people and the places to which they are deployed.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[March 30, 2010: A Project for Haiti: The Eradication of Two Diseases]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/publications/health/itfde_publications/drh-haiti-nyt-editorial-response.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[This letter to the editor of the New York Times by Carter Center Vice President for Health Programs Dr. Donald R. Hopkins was published March 30, 2010, in response to the March 28, 2010 editorial "Making Haiti Whole."]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[March 29, 2010: Former U.S. President Jimmy Carter Receives the Catalonia International Prize]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/catalonia-prize-032910.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Former U.S. President Jimmy Carter was announced today as winner of the XXII edition of the Catalonia International Prize for his "heart and courage" in defense of peace and human rights worldwide.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[March 25, 2010: Innovative Smartphone Technology Streamlines Election Observation Process]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/p/democracy/smartphone-election-observation.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center, long at the forefront of the election observation field, is working with students at Georgia Tech to take the field forward again &#150; using smartphone technology to streamline the observation process and compile the findings of observers in an efficient and transparent way.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[March 24, 2010: Mayo Clinic Alumni Association 66th Meeting, Profile of Speaker: Dr. John Hardman (PDF)]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/resources/pdfs/news/health_publications/guinea_worm/MayoClinicMag-Winter2010-hardman.pdf]]></link><description><![CDATA[This article was published March 1, 2010, by the Mayo Alumni magazine. Carter Center President and CEO Dr. John Hardman (a Mayo Clinic alumnus) presented the prestigious Raymond D. Pruitt Lecture during the 2009 Mayo Clinic Alumni Association's biennial meeting. The lecture series honors individuals who have expertise in medical specialties or areas of research. Dr. Hardman's presentation on "Not Neglecting Neglected Diseases for 24 Years and Counting..." covered the Center's work to prevent diseases in the world's poorest countries in Asia, Africa and Latin America.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[March 24, 2010: Trip Report by Former U.S. President Jimmy Carter to Seoul, South Korea, March 20-24, 2010]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/trip_reports/south-korea-032410.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The primary purpose of our trip was to establish a partnership between Cyber University of Korea and the Rosalynn Carter Institute on Caregiving at Georgia Southwestern State University. This will put the Caregiving curriculum online for thousands of students in Korea and other nations.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[March 23, 2010: Remarks by Former U.S. President Jimmy Carter at Korea University, Seoul, Korea]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/editorials_speeches/jimmy-carter-speech-korea-university.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[A Nuclear North Korea and Peace in the Korean Peninsula? My speech will cover three main subjects, and I hope to stimulate some questions from the audience.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[March 22, 2010: Statement by Former U.S. President Jimmy Carter on the Death of Girija Prasad Koirala ]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/koirala-032210.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Former U.S. President Jimmy Carter sends his sincere condolences on the passing of Nepali Congress President and former Prime Minister Girija Prasad Koirala.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[March 21, 2010: Statement by Former U.S. President Jimmy Carter On the Death of Liz Carpenter]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/liz-carpenter-032210.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Rosalynn and I are saddened to learn of the death of Liz Carpenter, who was the assistant secretary of education for public affairs during my administration.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[March 18, 2010: Carter Center Welcomes Sudan's Elections Campaign, Urges Steps to Ensure Open and Inclusive Process]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/sudan-031810.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[In its latest statement on Sudan's electoral process, The Carter Center notes that while much has been achieved in organizing the 2010 elections, the country's first competitive elections since 1986, the process remains at risk on multiple fronts including the ability of candidates to campaign freely and the impact of delayed logistical preparations by the National Elections Commission (NEC).]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[March 15, 2010: Sudanese Domestic Election Observer Feels Sense of Responsibility To Next Generation]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/p/democracy/profile-Merekaje-Lorna.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Merekaje Lorna can't wait to vote. A domestic election observer trained by The Carter Center in Sudan, she believes she and other young Sudanese have a responsibility to contribute to credible elections for the sake of the next generation, and as her country approaches its first multi-party elections in 24 years, she looks forward to being able to choose her leaders.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[March 15, 2010: Siblings Work Together to Prevent Malaria in La Bomba, Dominican Republic]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/publications/health/itfde_publications/siblings-work-to-prevent-malaria.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Brother and sister Juan Tavares Rodriguez and Casilda Trejada Abreu live with their family in a pine board home in La Bomba, Dominican Republic.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[March 5, 2010: Carter Center Condemns Attacks on Journalists in Nepal]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/nepal-030510.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center expresses serious concern about the growing incidence of threats and attacks on media personnel in Nepal. ]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[March 4, 2010: Plan of Action to Advance the Right of Access to Information in Africa Released Today]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/ati-conference-africa-2010.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Participants from the African Regional Conference on the Right of Access to Information today released the Regional Findings and Plan of Action to advance the right in Africa.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sept. 28, 2010: Statement From The Carter Center]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/statement-092810.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[While on a flight to Cleveland, former U.S. President Jimmy Carter developed an upset stomach, and, upon arrival, was taken to MetroHealth Hospital for observation.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[March 2, 2010: Carter Center and International IDEA Launch Initiative to Strengthen Andean-U.S. Relations (English and En Espa&#241;ol)]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/publications/peace/americas_publications/andean-us-dialogue-forum-2010.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Responding to a joint initiative of The Carter Center and International IDEA to strengthen cooperation relations between the Andean countries and the United States, approximately 40 citizens of these countries met in Atlanta on Feb. 23-24, 2010.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[March 2, 2010: Statement From The Carter Center on Earthquake in Chile]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/chile-earthquake.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[President and Mrs. Carter and the staff of The Carter Center express our deep sympathy for those affected by the earthquake in Chile.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[March 1, 2010: Ecuador Becomes Second Country in the Americas to Halt River Blindness Transmission - Carter Center Hails Major Step Forward in Campaign to Rid Americas of Parasitic Infection by 2012; Urges Intensified Efforts in the Four Remaining Endemic Countries (English and En Espanol)]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/ecuador-030110.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Carter Center experts congratulate the people of Ecuador for breaking transmission of the blinding parasitic disease river blindness, or onchocerciasis. Ecuador is the second nation in the Americas after Colombia (in 2008) to stop the transmission of this debilitating, yet preventable affliction on a countrywide basis, according to officials of the Ministry of Health of Ecuador and the Onchocerciasis Elimination Program in the Americas (OEPA).]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[March 1, 2010:  Make Online Reservations Now for "Africa - Elections Aren't Enough," March 10 Conversations at The Carter Center]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://carter.convio.net/site/Calendar?view=Detail&id=100481]]></link><description><![CDATA[Join us for a Conversation led by Paul Collier, award-winning author of books such as The Bottom Billion and War, Guns, and Votes. Collier is also professor of economics and director of the Center for the Study of African Economies at Oxford University. He researches the causes and consequences of civil war, the effects of aid, and the problems of democracy in low-income and natural resource-rich societies.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Feb. 28, 2010: Winter Weekend Auction Raises $1,322,300 for Carter Center Peace and Health Programs]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/winter-weekend-2010-results.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center's annual Winter Weekend auction, held Feb. 27 at Port St. Lucie, Fla., raised $1,322,300 to benefit the not-for-profit Center's initiatives to advance peace and health worldwide.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Feb. 22, 2010: Carter Center - Nepalis Want New Constitution to Promote Decentralization and Equality]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/nepal-022210.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[ccording to a Carter Center report released today, Nepalis expect their new constitution to provide peace, security, and address basic needs.  They support measures to promote equality, inclusivity, and education for all; end discrimination; uplift disadvantaged communities; and improve access to the state and justice system.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Feb. 18, 2010:  2010-2011 Rosalynn Carter Fellowships for Mental Health Journalism: Applications Being Accepted]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/mental-health-journalism-fellowships-2010.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Applications from U.S. residents are now being accepted for six one-year journalism fellowships with the Carter Center's Mental Health Program. These fellowships aim to enhance public understanding of mental health issues and reduce stigma and discrimination against people with mental illnesses through balanced and accurate reporting. The postmark deadline for applications is April 19, 2010, and the fellowship recipients will be announced July 9, 2010, on the Center's Web site, www.cartercenter.org. The 2010-2011 fellowship year begins in September 2010. ]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Feb. 17, 2010: U.S. Engagement With the U.N. Human Rights System (PDF)]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/resources/pdfs/peace/human_rights/brookings-021710-us-un-hr-system.pdf]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center and the Brookings Institution's Managing Global Insecurity Initiative convened human rights advocates from Brazil, Colombia, Egypt, Indonesia, Israel, Malaysia,Nigeria, Pakistan, Russia, and the United States to evaluate the impact of the U.N.'s human rights system on their work.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Feb. 15, 2010: Trip Report by Former U.S. President Jimmy Carter to Ghana & Sudan, Feb. 5-13, 2010]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/trip_reports/ghana-sudan-Feb-2010.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Rosalynn, John Hardman, Nancy Konigsmark, and I were fortunate to travel with Carter Center Trustee Richard Blum in his new Gulfstream. The purpose of this trip was to promote health programs in both countries, to attend a regional conference on Access to Information (ATI) in Accra, and help to prepare for April elections in Sudan and a referendum in Southern Sudan scheduled for next January.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Feb. 11, 2010: Former U.S. President Jimmy Carter Visits Last Stronghold of Guinea Worm Disease in Southern Sudan]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/sudan-021110.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[In the dusty and remote village of Molujore, Terekeka County, Southern Sudan, food shortages are common, insecurity lingers, and survival is a daily struggle. Yet, important progress is being made in the effort to wipe out Guinea worm disease, resulting in the community being singled out for a visit from former U.S. President Jimmy Carter, Central Equatoria State Governor Clement Wani Konga, and Commissioner Clement Maring Samuel today to urge intensification of efforts to wipe out the waterborne parasitic infection during the next transmission season beginning in April.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Feb. 11, 2010: Kenneth Byers Appointed Chair of Carter Center Board of Councilors]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/boc-kenneth-byers-021110.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Kenneth G. Byers, Jr., president of Byers Engineering Company, has been appointed chair of the Carter Center's Board of Councilors for 2010. The board is comprised of 221 members, who serve as a leadership advisory group that promotes understanding among opinion leaders and the broader community of The Carter Center and its activities.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Feb. 11, 2010: Rare Presidential and Sports Memorabilia To Be Auctioned to Benefit Carter Center]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/winter-weekend-2010.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Original artwork by former U.S. President Jimmy Carter, a baseball signed by five presidents, a behind-the-scenes tour of Delta Air Lines, and historic memorabilia from the Carter presidential campaign are among nearly 180 items up for public auction in Port St. Lucie, Fla. on Feb. 27, 2010, during the Carter Center's annual Winter Weekend celebration.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Feb. 4, 2010: Open Letter from Former U.S. President Jimmy Carter to the People of Nepal]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/letter-to-nepal-020410.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[I have followed closely Nepal's progress over the last several years, and I commend you for your continued dedication to sustainable peace and inclusive democracy.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Feb. 3, 2010: Former U.S. President Jimmy Carter to View Major Progress Against Guinea Worm Disease in Sudan]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/sudan-020310.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Former U.S. President Jimmy Carter and his wife, Rosalynn, will travel to the world's most Guinea worm-endemic country&#151;Sudan&#151;Feb. 9-12, 2010, to personally appeal for completing eradication of the crippling waterborne parasite as soon as possible and to urge peace and stability in the nation as it prepares for its first multi-party elections in 24 years in April, which the Carter Center's international election observation team will monitor.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Feb. 2, 2010: Jimmy Carter: A Crisis in Sudan]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/editorials_speeches/washington-post-jimmy-carter-020210.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[This op-ed by Jimmy Carter was published Feb. 2, 2010, by the Washington Post. One of the most urgent responsibilities the international community faces is in Sudan, which is facing a renewal of nationwide violence.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Feb. 1, 2010: Jimmy Carter to Lead Conference to Advance Right of Access to Information in Africa]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/p/access_to_information/africa-access-to-information.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Former U.S. President Jimmy Carter will lead the African Regional Conference on the Right of Access to Information Feb. 7-9, in Accra, Ghana, hosted by The Carter Center and its partners in Africa.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Jan. 26, 2010: Meet Yalanbu Zenabu: Former Trichiasis Patient Sees Hopeful Future]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/publications/health/trachoma_publications/profile-yalanbu-zenabu.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Three years ago, Yalanbu Zenabu of Botingli, northern Ghana, was consumed by the daily suffering of trachoma.  As a victim of trichiasis, the blinding form of trachoma, her disease had progressed to the stage where her eyelashes scratched against her eye, causing intense pain and debilitation.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Jan. 26, 2010: Meet Olawale Fapohunda: Committed to Proposed African Charter]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/publications/peace/democracy_publications/profile-olawale-fapohunda.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Olawale Fapohunda believes that the proposed African Charter on Democracy, Elections and Governance (ACDEG) will enable African citizens to more fully participate in the electoral process and advance protection of human rights by African governments.  And, in places like his home country of Nigeria, he feels the need for its ratification is vital.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Jan. 26, 2010: Carter Center Calls Upon All Palestinian Authorities and Political Parties to Allow Unhindered Participation in the Political Process]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/palestine_012610.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center hopes to observe presidential and legislative elections in Palestine, but will only consider the opportunity if the democratic principles and fundamental freedoms required for genuine and inclusive elections across the West Bank and Gaza are met.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Jan. 26, 2010: Ghana Conference to Address Africa's Right of Access to Information, Develop Action Plan]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/p/access_to_information/africa-access-to-information.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Listen to Laura Neuman, associate director for the Americas Program at The Carter Center and the access to information project manager, discuss the upcoming African Regional Conference on the Right of Access to Information, to be held in Accra, Ghana, on Feb. 7-9.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Jan. 20, 2010: Carter Center Calls for Objective and Transparent Resolution of Fraud Allegations in Cote D'Ivoire Election Preparations (En anglais et en fran&#231;ais)]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/cotedivoire_012010.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Former U.S. President Jimmy Carter, responding to recent allegations of attempted fraud in Cote d'Ivoire's election preparations, called for an objective and transparent resolution of the issue, noting that the claims "should not be used to discredit the other important achievements, to delay unduly the election, or to challenge previous political agreements that serve as the basis to conduct the elections."]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Jan. 17, 2010: Statement From The Carter Center on Earthquake in Haiti]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/haiti-earthquake-011710.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[President and Mrs. Carter and the staff of The Carter Center are saddened at the devastation and loss of life in Haiti.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Jan. 6, 2010: China Elections and Governance Online Receives Top Web Awards From China-Based Publications]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/p/china/awards-010610.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[China Elections and Governance Online, a project of the Carter Center's China Program, has received top honors from two major Chinese publications.  Named Web site of the year in China by Southern Weekend &#150; an international current affairs weekly, based in Guangzhou, Chuangdong Province &#150; China Elections and Governance Online was also recognized recently as a "top organization working for promotion of public interest in China" by Nanfeng Chuang (South Wind Window) magazine.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Dec. 29, 2009; This Is Not Humane.  We Need Dignity.]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/editorials_speeches/abdelshafi-122909.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[This editorial by Sami Abdel-Shafi, the Carter Center's Gaza representative, was published in the Dec. 29, 2009, edition of The Guardian. ]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Dec. 21, 2009: Guinea Worm Disease:  Nigeria's Last Case]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/h/guinea_worm/nigeria-last-gw.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Once the most endemic country for Guinea worm disease in the world, Nigeria declares victory in its 20-year war. In Ezza Nkwubor village in southeastern Nigeria, 58-year-old Grace Otubo sits on a wooden bench and touches her right heel, recalling where a Guinea worm painfully emerged in November 2008.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Dec. 19, 2009: Gaza Must Be Rebuilt Now]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/editorials_speeches/gaza-121909.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[This op-ed by former U.S. President Jimmy Carter was published Dec. 19, 2009, by The Guardian. It is generally recognised that the Middle East peace process is in the doldrums, almost moribund. Israeli settlement expansion within Palestine continues, and PLO leaders refuse to join in renewed peace talks without a settlement freeze, knowing that no Arab or Islamic nation will accept any comprehensive agreement while Israel retains control of East Jerusalem.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Dec. 17, 2009: Carter Center Commends Broad Participation in Sudan's Registration,  Urges Additional Steps to Ensure Genuine Elections]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/sudan-121709.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[In a statement released today, The Carter Center welcomed the conclusion of national voter registration in Sudan, which ended Dec. 7, and congratulated the people of Sudan for the broad and generally peaceful participation in the registration process.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Dec. 14, 2009: Trip Report by Former U.S. President Jimmy Carter to Cyprus, Dec. 8-11, 2009]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/trip_reports/cyprus-120809.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[On The Elders' third trip to Cyprus, I joined Archbishop Desmond Tutu and Lakhdar Brahimi. This concentration of our visits on Cyprus was because of the importance of a successful effort to bring peace and unity to the troubled island, and the growing likelihood of success.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Dec. 3, 2009: Watch Archived Webcast of "China &#150; U.S. Relations"]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/multimedia/Conversations/China-US-Relations-120309.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Normalizing relations with China was one of the most important decisions for former U.S. President Jimmy Carter during his administration 30 years ago.  Making the decision was difficult and it is equally difficult to maintain this complex and multi-faceted relationship.  Both nations are now facing new challenges.  Managing this important bilateral relationship has a huge impact on world peace, stability, and prosperity. This discussion on the history, present, and future of the relationship between these two great nations is moderated by Carter Center Vice President for Peace Programs John Stremlau.  Panelists include former U.S. President Jimmy Carter; Vice President of the Chinese People's Association for Friendship with Foreign Countries Madam Li Xiaolin;  Emory University distinguished visiting professor of China studies Mary Brown Bullock;  and Carter Center China Program Director Yawei Liu.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Everyday Citizens Creating Extraordinary Change: A Look at the Work of Carter Center Volunteers (Slideshow, 2009)]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/multimedia/GeneralTopics/CarterCenterVolunteers.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Around the world, men and women, many of whom live on less than a dollar a day, volunteer their time and hard work to make a difference in their communities. They knock on a neighbor's door to distribute medicines that prevent horrible diseases or sit watchfully at a polling station to ensure each person's vote is counted. These networks of volunteers across the globe are vital to the Carter Center's work. During this holiday season, we pay tribute to our international volunteers for their selfless acts that are building hope for millions.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Dec. 8, 2009: Meet Alba Lucia Morales: Health Educator Fills Critical Role in Final Push Toward Onchocerciasis Elimination]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/h/river_blindness/morales-oepa.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[For Alba Lucia Morales Castro, health education adviser with the Onchocerciasis Elimination Program for the Americas (OEPA)--the Carter Center-sponsored river blindness elimination organization in Latin America--the joy of working in the field is its own reward.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Dec. 8, 2009: Meet Jordan Bracho:  Center's Media Training in Venezuela Addresses Balance, Dialog ]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/p/americas/jordan-bracho-venezuela.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[For Jordan Bracho, editor-in-chief at Telesur TV in Venezuela, attending The Carter Center "Journalism Beyond Print" workshop in August 2009 led to an immediate improvement in his work and allowed him to develop relationships with colleagues that he wouldn't have otherwise been able to in Venezuela's current media environment.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Dec. 7, 2009: Carter Center Commends Bolivians on Peaceful Election Day and Urges National Electoral Court to Strengthen Confidence in the Biometric Register (English and Spanish)]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/bolivia-120709.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center limited observation mission in Bolivia found election day to be generally peaceful and that the new biometric voter list served the purposes for which it has been implemented. The Center recommends that Bolivian society and the National Electoral Court (CNE) continue to strengthen their efforts to consolidate credibility in their institutions.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Dec. 4, 2009 : Friends of the Inter-American Democratic Charter Submit Letter to OAS on Honduras]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/honduras-120409.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The following letter was distributed today from The Carter Center and The Friends of the Inter-American Democratic Charter to the Permanent Representatives of the OAS prior to their planned discussion on Honduras.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Dec. 3, 2009: Speech by Jimmy Carter to the Parliament of the World's Religions]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/editorials_speeches/parliament-world-religions-120309.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Delivered via remote video from Atlanta, Ga. First, I want to thank Executive Director Dirk Ficca for making it possible for me to join you, even though remotely. I occupy a privileged position these days, best explained by a cartoon in New Yorker magazine.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Dec. 3, 2009: Carter Center Delegation to Observe Bolivia's Dec. 6 Elections (English and Spanish)]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/bolivia-120309.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center announced today that it will deploy a small observation delegation to Bolivia's Dec. 6 elections, led by Jennifer McCoy, director of the Center's Americas Program.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[Dec. 2, 2009: Dispatch From Bolivia:  The Carter Center Blogs From The 2009 Presidential and Legislative Elections]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/blogs/p/elections/bolivia/dhakes-2009.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Join the Carter Center's Deborah Hakes, assistant director of public information, on the ground in Bolivia, as she blogs daily through Dec. 7 about the presidential and legislative elections, their importance for the Latin American country, and the Carter Center's role in the process.  She joins the Carter Center election observation delegation led by Americas Program Director Jennifer McCoy.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[1 December 2009: The Carter Center Commends Advances in Bolivia's Biometric Voter Registry but Urges More Transparency in Processing Data and Timely Resolution to the Situation of Citizens Conditionally Allowed to Vote ("Observados")]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/bolivia-120109.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[In a report released today, The Carter Center commended the publication of the biometric voter registry by the National Electoral Court (CNE) for contributing significantly to the transparency of the Dec. 6 elections. However, the Center urged the CNE to provide more information about the data processing steps used to screen the voter list and create the new registry.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[30 November 2009: Carter Center Welcomes Peaceful Voter Registration in Sudan; Urges Further Steps to Improve Registration Process]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/sudan_113009.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[In a statement released today, The Carter Center commended the largely peaceful implementation of national voter registration in Sudan, which began on Nov. 1, and welcomed the National Election Commission's decision to extend voter registration by one week to promote greater inclusion in the process.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[30 November 2009: Carter Center Notes Poor but Improved Tarai Security Environment in Nepal]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/nepal_113009.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[In a report released today, The Carter Center in Nepal describes the current security environment around the country and notes that while the situation across parts of the Tarai remains poor, it has moderately improved since early-2009.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[25 November 2009: Carter Center Statement on the Honduran Elections (English and Spanish)]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/honduras_112509.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center has decided not to observe the Honduras elections scheduled for Nov. 29 because a national unity government has not been established and the vote by the Congress is not scheduled until after the elections.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[23 November 2009: Internationally-Renowned Humanitarian Groups Support Challenge to Unconstitutional "Material Support" Law]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/aclu-112309.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The American Civil Liberties Union today filed a friend-of-the-court brief on behalf of the Carter Center, Human Rights Watch and several other human rights and humanitarian organizations in a case before the U.S. Supreme Court challenging the constitutionality of a law that makes it a crime to provide "material support or resources" to any organization that the Secretary of State has designated a "foreign terrorist organization" (FTO).]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[9 November 2009: Update: Carter Center Assists Ecuador-Colombia Agreement]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/p/americas/ecuador-colombia-update110909.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Ecuadorian Chancellor Fander Falcon&#237; met with his Colombian counterpart Jaime Berm&#250;dez in Cotacachi, Ecuador, on Nov. 3, 2009, in a meeting facilitated by Dr. Jennifer McCoy of The Carter Center and Jos&#233; Miguel Insulza of the Organization of the American States (OAS).]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[5 November 2009: Goldstone and Gaza]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/editorials_speeches/goldstone-gaza-jc-oped-110509.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[This op-ed by former U.S. President Jimmy Carter was published Nov. 5, 2009, by the International Herald Tribune and The New York Times. Judge Richard Goldstone and the United Nations fact-finding mission on the Gaza conflict have issued a report about Gaza that is strongly critical of both Israel and Hamas for their violations of human rights.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[2 November 2009: Carter Center Concerned About Sudan's Voter Registration Process and Obstacles to Observer Accreditation]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/sudan_110209.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[In a statement released today, The Carter Center noted continued progress in Sudan's electoral process, including voter registration, which began Nov. 1, but expressed concerns about the obstacles facing election observers, including delays in finalizing their accreditation procedures and delays in election preparations, as well as continued reports of harassment of political party and civil society activity.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[2 November 2009: Trip Report by Former U.S. President Jimmy Carter to Saudi Arabia, Kuwait, Qatar, Dubai, Oman, Egypt, Jordan, and Turkey, Oct. 18-30, 2009]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/trip_reports/saudi-arabia-101809.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Our goal in visiting the Arab nations was to describe work of The Carter Center and seek financial assistance for our health programs in Africa. At each stop, our hosts were also quite interested in our efforts to promote peace between Israel and its neighbors.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[24 October 2009: Statement by The Carter Center and Friends of the Inter-American Democratic Charter in Honduras]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/honduras_102409.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Upon completing two days of interviews with a range of political actors and representatives of Honduran society, the delegation from The Carter Center and the Friends of the Inter-American Democratic Charter group share their findings and initial insights in the statement below, and they reiterate their commitment to the promotion of democracy and to effective international support and vigilance.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[12 October 2009: Carter Center Assists Ecuador-Colombia Agreement]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/p/americas/ecuador-colombia-agreement.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Ecuador and Colombia recently announced that they will begin steps to establish diplomatic relations at the charge d'affairs level by the end of October.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[9 October 2009: Trip Report by Former U.S. President Jimmy Carter to Dominican Republic and Haiti, Oct. 6-8, 2009]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/trip_reports/hispaniola.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[A group representing The Carter Center flew to Puerto Plata, Dominican Republic, to help finalize and publicize an agreement between Haiti and the Dominican Republic to eliminate malaria and lymphatic filariasis from the Island of Hispaniola. Our International Task Force for Disease Eradication had identified this as a worthy project, as this is the only island in the Caribbean on which the two diseases still exist.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[8 October 2009 : Former U.S. President Jimmy Carter and Carter Center Delegation Tour Hispaniola to Support Elimination of Malaria and Lymphatic Filariasis from Caribbean]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/h/hispaniola/2009-tour.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Efforts to eliminate malaria and lymphatic filariasis from the Caribbean island of Hispaniola were underscored Oct. 7-8 during a visit by former U.S. President Jimmy Carter and a Carter Center delegation.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[5 October 2009 : Carter Center-Sponsored Web Site Redesigned to Engage China's Youth]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/p/china/china-elections-site-redesign.html ]]></link><description><![CDATA[After seven years online, the Carter Center sponsored-Web site www.chinaelections.org is one of the most visible platforms in China for the dissemination of democratic awareness and civic culture. The site, which receives a robust 65,000 visits per day, was recently redesigned to attract younger people and to expand its focus on global elections.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[2 October 2009: Carter Center Condemns Violence in Guinea]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/guinea_100209.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center deplores the violent attacks by security forces that killed more than 150 peaceful demonstrators in Conakry, Guinea, on Sept. 28.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[22 September 2009: Chasing the Worm]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/publications/health/guinea_worm_publications/chasing-the-worm.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[This article was published Sept. 22, 2009 by the British Medical Journal 2009;339:b3892. New cases of guinea worm disease in southern Sudan have recently fallen from 20 000 a year to an estimated 1500, and doctors are hoping that the disease will become the second in history to be eliminated.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[21 September 2009: Address by Former U.S. President Jimmy Carter: Mahatma Gandhi Global Nonviolence Award]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/editorials_speeches/gandhi-award-speech.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Former U.S. President Jimmy Carter and former First Lady Rosalynn Carter were named recipients of the 2009 Mahatma Gandhi Global Nonviolence Award in recognition of the couple's humanitarian efforts worldwide.  The full transcript of President Carter's speech during the presentation ceremony at James Madison University, Harrisonburg, Va., follows.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[19 September 2009: Transcript of Former President Jimmy Carter's Remarks on Racism at an Emory University Townhall Meeting on Wednesday, Sept. 16, 2009]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/editorials_speeches/emory-racism-091609.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Question and answer from President Carter's townhall meeting Sept. 16, 2009 at Emory University in Atlanta, Ga.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[18 September 2009: Carter Center Urges All Parties to Heed Goldstone Report Recommendations]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/gaza-091809.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center urges all parties to heed the recommendations of the recent United Nations report on hostilities in and around Gaza from December 2008 to January 2009.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[17 September 2009: Carter Center Continues Observation of Bolivia's Biometric Census Registration Process (English and Spanish)]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/bolivia_091709.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[At the invitation of the National Electoral Court, The Carter Center is continuing to observe the process of the biometric census registration in all of the departments of Bolivia, including rural districts, isolated areas, special districts, and some cities outside of the country. The team of long-term observers, comprised of professionals from Ecuador, Peru, Germany, Argentina, Nicaragua, Brazil, the United States, Costa Rica, and Portugal, will remain in Bolivia until the registration process has concluded and the biometric census is complete.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[15 September 2009: The Carter Center Commemorates the 2nd Annual International Day of Democracy]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/day-of-democracy-2.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[In celebration of the second annual International Day of Democracy, former U.S. President Jimmy Carter and The Carter Center call upon citizens around the globe to recommit themselves to the principles of democracy.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[13 September 2009: Statement by Former U.S. President Jimmy Carter on the Death of Dr. Norman Borlaug]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/borlaug-statement-091309.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[I am saddened by the passing of my close friend and colleague Dr. Norman Borlaug.  For more than two decades, I had the pleasure of working with Dr. Borlaug, a senior fellow at The Carter Center, on the Sasakawa-Global 2000 effort to increase agricultural production in Africa.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[6 September 2009: Concern in the Holy Land: The Elders' View of the Middle East]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/editorials_speeches/washington-post-090609.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Washington Post op-ed by former U.S. President Jimmy Carter. During the past 16 months I have visited the Middle East four times and met with leaders in Israel, Egypt, Lebanon, Saudi Arabia, Jordan, Syria, the West Bank and Gaza.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[1 September 2009: Efforts to Control Blinding Trachoma Reduce Child Mortality in Ethiopia, JAMA Study Finds]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/trachoma-ethiopia-090109.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Ethiopia's devastating child mortality rates&#151;which are among the highest in the world&#151;could be significantly decreased as a result of treatment to control the nonfatal eye disease trachoma, suggests new research published in the Sept. 2, 2009, issue of the Journal of the American Medical Association by the University of California at San Francisco and The Carter Center, in partnership with the Ethiopia Ministry of Health.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[31 August 2009: Trip Report by Former U.S. President Jimmy Carter on the Elders Visit to the Middle East: August 22-29, 2009]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/trip_reports/elders-middle-east-aug2009.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Rosalynn and I arrived in Jerusalem before the other Elders, and on Monday we met with Ahmed Tiki, an Arab-Israeli who is a member&#150;and deputy speaker&#150;of the Knesset. He reminded us that 20 percent of Israeli citizens are Arabs: they hold about 10 percent of the legislative seats, are severely restricted from acquiring additional property or traveling to Palestine, have only six percent of government jobs, and no Arab is among the 600 employees of the Central Bank.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[26 August 2009: The Carter Center Urges Progress on Nepal's Peace and Constitutional Processes, Increased Attention to the Local Level]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://cartercenter.org/news/pr/nepal-082609.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Nepal has made significant progress on the path to peace and inclusive democracy over the past three years but the future of the process now appears in question. Reminiscent of the 1990s, political leaders in Kathmandu appear focused on zero-sum power politics at the expense of the constitution drafting, peace process, and provision of basic government services. ]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[26 August 2009: Carter Center Launches Voter Registration Observation Mission to Bolivia (English and Spanish)]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://cartercenter.org/news/pr/bolivia-082609.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center launched a voter registration observation mission to Bolivia this week by deploying six long-term observers to cover all of the country's nine departamentos (districts). The Center's observers will monitor the biometric voter registration process, focusing on the administration of voter registration, citizen participation, voter registration complaints, and related issues. The Center's assessment will be made against criteria based on Bolivia's electoral laws and constitution and the country's international commitments regarding democratic elections.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[24 August 2009: Public Radio International's "The World:" Fighting Blindness in Ethiopia]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.theworld.org/2009/08/24/fighting-blindness-in-ethiopia/]]></link><description><![CDATA[Health problems that afflict the world's poor have received unprecedented attention in recent years. Governments and foundations alike are pouring billions of dollars into the fights against diseases such as HIV/AIDS, malaria and tuberculosis. But medical workers who focus on lesser known diseases say their efforts remain as difficult as ever. Reporter Odette Yousef of station WABE in Atlanta traveled to Ethiopia to follow the Carter Center's fight against trachoma, a leading cause of blindness in Africa.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[19 August 2009: Carter Center Notes Progress in Electoral Preparations, But Expresses Concern Over Electoral Delays and Peace Agreement Implementation]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://cartercenter.org/news/pr/sudan-081909.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[In a statement released today, The Carter Center noted recent positive steps in Sudan's electoral process, including the release of a revised electoral calendar that should allow voter registration to take place in November, avoiding the rainy season, as well as the formation of 25 state Election High Committees and the Southern Sudan Elections High Committee (SSEHC).]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[19 August 2009: Status of the Electoral Process in Sudan &#150; Concerns Remain Over Electoral Delays and Peace Agreement Implementation (PDF)]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://cartercenter.org/resources/pdfs/news/peace_publications/election_reports/Statement-Sudan-Election-081909.pdf]]></link><description><![CDATA[This statement summarizes the observations of the Carter Center's election observation mission in Sudan during the period from May &#150; August 2009 and follows a public statement released on May 7, 2009. ]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[19 August 2009: Carter Center Annonces Agreement With the Government of Sudan, the National Elections Commission and the Government of Southern Sudan on Election Observation]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://cartercenter.org/news/pr/sudan-agreement-081909.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center is pleased to have finalized memoranda of understanding with the Government of National Unity (GONU) of Sudan and the National Elections Commission (NEC) and the Government of Southern Sudan (GOSS) on its program of election observation in Sudan.  The Center welcomes the spirit of cooperation demonstrated by Sudanese authorities in these efforts.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[17 August 2009: Former U.S. President Jimmy Carter and Former First Lady Rosalynn Carter to Launch 2009-2010 Season of Conversations at The Carter Center]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://cartercenter.org/news/pr/conversations-2009-2010.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Former U.S. President Jimmy Carter and former First Lady Rosalynn Carter will open the upcoming season of Conversations at The Carter Center on Sept. 15, 2009. The annual speaker series features panel discussions of current world topics and Carter Center work.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[13 August 2009: Attaining a Culture of Peace in Bolivia]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://cartercenter.org/news/features/p/americas/peace-culture-bolivia.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[In Bolivia, political disputes often escalate to the brink of conflict. One of the poorest countries in the Western Hemisphere, Bolivia's ethnic and cultural diversity, as well as struggles over natural resources, fuel strong social and economic tensions.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[5 August 2009: "Preventing Blindness" -- CNN's Impact Your World Showcases Carter Center Trachoma Control Program]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://cartercenter.org/news/features/h/trachoma/cnn-impact-trachoma.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Trachoma is the world's leading cause of "preventable" blindness, yet it costs 10 million people their eyesight.  The Carter Center, with partner organizations and community health workers in six African nations, is working to carry out simple solutions to prevent this disease affecting the world's poorest and most forgotten people. ]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[31 July 2009: Carter Center Statement on Situation in Honduras (English and Spanish)]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://cartercenter.org/news/pr/honduras_073109.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[We are deeply concerned about a possible escalation in violence and bloodshed in Honduras.  The San Jose Accords provide the best avenue to resolve the current crisis, and we urge both sides to work in good faith to achieve an agreement along these lines. International verification will be important to ensure that the agreements are fully implemented and to provide reassurance to all Hondurans.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[21 July 2009: Human Rights House Provides Safe Space for Activists, Supports Citizens in Democratic Republic of the Congo]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://cartercenter.org/news/features/p/human_rights/hr-house.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The initial vision for the Carter Center's Human Rights House was to provide both a space and forum for human rights activists in the Democratic Republic of the Congo, building on the momentum of the 2006 elections.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[21 July 2009: Profile: Valerie Harden, Deputy Field Director, Carter Center Kinshasa Field Office]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://cartercenter.org/news/publications/peace/human_rights_publications/valerie-harden-profile.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[When she began work as a job counselor almost 10 years ago in Atlanta with refugees from the Democratic Republic of the Congo, Valerie Harden never imagined she would one day play a role in the restoration of their war-torn country.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[20 July 2009: Three Countries Announce Elimination of Blinding Trachoma at Meeting of Alliance for the Global Elimination of Blinding Trachoma]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://cartercenter.org/news/pr/get2020-072009.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[At a meeting of the World Health Organization's (WHO) global partnership on eye disease &#151; the Alliance for the Global Elimination of Blinding Trachoma by the Year 2020 (GET 2020) &#151; Ghana, Mexico, and Saudi Arabia reported that they have reached the goal for eliminating blinding trachoma.  Each country has also strengthened its health care system so it can deliver eye surgery for those in need.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[14 July 2009: Statement By The Carter Center on the Release of the Final Report of Liberia's Truth and Reconciliation Commission]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://cartercenter.org/news/pr/liberia-trc-rpt-071409.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Based on the Carter Center's long concern for the peace and well-being of the Liberian people and its current collaboration with the government of Liberia to conduct civic education on the rule of law, this statement aims to help explain in simple terms what will happen now that the Truth and Reconciliation Commission (TRC) has issued its final report.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[13 July 2009: Constitutional Crisis in Honduras:  An Expert Q&A by Dr. Jennifer McCoy, Director, Americas Program]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://cartercenter.org/news/current_qa/honduras_071309.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[An expert Q&A with Dr. Jennifer McCoy, director of the Carter Center's Americas Program, on the constitutional crisis in Honduras.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[12 July 2009: The Words of God Do Not Justify Cruelty to Women]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://cartercenter.org/news/editorials_speeches/observer_071209.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Discrimination and abuse wrongly backed by doctrine are damaging society, argues the former U.S. president. Editorial by former U.S. President Jimmy Carter, published in the July 12, 2009, edition of The Observer.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[10 July 2009: The Carter Center Continues Support to Nepal's Peace Process]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://cartercenter.org/news/pr/nepal_071009.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center commends the significant progress that Nepal has made on the path to peace and stability during the last three years, but notes with concern that the breakdown in consensus politics following the 2008 Constituent Assembly elections, as well as the delay in implementing previous commitments, threatens to derail the progress made thus far.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[10 July 2009:The Carter Center Awards 2009-2010 Rosalynn Carter Fellowships for Mental Health Journalism]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://cartercenter.org/news/pr/mental-health-fellows-2009-2010.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[After receiving a record number of applicants, the Carter Center's Rosalynn Carter Fellowships for Mental Health Journalism&#151;the only journalism fellowships exclusively for mental health&#151;announced today the winners of its 2009-2010 awards (see below for full list of fellows and their project topics). Since 1996, the fellowship program has educated more than 100 journalists, who set the standard in their field for accurate and sensitive portrayals of mental health issues.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[30 June 2009: The Carter Center In the News]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/cc/in_the_news.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Latest media coverage of the Carter Center's global peace and health work. ]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[30 June 2009: Statement by the Friends of the Inter-American Democratic Charter on the Honduran Coup, Sunday, June 28, 2009 (English and Spanish versions)]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/honduras-statement-on-coup-063009.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Faced with the occurrence of the coup d'&#233;tat in the Republic of Honduras, Sunday, June 28, We, the Friends of the Inter-American Democratic Charter, express our great concern for the rupture of the constitutional order in the Republic of Honduras that took place on June 28, 2009.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[29 June 2009: East Jerusalem Family Forced to Demolish Part of Own Home, Center Expert Cites Abuse of Permit System]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/p/democracy/palestinian-home-demolitions.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[From the roof of his family's home in East Jerusalem within the walls of the Old City, Raed Sa'id points to the golden Dome of The Rock, which is glowing in the late-afternoon sun.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[26 June 2009: The Carter Center Congratulates Indonesia's Constitutional Court for Timely Resolution of Election Disputes]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/indonesia-062609.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center commends Indonesia's Constitutional Court for their timely handling disputes relating to election results for the April 9, 2009 legislative elections.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[25 June 2009: Farmer Sows Seeds of Change in his Ghana Community]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/publications/health/agriculture_publications/farmer-sows-seeds-of-change.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[In the small agricultural community of Bondo, Ghana, Kojo Osonyame finds it difficult to suppress his smile as he walks through the fields of his fertile farm. Acre after acre bursts forth with healthy crops creating a colorful maze of peppers, eggplants, okra, cassava, and plantains.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[24 June 2009: The Carter Center Appoints Atlanta Leaders to Board of Councilors]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/boc-062409.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center, a not-for-profit organization advancing peace and health worldwide, recently appointed 17 new members to the Board of Councilors, bringing its total membership to 187.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[24 June 2009: Voter Encouraged by Carter Center Presence During Lebanon Elections, Hopeful About Country's Political Future]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/publications/peace/democracy_publications/profile-Lama-Naja.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Lama Naja represents hope for Lebanon's political future. A politically independent young person in a country full of strong political passions and fierce party loyalties, she instead voted on June 7 for the people she thought may keep their campaign promises.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[24 June 2009: Nigerien Soap Provides Income, Helps Prevent Blindness]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/publications/health/trachoma_publications/nigerien_soap.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[It is nearly evening in the desert village of Adorihi in southern Niger, and 36-year-old Aisha Oumarou crouches over her cooking fire carefully mixing oil into a pot on coals. Although the mixture smells faintly of peanuts, the hot dough that Oumarou extracts from the pot and rolls between her hands is not destined to be the evening's meal, but balls of soap.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[17 June 2009: Election Day in Lebanon:  Carter Center Observers Monitor Polling Sites]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/blogs/p/elections/lebanon/lebanon-wrap-up.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[A multinational Carter Center delegation observed Lebanon's June 7 parliamentary elections, monitoring polling sites throughout the country's 25 qadas (districts). Led by former U.S. President Jimmy Carter and former Yemini Prime Minister Abdulkareem Al-Eryani, the 60 member delegation included elected officials, electoral and human rights experts, regional specialists, and political and civic leaders from more than 20 countries in North America, Africa, Europe, South America, Asia, and the Middle East.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[17 June 2009: Carter Center Successfully Distributes Nine Million Doses of Antibiotics During Ethiopia MALTRA Weeks]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/h/maltra/wabe-radio-06172009.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[With a population of approximately 17 million, the Amhara Region of Ethiopia is one of the most severely affected trachoma-endemic areas in the world. There are currently more than 15 million people at risk of infection and approximately 470,000 people visually impaired as a result of trichiasis, the blinding form of the disease. In addition, the region is susceptible to seasonal malaria epidemics, putting the majority of the population at risk for the potentially fatal disease.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[17 June 2009: Trip Report by Former U.S. President Jimmy Carter to Lebanon, Syria, Israel, West Bank, and Gaza - June 2-17, 2009]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/trip_reports/middle-east-2009.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The purpose of this trip was to join other Carter Center observers during the Lebanese election and to visit leaders involved in the overall peace process in Syria, Israel, and Palestine. In Lebanon, approximately 60 Carter Center observers from 23 nations were led by David Carroll, and former Yemeni Prime Minister Abdulkarim al Eryani was my co-chairman.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[17 June 2009: Lebanon Election Day Wrap-up Video:  Carter Center Observers Monitor Polling Sites]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/blogs/p/elections/lebanon/lebanon-wrap-up.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Wap-up video captures the Carter Center's work in Lebanon on election day, showing what it was like for observers on the ground, with commentary by Carter Center Democracy Program Director David Carroll.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[16 June 2009: Speech by Former U.S. President Jimmy Carter to the United Nations Relief Works Agency's Human Rights Graduation in Gaza]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/editorials_speeches/gaza-061609.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Full text of speech delivered in Gaza during President Carter's tour of the Middle East following the June 7 Lebanon parliamentary elections.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[15 June 2009: Week-Long Series Highlights Center's Work to Prevent Trachoma During "MALTRA" Weeks in Ethiopia]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/h/maltra/wabe-series.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Tune in June 15-19, 2009, to Morning Edition on WABE 90.1 FM, Atlanta's NPR station, as Odette Yousef&#151;who traveled with The Carter Center to Ethiopia in April 2009&#151;reports a five-part series on work to prevent trachoma and malaria there.   Beginning Monday, June 15, segments will be aired at 6:39 a.m. and again at 8:39 a.m. (EST).    Click here for more series information and for archived reports.  Listen live online at www.pba.org/]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[12 June 2009: Former U.S. President Jimmy Carter Visits Syria, Israel, West Bank, and Gaza]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/blogs/p/middle-east-2009/dispatches.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Former US President Jimmy Carter is visiting Syria, Israel, the West Bank, and Gaza following the Carter Center's observation of the June 7 Lebanese elections. Throughout the visit, as part of his ongoing efforts to promote constructive dialog, he will hold meetings with representatives of all parties to the Israeli-Arab conflict. ]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[10 June 2009: Deborah Hakes Blogs From the 2009 Lebanon Parliamentary Elections]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/blogs/p/elections/lebanon/dhakes_june10.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[For the past week and a half (and for weeks before I arrived), the Carter Center office for the elections was a scene of constant intense activity at all hours of a day. Now the field staff has returned to their regular office outside the hotel, and Atlanta-based staff are flying home or to another field project.   Read the full blog >]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[9 June 2009: Deborah Hakes Blogs From the 2009 Lebanon Parliamentary Elections]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/blogs/p/elections/lebanon/dhakes_june9.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[I've been sharing my experiences with you from Lebanon for the past week and thought it was also important to share a few of the many other voices whose hard work made the election observation mission possible.  Read the full blog >]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[8 June 2009: Carter Center Commends Lebanon's Successful Elections; Notes Shortcomings and Encourages Continued Reform]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/lebanon-statement-060809.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center commends the Lebanese people and the electoral authorities for the successful conduct of the 2009 parliamentary elections, the results of which have been accepted by both sides.  While the process fell short of several of Lebanon's international commitments, most notably secrecy of the ballot, it was conducted with enhanced transparency and in accordance with Lebanon's new consensual electoral law and regulations.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[8 June 2009: Deborah Hakes Blogs From the 2009 Lebanon Parliamentary Elections]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/blogs/p/elections/lebanon/dhakes_june8.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Things are wrapping up here for this phase of the Carter Center's election observation mission to Lebanon.  Our long-term observers will remain deployed to monitor the post-election processes. Read the full blog and watch press conference video >]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[7 June 2009:  Deborah Hakes Blogs From the 2009 Lebanon Parliamentary Elections]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/blogs/p/elections/lebanon/dhakes_june7.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[It is the eve of Lebanon's parliamentary elections and things seem quiet. Our observers were deployed yesterday, and they continue regular check-in calls to let us know that they are safe.  Read the full blog >]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[6 June 2009:  Deborah Hakes Blogs From the 2009 Lebanon Parliamentary Elections]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/blogs/p/elections/lebanon/dhakes_june6.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[It is the eve of Lebanon's parliamentary elections and things seem quiet. Our observers were deployed yesterday, and they continue regular check-in calls to let us know that they are safe.  Read the full blog >]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[5 June 2009: Deborah Hakes Blogs From the 2009 Lebanon Parliamentary Elections]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/blogs/p/elections/lebanon/dhakes_june5.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Today, I headed south to Lebanon's border with Hrair Balian, director of the Conflict Resolution Program at The Carter Center, to be briefed by the United Nations Interim Forces in Lebanon (UNIFIL), and to see what the pre-election environment was like there. Read the full blog >]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[4 June 2009: Deborah Hakes Blogs From the 2009 Lebanon Parliamentary Elections]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/blogs/p/elections/lebanon/dhakes_june4.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Across Lebanon today, more than 11,000 polling station workers could cast their ballots early for the parliamentary elections. I traveled to Baabda, a town in the mountains southeast of Beirut, to watch the process.  Read the full blog >]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[3 June 2009: Deborah Hakes Blogs From  the 2009 Lebanon Parliamentary Elections]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/blogs/p/elections/lebanon/dhakes_june3.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[I've only been in Beirut, Lebanon, for 24 hours, but I can already tell that the parliamentary elections to be held this coming Sunday are going to be a fascinating process, and I am thrilled to be a part of it. The world is watching what happens here, and I will get to see it firsthand.  I'll do my best to share what I see with you.  Read the full blog >]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[1 June 2009: Jimmy Carter to Co-Lead Carter Center Delegation to Observe Lebanon's June 7 Elections]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/lebanon060109.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center announced today that former U.S. President Jimmy Carter and former Yemeni Prime Minister Abdul Karim al-Eryani will lead the Center's international election observation delegation to observe Lebanon's June 7 parliamentary elections. The Carter Center mission will also include more than 50 observers representing more than 20 different nations deployed throughout the country to observe balloting, counting, and tabulation processes.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[29 May 2009: Carter Center Commends Lebanon's Constitutional Council Appointments; Urges Further Clarification of Election Procedures]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/lebanon_052909.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[In a report released today, The Carter Center welcomed the May 26 decision by Lebanon's Council of Ministers to appoint the final five members of the Constitutional Council, the body mandated to adjudicate candidates' challenges to electoral results. At the same time, the Center urged Lebanese electoral authorities to provide further clarification of procedures for the filing and resolution of election day complaints by voters and party agents and for the district-level tabulation of official election results.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[29 May 2009: Ghanaian Reggae Artist Sings Out Against Guinea Worm Disease, Educates Concert-Goers About Prevention]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/h/guinea_worm/musician.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[It is dusk in northern Ghana and communities reverberate with the local mosque's call to prayer. The setting sun has fallen beyond the concrete buildings that flank the market square, casting everyone in deep purple shadow. Thousands of people are making their way to this rural outpost, the current epicenter of the country's decades-long battle to eradicate Guinea worm disease.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[28 May 2009: Carter Center Deploys Election Observation Delegation to Lebanon's June 7, 2009, Parliamentary Elections]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/p/elections/lebanon/observers.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[A multinational Carter Center delegation will observe Lebanon's June 7 parliamentary elections, monitoring polling sites throughout the country's 25 qadas (districts). Led by former U.S. President Jimmy Carter and former Yemini Prime Minister Abdulkareem Al-Eryani, the 50-some member delegation includes elected officials, electoral and human rights experts, regional specialists, and political and civic leaders from more than 20 countries in North America, Africa, Europe, South America, Asia, and the Middle East.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[21 May 2009: Carter Center Offers Steps for Indonesia to Strengthen its Electoral Dispute Mechanisms ]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/indonesia_052209.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center congratulates the government of Indonesia, the National Election Commission (KPU), the Election Supervisory Body (Bawaslu), and civil society groups for the ongoing commitment they have shown to establishing electoral complaints and dispute resolution mechanisms within the electoral system of Indonesia. ]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[21 May 2009: New York Times Spotlights Gender Violence and Rule of Law in Liberia]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/p/kristof_liberia_09.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[New York Times journalist Nicholas Kristof recently traveled to Liberia to explore progress against sexual and gender violence there and the impact of the Carter Center's rule of law project. ]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[21 May 2009: Plan of Action to Advance the Right of Access to Public Information in the Americas Released Today]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/ati_052109.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Participants in a conference on the right of access to information released today their findings and plan of action to advance the right in the Americas. The Americas Regional Plan of Action provides a blueprint for the regional and international community, states, and non-state actors to establish, develop, and nurture the right of access to information in the Americas and calls on them to commit to the plan in furtherance of our common objective.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[18 May 2009: Christian Leaders Appeal For Peace With Justice in Holy Land]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/christian-leaders-appeal-for-peace.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[National Christian leaders meeting at The Carter Center on May 14-15 sent the following letter to President Barack Obama following two days of discussions on the Israeli/Palestinian conflict.  Citing a growing sense of despair in the Holy Land, the letter conveys to the President support for his efforts to push for a two-state solution and calls for an immediate opening of the Gaza borders.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[18 May 2009: Carter Center Observers in Lebanon Prepare for Upcoming Election]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/p/elections/lebanon/lebanonLTOs_051809.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Center's long-term observers are currently monitoring the pre-elections environment in Lebanon ahead of a larger delegation that will arrive closer to election day. Read the experiences of two observers.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[12 May 2009: Former U.S. President Jimmy Carter Addresses Energy Security Before U.S. Senate Foreign Relations Committee Hearing]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/editorials_speeches/BostonGlobe-energy-security-hearings.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Full text of former U.S. President Jimmy Carter's testimony on the impact of energy issues on national security before a Senate Foreign Relations Committee hearing May 12, 2009.: ]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[11 May 2009: Next Steps in the Right of Access to Information in the Americas]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/current_qa/ati_in_americas_051109.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[A Q&A with Laura Neuman, associate director of the Carter Center's Americas Program and the access to information project manager.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[8 May 2009: Carter Center Notes Significant Achievement in C&#244;te d'Ivoire's Voter Identification and Registration]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/cotedivoire_050809.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center calls on Ivorian political leaders to sustain the hard-earned momentum of the ongoing identification and voter registration process and bring about the credible democratic elections envisioned by the Ouagadougou Political Accord (OPA). ]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[7 May 2009: Carter Center Welcomes Sudan's Electoral Calendar But Urges Additional Steps to Ensure Genuine and Viable Elections]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/sudan_050609.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[In a report issued today, The Carter Center welcomes the important steps taken in Sudan toward holding national elections but identifies additional key steps that the Government of National Unity (GONU) and the National Elections Commission (NEC) should take to ensure a genuine and viable electoral process.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[6 May 2009: Trip Report by Former U.S. President Jimmy Carter to Ecuador, Peru, Bolivia, Brazil:  April 27 &#150; May 5, 2009]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/trip_reports/latin_america_2009.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Along with Rosalynn, John Hardman, Jennifer McCoy, Francisco Diez, and Melissa Montgomery, I visited leaders in these four nations to pursue the following objectives of The Carter Center...]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[1 May 2009: Carter Center Commends Indonesia's Progress in Campaign Finance Regulations, Encourages Stronger Reporting and Disclosure Requirements]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/indonesia_050109.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center commends the parties, candidates, and National Elections Commission of Indonesia for the important progress made in campaign finance laws and practices since the 2004 elections.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[29 April 2009: African Health Leaders Honor President Carter and The Carter Center for 'Pioneering' Efforts Against Neglected Diseases]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/african_leaders_honor_carter_center09.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Health officials from 11 African countries have honored former U.S. President Jimmy Carter and The Carter Center for their "pioneering contributions to eradicating neglected tropical diseases in Africa." The leadership award was presented to Carter Center CEO Dr. John Hardman and Dr. Donald Hopkins, Vice President of Health Programs on April 22 in a Washington, D.C. event sponsored by The Whitaker Group, ONE, and Global Health Progress.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[29 April 2009: Remarks by Former U.S. President Carter at FLACSO University in Ecuador]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/editorials_speeches/FLACSO_042909.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[It is a privilege for me at this moment in our history to be here in Ecuador.  Thirty years ago this nation began a new wave of democracy in the region while I was President of the United States, and my wife Rosalynn attended the inauguration of your new president.  Now, Ecuador is beginning a new cycle with a new constitution, and my own president has proposed a new era in relations between the United States and Latin America and the Caribbean. ]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[27 April 2009: Carter Center Calls for an End to Palestinian Political Violence]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/palestine_042709.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center condemns the killing and maiming of suspected collaborators, political opponents, and common criminals committed by Hamas-affiliated security forces in the Gaza Strip. ]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[27 April 2009: What Happened to the Ban on Assault Weapons?]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/editorials_speeches/nytimes_042709.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[This op-ed was published in the April 27, 2009 issue of the New York Times. The evolution in public policy concerning the manufacture, sale and possession of semiautomatic assault weapons like AK-47s, AR-15s and Uzis has been very disturbing.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[24 April 2009: Blog from Latin America: Americas Program Director Jennifer McCoy Writes From Ecuador, Peru, Bolivia, and Brazil]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.com/news/features/p/americas/mccoy_blog.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Dr. Jennifer McCoy, director of the Carter Center's Americas Program, is traveling with former U.S. President Jimmy Carter as a member of the Carter Center delegation to Ecuador, Peru, Bolivia, and Brazil from April 27 to May 4, 2009.  Read her blog entries.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[24 April 2009: Carter Center Conference to Address Advancements and Challenges to the Right of Access to Information in the Americas]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/ati_042409.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[More than 100 high-ranking officials, civil society leaders, and journalists from 20 countries will participate in a Carter Center-hosted Americas Regional Conference on the Right of Access to Information from April 28-20 in Lima, Peru. Former U.S. President Jimmy Carter will attend as part of his four-country trip to visit Carter Center projects in Ecuador, Bolivia, and Brazil, in addition to the Lima conference, from April 27-May 4.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[22 April 2009: Carter Center Long-Term Observers Reflect on Their Experiences in Aceh, Indonesia]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/p/elections/indonesia_042209.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Long-term election observers Whitney Haring-Smith and Eunsook Jung have been deployed in Aceh since March 2009 as part of the Carter Center's mission to observe Indonesia's April 9, 2009 parliamentary elections. Aceh, an Indonesian territory on the northern tip of the island of Sumatra, has a history of political independence and strong resistance to outside control.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[21 April 2009: Carter Center Launches Election Observation Mission to Lebanon]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/lebanon_042109.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center launched an international election observation mission to Lebanon last week by deploying six long-term observers to cover all of the country's qadas (districts). The observers represent a diverse team from six countries: Portugal, Belgium, Iraq, the United Kingdom, Albania, and the United States.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[17 April 2009: Read about The Carter Center's work in the 2007-2008 Annual Report (PDF) >]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://cartercenter.org/resources/pdfs/news/annual_reports/annual-report-08.pdf]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Center has observed 72 elections in 28 countries; helped farmers double or triple grain production in 15 African countries; worked to prevent and resolve civil and international conflicts worldwide; intervened to prevent unnecessary diseases in Latin America and Africa; and strived to diminish the stigma against mental illnesses.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[17 April 2009: Read the latest issue of The Carter Center News (Spring 2009, PDF)]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://cartercenter.org/resources/pdfs/news/carter_center_news/CCNews_Spr09.pdf]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center News is the official newsletter of the peace and health organization founded by Nobel Peace Prize laureate and former U.S. President Jimmy Carter and former First Lady Rosalynn Carter.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[13 April 2009: President Carter to Lead Delegation to Latin America]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/AP_041309.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Brazil from April 27-May 4 to assess Carter Center projects, participate in a regional conference on the right of access to information, and meet with officials to discuss regional themes of importance following the Summit of the Americas.  ]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[13 April 2009: Carter Center Observers Note Largely Peaceful By-Election Day, Progress in Electoral Conduct, Some Areas for Improvement]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/nepal_041309.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center congratulates the people of Nepal, the election commission, and the political parties for a generally peaceful and orderly by-election process. ]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[12 April 2009: Carter Center Congratulates Indonesia on Generally Peaceful Elections]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/indonesia-041109.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center congratulates the people, political parties, and National Election Commission (KPU) of Indonesia on the generally peaceful April 9, 2009, legislative elections, the third since the country's democratic transition from the New Order of former President Soeharto. ]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[3 April 2009: Statement on El Salvador by The Friends of the Inter-American Democratic Charter]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/fdc_040309.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Friends of the Inter-American Democratic Charter have followed the recent Presidential elections in El Salvador with particular interest.  We congratulate president-elect Mauricio Funes and his FMLN party, as well as Rodrigo Avila for his rapid and unhesitating acceptance of the verdict of the Salvadoran people as announced by the Supreme Electoral Tribunal.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[3 April 2009: The Mining Review in the Democratic Republic of the Congo: Missed Opportunities, Failed Expectations, Hopes for the Future]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/drc_040309.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Few benefits resulted for the people of the Democratic Republic of the Congo (DRC) from the government's two-year review of contracts with companies mining billions of dollars of gold, copper, cobalt, diamonds, and other minerals.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[30 March 2009: A Milestone Toward Ending River Blindness in the Western Hemisphere by 2012: Escuintla, Guatemala Largest Endemic Area Yet to Stop Transmission (English and Spanish versions)]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/riverblindness_2012_milestone.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[An international team of researchers led by Rodrigo Gonzalez of the Universidad del Valle de Guatemala reports that the transmission of onchocerciasis or river blindness has been broken in Escuintla, Guatemala, one of the largest endemic areas in the Western Hemisphere to date to stop the transmission of the parasitic disease.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[25 March  2009: Carter Center Launches Limited Election Observation Mission to Indonesia]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/indonesia_032509.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center deployed three teams of long-term observers to locations in Indonesia this week to formally launch its limited election observation mission of the country's April 9 legislative elections.  These will be the third elections in Indonesia that the Center has observed. ]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[16 March 2009: Carter Center Calls for End to Home Demolitions and Settlement Construction in the West Bank]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/westbank_031609.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center expresses strong concern about recent home demolition orders issued by the Jerusalem Municipality.  If implemented, a total of 95 structures, including 87 homes in the historic Al-Bustan neighborhood south of the Old City, would be demolished and some 1,840 Palestinian residents of East Jerusalem would be displaced. ]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[24 February 2009: Jimmy and Rosalynn Carter Voice Support for New Mexico Legislative Action To Outlaw Death Penalty]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/nm_death_penalty.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Former U.S. President Jimmy Carter and his wife, Rosalynn, hailed the New Mexico legislature's actions to outlaw the death penalty in the state and bolster support for the families of crime victims in a letter to Governor Bill Richardson yesterday.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[20 February 2009: Carter Center Conducts Human Rights Training for Congolese Police Officers]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/p/drc_021709.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Until recently, police officers in Kimbasneke, Democratic Republic of the Congo (DRC), investigated case files at a music bar or other public space because they didn't have office space. When it rained, they carried the papers under their shirts to preserve the files.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[18 February 2009: 2009-2010 Rosalynn Carter Fellowships for Mental Health Journalism: Applications Being Accepted]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/mhfellows2009.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Applications are now being accepted for six one-year journalism fellowships with the Carter Center's Mental Health Program. The 2009-2010 fellowships begin in September 2009, and aim to enhance public understanding of mental health issues and combat stigma and discrimination against people with mental illnesses. Applicants must be U.S. residents.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[17 February 2009: Claire Lewis Arnold Appointed Chair of Carter Center Board of Councilors]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/boc_arnold.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Claire Lewis Arnold, CEO of Leapfrog Services Inc., has been appointed chair of the Carter Center's Board of Councilors for 2009.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[8 February 2009: 2009 Winter Weekend Live and Silent Auctions Raise $817,590 for the Carter Center's Global Peace, Health Work]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/winter_weekend_total09.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center's annual Winter Weekend auction, held Jan. 7 at Port St. Lucie, Fla., raised $817,590 to help support the work of the not-for-profit Center, advancing peace and health worldwide. ]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[1 February 2009: China Elections and Governance Review]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/publications/peace/china_elections_governance_review.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Issue 1:  Understanding Chinese Village Elections.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[29 January 2009: Open Letter by Members of Global Openness Community Welcoming President Obama's Initiative on Transparency (PDF)]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/resources/pdfs/peace/americas/FOIA%20to%20Obama%2028%2001%2009.pdf]]></link><description><![CDATA[The undersigned organizations, which work around the world to promote the right of access to information, welcome the steps taken by President Barack Obama on his first day in office to reverse recent trends and to promote high standards of openness in government. ]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[28 January 2009: Out of Hope Springs Tulips: Jerome Lawrence]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/features/lawrence_ww_profile.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[There are a lot of images that convey the spirit of the Carter Center's work around the world, but few are as unusual and exuberant as a painting of bright red tulips by local Atlanta artist Jerome Lawrence. The vibrant, cheerful painting titled "Tulips are People II," was featured on the Carter Center's 2008 holiday card.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[27 January 2009: Carter Center Congratulates Bolivia on Peaceful Referendum; Urges Progress to Continue]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/bolivia_012709.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center congratulates the Bolivian people for the peaceful exercise of its civic obligations during the constitutional referendum held on Jan. 25. The Center's political mission visited more than 100 polling stations and did not witness any act of violence or intimidation that would affect the voting of the citizens.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[23 January 2009: Carter Center Welcomes the Temporary Ceasefire in Gaza, Calls for "a Credible Peace with Israel"]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/gaza_012309.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center welcomes the temporary cessation of the war in and around the Gaza Strip, but notes that the situation remains extremely precarious.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[22 January 2009: China Trip Report by Former U.S. President Jimmy Carter: Jan. 10-16, 2009]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/trip_reports/china_jan2009.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Rosalynn and I flew from Atlanta to Shanghai and then to Beijing to commemorate the 30th anniversary of normalizing diplomatic relations with Deng Xiaoping and to expand our Center's working relations with government ministries. Accompanied on the trip by Melissa Montgomery, we were met by John Hardman and Yawei Liu, and the next day joined Henry Kissinger, Zbig Brzezinski, Brent Scowcroft, six former U.S. ambassadors, and other Americans who have played important roles in China.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[22 January 2009: Carter Center and Ministry of Internal Affairs Lead Workshops to Strengthen Rule of Law and Expand Role of Women in Liberia's Local Governance ]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/liberia_012209.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center, in partnership with Liberia's Ministry of Internal Affairs, the National Traditional Council, and the Ministry of Gender, will conduct workshops for Liberia's local leaders on how to strengthen the rule of law and expand the role of women in local governance in each of the country's fifteen counties between Jan. 27 and the end of April 2009.  ]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[21 January 2009: Carter Center Sends Political Mission to Observe Bolivia's Constitutional Referendum]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/bolivia_012009.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center will deploy a small political mission to observe Bolivia's constitutional referendum on Jan. 25.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[15 January 2009: Carter Center Urges an End to Political Violence in Nicaragua]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/nica_011509.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center expresses deep concern for the resurgence in politically driven violence in Nicaragua, which began after contentious Nov. 9 elections and recently regained intensity.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[14 January 2009: Winter Weekend Auction Features Sports, Space, and Presidential Memorabilia]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/winter_weekend_2009.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[Historic memorabilia from the White House, presidential elections, the space race, and American sports are among the more than 100 items up for public auction in Port St. Lucie, Fla. on Feb. 7, 2009 during the Carter Center's annual Winter Weekend celebration.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[12 January 2009: Commentary: A Victory for Democracy in Africa]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/editorials_speeches/stremlau_cnn_victory_democracy_africa.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[This op-ed by John Stremlau was published on CNN.com on Jan. 12, 2009. Supporters of democracy around the world can celebrate the January 7 inauguration of Ghana's new president, professor John Evans Atta Mills, who defeated the leader of the incumbent party in a December 28 runoff election by a mere 41,566 votes out of 9,001,478.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[8 January 2009: An Unnecessary War - Washington Post Op-Ed by Former U.S. President Jimmy Carter]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/editorials_speeches/gaza_010809.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[This op-ed was published in the Jan. 8, 2009 edition of The Washington Post.  I know from personal involvement that the devastating invasion of Gaza by Israel could easily have been avoided.]]></description></item><item><title><![CDATA[3 January 2009: Carter Center Congratulates Ghana President-Elect John Evans Atta Mills]]></title><link><![CDATA[http://www.cartercenter.org/news/pr/ghana_mills_010309.html]]></link><description><![CDATA[The Carter Center congratulates Ghana President-elect John Evans Atta Mills of the National Democratic Congress following the Electoral Commission of Ghana's Jan. 3 announcement of final election results.]]></description></item></channel></rss>