<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Faculty Experts News@Emory</title><description>All the latest news from Emory University.</description><link>http://shared.web.emory.edu.xml</link><docs>http://shared.web.emory.edu.xml</docs><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2011 21:06:35 -0400</pubDate><generator>Cascade Server</generator><item><title>Future of Libya: Emory Experts Available</title><description>Emory University has faculty experts available to discuss the situation in Libya, the death of Moammar Gadhafi, and what the future of the country and transitional government may be.y</description><link>
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/10/future-of-libya-emory-experts-available.html
				</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2011 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/10/future-of-libya-emory-experts-available.html
				</guid></item><item><title>Is the U.S. Headed Toward a Second Recession? Emory Expert Weighs In</title><description>With employment growing at a very slow pace and government in-fighting getting in the way of needed economic policy responses, Emory University visiting economics scholar Sheila Tschinkel says a second recession is still possible, even if it is not the most likely outcome.</description><link>
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/10/is-the-us-headed-toward-a-second-recession-emory-expert-weighs-in.html
				</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2011 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/10/is-the-us-headed-toward-a-second-recession-emory-expert-weighs-in.html
				</guid></item><item><title>Cain, Perry and Romney: What's Next for the Republicans? </title><description>Emory University political scientist Merle Black analyzes the Republican field, discussing whether Herman Cain is a legitimate Republican presidential contender, how he would fare against President Obama in the general election and if Rick Perry still has a chance to be the nominee. </description><link>
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/10/cain-perry-and-romney-whats-next-for-the-republicans.html
				</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2011 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/10/cain-perry-and-romney-whats-next-for-the-republicans.html
				</guid></item><item><title>Cain, Voters and Obama: What to Expect </title><description>Emory University political science professor Andra Gillespie discusses Republican presidential candidate Herman Cain and his  claims that African Americans are "brainwashed," how he would do against President Obama if he was the Republican candidate, and why it will be difficult to get African Americans back to the polls. Gillespie is a specialist in  political mobilization and race, and is the author of the forthcoming book "The New Black Politician: Cory Booker, Newark and the Post-Racial America."</description><link>
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/10/herman-cain-and-obama-and-african-american-voters.html
				</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2011 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/10/herman-cain-and-obama-and-african-american-voters.html
				</guid></item><item><title>Government Shutdown: Emory Experts Say Everybody Loses</title><description>With a potential government shutdown looming at the end of the week, Emory University experts in national politics are available to discuss whether another short-term budget will pass, who benefits or loses, how a shutdown will further damage the approval ratings of Congress and President Obama, and what it may mean for next year's elections.</description><link>
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/09/political-experts-on-government-shutdown.html
				</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2011 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/09/political-experts-on-government-shutdown.html
				</guid></item><item><title>Jewish Law Supports Reproductive Technologies, Says Emory Professor</title><description>Jewish law supports current and emerging forms of biotechnology used in assisted reproduction - including artificial insemination, surrogacy, embryo screening and even more debatable techniques - as long as the overriding intent is to "produce a healthy or healthier child," says Rabbi Michael J. Broyde, professor of law at Emory University.</description><link>
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/09/jewish-law-supports-reproductive-technologies-says-emory-professor.html
				</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2011 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/09/jewish-law-supports-reproductive-technologies-says-emory-professor.html
				</guid></item><item><title>Previewing 2012 Elections: Emory Experts Available</title><description>As the Republican field continues to solidify and polls show President Obama's approval rate dropping, Emory University experts in national politics, the "Tea Party" and partisanship, election forecasting, congressional elections and political mobilization and race are available to preview the 2012 elections.</description><link>
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/09/previewing-2012-elections-emory-experts-available.html
				</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2011 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/09/previewing-2012-elections-emory-experts-available.html
				</guid></item><item><title>Study Shows Prevention Programs Could Offer Up to $15 Billion in Medicare Savings</title><description>An Emory University study says the U.S. government could save up to $15 billion over the lifetimes of a group of baby boomers by investing in weight loss programs to help prevent diabetes or heart disease.</description><link>
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/09/study-shows-prevention-programs-could-offer-up-to-15-billion-in-medicare-savings.html
				</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2011 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/09/study-shows-prevention-programs-could-offer-up-to-15-billion-in-medicare-savings.html
				</guid></item><item><title>Eurozone faces extreme economic challenges, Emory political scientist explains why</title><description>The economic crisis in Europe's Eurozone is worsening, and Emory University political science professor and Europe expert Thomas D. Lancaster says the brunt of the financial burden falls on one country, Germany.</description><link>
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/09/eurozone-economic-challenges-emory-thomas-lancaster-explains.html
				</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/09/eurozone-economic-challenges-emory-thomas-lancaster-explains.html
				</guid></item><item><title>The Race for the White House: Emory Political Scientist Analyzes the Field</title><description>Emory University political scientist Merle Black breaks down the Republican field.</description><link>
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/09/the-race-for-the-white-house-emory-political-scientist-analyzes-the-field.html
				</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/09/the-race-for-the-white-house-emory-political-scientist-analyzes-the-field.html
				</guid></item><item><title>International Law Expert Delivers Inaugural Bederman Lecture Sept. 26</title><description>Professor David J. Bederman will deliver the inaugural David J. Bederman Lecture, "Public Law and Custom," at 4 p.m. Monday, Sept. 26, at Emory University School of Law, 1301 Clifton Rd.</description><link>
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/09/international-law-expert-delivers-inaugural-bederman-lecture-sept-26.html
				</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/09/international-law-expert-delivers-inaugural-bederman-lecture-sept-26.html
				</guid></item><item><title>9/11 Expert: The Lasting Economic Effects of 9/11</title><description>Emory finance professor Jeff Rosensweig is director of the Global Perspectives Program at Goizueta Business School and is a frequest keynote speaker about international business. Prior to joining Emory, he was the senior international economist at the Federal Reserve Bank of Atlanta.  </description><link>
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/09/911-expert-the-lasting-economic-effects-of-911.html
				</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2011 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/09/911-expert-the-lasting-economic-effects-of-911.html
				</guid></item><item><title>Emory Expert: Are We Witnessing a True Revolution in Libya? </title><description>Emory Middle Eastern history and Islamic studies professor Kenneth Stein is an expert in the Middle East, American foreign policy in the region and the modern Arab world.</description><link>
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/09/emory-expert-witnessing-a-true-revolution-in-libya.html
				</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2011 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/09/emory-expert-witnessing-a-true-revolution-in-libya.html
				</guid></item><item><title>Emory Expert Offers Tips for Coping with Life-Threatening Illnesses in New Book</title><description>Receiving a life-threatening diagnosis is often considered one of the most difficult things a person can go through, causing feelings of fear, worry and loss.</description><link>
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/08/emory-expert-offers-tips-for-coping-with-life-threatening-illnesses-in-new-book.html
				</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 01:10:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/08/emory-expert-offers-tips-for-coping-with-life-threatening-illnesses-in-new-book.html
				</guid></item><item><title>Emory Experts Discuss the Future of Libya</title><description>As drastic change continues in Libya, Emory University experts are available to discuss the future of the country, the difficulties Libya faces transitioning to a democracy and the role the international community should play in the formation of the new government.</description><link>
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/09/emory-experts-discuss-future-of-libya.html
				</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:01:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/09/emory-experts-discuss-future-of-libya.html
				</guid></item></channel></rss>