<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>News@Woodruff Health Sciences Center</title><description>All the latest news from Woodruff Health Sciences Center.</description><link>http://shared.web.emory.edu.rss</link><docs>http://shared.web.emory.edu.rss</docs><pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2011 02:35:31 -0400</pubDate><generator>Cascade Server</generator><item><title>"A Family Affair" to Spotlight Music and the Brain</title><description>On Thursday, October 27, Emory University's Alzheimer"s Disease Research Center (ADRC) and the Atlanta Symphony Orchestra will come together for "A Family Affair." The event, chaired by Madeline and Howell Adams, will feature dinner and a concert. </description><link>http://shared.web.emory.edu/whsc/news/releases/2011/10/a-family-affair-to-spotlight-music-and-the-brain.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2011 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://shared.web.emory.edu/whsc/news/releases/2011/10/a-family-affair-to-spotlight-music-and-the-brain.html</guid></item><item><title>FDA Approves Continuation of ALS Stem Cell Trial</title><description>Emory University researchers have received approval from the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) to advance to the next phase of a landmark trial to treat patients with Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis (ALS) using human neural stem cells. </description><link>http://shared.web.emory.edu/whsc/news/releases/2011/10/fda-approves-continuation-of-als-stem-cell-trial.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2011 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://shared.web.emory.edu/whsc/news/releases/2011/10/fda-approves-continuation-of-als-stem-cell-trial.html</guid></item><item><title>Emory Ethicist Nominated for World Technology Award</title><description>Paul Root Wolpe, director of Emory University's Center for Ethics, has been named a finalist for a prestigious World Technology Award in Ethics, to be presented by the World Technology Network at the United Nations next week. </description><link>http://shared.web.emory.edu/whsc/news/releases/2011/10/emory-ethicist-nominated-for-world-technology-award.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2011 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://shared.web.emory.edu/whsc/news/releases/2011/10/emory-ethicist-nominated-for-world-technology-award.html</guid></item><item><title>Emory Hosts France-Atlanta 2011 Symposia on Kidney Disease Treatment</title><description>French and American scientists, academics and physicians will gather at Emory University in early November for two one-day conferences focusing on innovation in the treatment of chronic kidney disease across the globe. Both events are free and open to the public.</description><link>http://shared.web.emory.edu/whsc/news/releases/2011/10/emory-hosts-france-atlanta-2011-symposia-on-kidney-disease-treatment.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2011 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://shared.web.emory.edu/whsc/news/releases/2011/10/emory-hosts-france-atlanta-2011-symposia-on-kidney-disease-treatment.html</guid></item><item><title>School-Based Flu Vaccine Clinics Boost Participation Among Adolescents</title><description>A new study shows flu vaccination campaigns are most effective at recruiting adolescents when they include active cooperation with schools.</description><link>http://shared.web.emory.edu/whsc/news/releases/2011/10/school-based-flu-vaccine-clinics-boost-participation-among-adolescents.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2011 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://shared.web.emory.edu/whsc/news/releases/2011/10/school-based-flu-vaccine-clinics-boost-participation-among-adolescents.html</guid></item><item><title>Technology Targets Genetic Disorders Linked to X Chromosome </title><description>Geneticists at Emory University School of Medicine have demonstrated a method that enables the routine amplification of all the genes on the X chromosome. The technology allows the rapid and highly accurate sequencing and identification of novel genetic variants affecting X chromosome genes.</description><link>http://shared.web.emory.edu/whsc/news/releases/2011/10/technology-targets-genetic-disorders-linked-to-x-chromosome-.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2011 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://shared.web.emory.edu/whsc/news/releases/2011/10/technology-targets-genetic-disorders-linked-to-x-chromosome-.html</guid></item><item><title>Emory Alzheimer's Disease Research Center Presents "Aging Well for People of Color"</title><description>The Emory University Alzheimer's Disease Research Center, Emory Center for Health in Aging and the Registry for Remembrance will host a free community forum, "Aging Well for People of Color."</description><link>http://shared.web.emory.edu/whsc/news/releases/2011/10/emory-alzheimers-disease-research-center-presents-aging-well-for-people-of-color.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2011 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://shared.web.emory.edu/whsc/news/releases/2011/10/emory-alzheimers-disease-research-center-presents-aging-well-for-people-of-color.html</guid></item><item><title>Muscling Toward a Longer Life: Genetic Aging Pathway Identified in Flies</title><description>Emory researchers have identified a set of genes that act in muscles to modulate aging and resistance to stress in fruit flies.</description><link>http://shared.web.emory.edu/whsc/news/releases/2011/10/muscling-toward-a-longer-life-genetic-aging-pathway-identified-in-flies.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2011 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://shared.web.emory.edu/whsc/news/releases/2011/10/muscling-toward-a-longer-life-genetic-aging-pathway-identified-in-flies.html</guid></item><item><title>Prolonged Use of Estrogen Leads to Reports of Urinary Incontinence, New Study Shows </title><description>Researchers have found that postmenopausal women who reported taking postmenopausal hormone therapy with estrogen for five years or more were more likely to develop urinary incontinence (UI) than were women who took estrogen for less than five years or not at all. </description><link>http://shared.web.emory.edu/whsc/news/releases/2011/10/prolonged-use-of-estrogen-leads-to-reports-of-urinary-incontinence,-new-study-shows-.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2011 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://shared.web.emory.edu/whsc/news/releases/2011/10/prolonged-use-of-estrogen-leads-to-reports-of-urinary-incontinence,-new-study-shows-.html</guid></item><item><title>Two Emory Nursing Faculty Named 2011 American Academy of Nursing Fellows</title><description>Marcia Holstad, DSN, RN, FNP and William Puentes, PhD, RN, professors at Emory University¿s Nell Hodgson Woodruff School of Nursing, were inducted into the American Academy of Nursing (AAN) Fellowship during a formal ceremony at the AAN's 38th Annual Conference and Meeting in Washington D.C</description><link>http://shared.web.emory.edu/whsc/news/releases/2011/10/two-emory-nursing-faculty-named-2011-american-academy-of-nursing-fellows.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2011 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://shared.web.emory.edu/whsc/news/releases/2011/10/two-emory-nursing-faculty-named-2011-american-academy-of-nursing-fellows.html</guid></item><item><title>Emory Vaccine Center Partners With Global Initiative to Boost Vaccine Research and Development </title><description>A team of 42 universities and research institutions in 13 countries will work to accelerate human vaccine development through a new collaborative research program named Advanced Immunization Technologies. </description><link>http://shared.web.emory.edu/whsc/news/releases/2011/10/emory-vaccine-center-partners-with-global-initiative-to-boost-vaccine-research-and-development-.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2011 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://shared.web.emory.edu/whsc/news/releases/2011/10/emory-vaccine-center-partners-with-global-initiative-to-boost-vaccine-research-and-development-.html</guid></item><item><title>FDA Grant Launches Atlanta Pediatric Device Consortium </title><description>The U.S. Food and Drug Administration has awarded the Georgia Institute of Technology, Children's Healthcare of Atlanta, Emory University and Saint Joseph's Translational Research Institute (SJTRI) a two-year, $1.8 million grant to foster the development of medical devices focused on the special needs of children. </description><link>http://shared.web.emory.edu/whsc/news/releases/2011/10/fda-grant-launches-atlanta-pediatric-device-consortium-.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2011 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://shared.web.emory.edu/whsc/news/releases/2011/10/fda-grant-launches-atlanta-pediatric-device-consortium-.html</guid></item><item><title>Georgia Named an Official Future of Nursing Action Coalition To Ensure High-Quality, Patient-Centered Health Care for All</title><description>Georgia has joined 36 states in being named Action Coalitions by the Future of Nursing: Campaign for Action, an initiative of the Robert Wood Johnson Foundation, AARP and the Center to Champion Nursing in America. The initiative aims to ensure that all Americans have access to high-quality health care, with nurses contributing to the full extent of their capabilities.  Regional or state-wide action coalitions work with the campaign to implement recommendations of the landmark Institute of Medicine (IOM) report, The Future of Nursing: Leading Change, Advancing Health.</description><link>http://shared.web.emory.edu/whsc/news/releases/2011/10/georgia-named-an-official-future-of-nursing-action-coalition-to-ensure-high-quality,-patient-centered-health-care-for-all.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2011 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://shared.web.emory.edu/whsc/news/releases/2011/10/georgia-named-an-official-future-of-nursing-action-coalition-to-ensure-high-quality,-patient-centered-health-care-for-all.html</guid></item><item><title>Emory Hosts Global Summit on Cardio-Metabolic Syndrome </title><description>Medical experts from around the world will gather at Emory University Oct. 13-14 to discuss the prevention and treatment of the rising global epidemic of cardio-metabolic syndrome. </description><link>http://shared.web.emory.edu/whsc/news/releases/2011/10/emory-hosts-global-summit-on-cardio-metabolic-syndrome-.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2011 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://shared.web.emory.edu/whsc/news/releases/2011/10/emory-hosts-global-summit-on-cardio-metabolic-syndrome-.html</guid></item><item><title>Battling Infectious Diseases: New Book Tells Inside Stories of Disease Fighters </title><description>In his new book, Germ Theory: Medical Pioneers in Infectious Diseases, (ASM Press) Emory infectious disease expert Robert Gaynes, MD, brings to life the stories of a dozen pioneering individuals, from Hippocrates and Avicenna to Paul Ehrlich and Lillian Wald, and the struggles they overcame to have their work accepted.</description><link>http://shared.web.emory.edu/whsc/news/releases/2011/10/battling-infectious-diseases-new-book-tells-inside-stories-of-disease-fighters-.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2011 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">http://shared.web.emory.edu/whsc/news/releases/2011/10/battling-infectious-diseases-new-book-tells-inside-stories-of-disease-fighters-.html</guid></item></channel></rss>