<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Politics News@Emory</title><description>All the latest news from Emory University.</description><link>http://shared.web.emory.edu.xml</link><docs>http://shared.web.emory.edu.xml</docs><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2011 21:06:35 -0400</pubDate><generator>Cascade Server</generator><item><title>Cain, Perry and Romney: What's Next for the Republicans? </title><description>Emory University political scientist Merle Black analyzes the Republican field, discussing whether Herman Cain is a legitimate Republican presidential contender, how he would fare against President Obama in the general election and if Rick Perry still has a chance to be the nominee. </description><link>
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/10/cain-perry-and-romney-whats-next-for-the-republicans.html
				</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2011 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/10/cain-perry-and-romney-whats-next-for-the-republicans.html
				</guid></item><item><title>Cain, Voters and Obama: What to Expect </title><description>Emory University political science professor Andra Gillespie discusses Republican presidential candidate Herman Cain and his  claims that African Americans are "brainwashed," how he would do against President Obama if he was the Republican candidate, and why it will be difficult to get African Americans back to the polls. Gillespie is a specialist in  political mobilization and race, and is the author of the forthcoming book "The New Black Politician: Cory Booker, Newark and the Post-Racial America."</description><link>
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/10/herman-cain-and-obama-and-african-american-voters.html
				</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2011 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/10/herman-cain-and-obama-and-african-american-voters.html
				</guid></item><item><title>Government Shutdown: Emory Experts Say Everybody Loses</title><description>With a potential government shutdown looming at the end of the week, Emory University experts in national politics are available to discuss whether another short-term budget will pass, who benefits or loses, how a shutdown will further damage the approval ratings of Congress and President Obama, and what it may mean for next year's elections.</description><link>
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/09/political-experts-on-government-shutdown.html
				</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2011 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/09/political-experts-on-government-shutdown.html
				</guid></item><item><title>Previewing 2012 Elections: Emory Experts Available</title><description>As the Republican field continues to solidify and polls show President Obama's approval rate dropping, Emory University experts in national politics, the "Tea Party" and partisanship, election forecasting, congressional elections and political mobilization and race are available to preview the 2012 elections.</description><link>
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/09/previewing-2012-elections-emory-experts-available.html
				</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2011 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/09/previewing-2012-elections-emory-experts-available.html
				</guid></item><item><title>Eurozone faces extreme economic challenges, Emory political scientist explains why</title><description>The economic crisis in Europe's Eurozone is worsening, and Emory University political science professor and Europe expert Thomas D. Lancaster says the brunt of the financial burden falls on one country, Germany.</description><link>
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/09/eurozone-economic-challenges-emory-thomas-lancaster-explains.html
				</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2011 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/09/eurozone-economic-challenges-emory-thomas-lancaster-explains.html
				</guid></item><item><title>9/11 Expert: U.S. Foreign Policy, Muslim Attitudes Toward the U.S.</title><description>Law professor Abdullahi An-Na'im is an expert in Islam, Human Rights and Shari'a.  An-Na'im discusses how U.S. foreign policy changed in the wake of 9/11 and how Muslim peoples around the world feel about the U.S.</description><link>
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/08/911-expert-muslim-attitudes-towards-america.html
				</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2011 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/08/911-expert-muslim-attitudes-towards-america.html
				</guid></item><item><title>London Riots Reflect Culminations of Multiple Tensions, Says Emory Political Scientist </title><description>Emory University political science professor Thomas Lancaster says the rioting in London, sparking 500 arrests about much more than the police shooting of a 29-year-old man.</description><link>
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/08/london-riots-reflect-culminations-of-multiple-tensions,-says-emory-political-scientist-.html
				</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2011 13:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/08/london-riots-reflect-culminations-of-multiple-tensions,-says-emory-political-scientist-.html
				</guid></item><item><title>From 'Chaos,' a Budget Deal is Emerging, says Emory Congressional Expert </title><description>The Gang of Six plan demonstrates "the capacity of the American Constitutional system to continue to generate serious proposals to address the complex and politically contentious budget and debt ceiling issues -- even after negotiations led by the president had reached an impasse," says Emory University political scientist Randall Strahan, a Congressional politics expert. </description><link>
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/07/congressional-expert-on-budget-deal.html
				</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2011 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/07/congressional-expert-on-budget-deal.html
				</guid></item><item><title>Economist Recalls When Government Made Things Worse</title><description>Government wrangling over raising the debt ceiling, cutting spending and raising taxes has a familiar ring to Emory University economic historian Leonard Carlson, who says that throughout the nation¿s history, colliding economic philosophies have produced mixed or even negative results.</description><link>
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/07/economist-recalls-when-government-made-things-worse.html
				</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2011 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/07/economist-recalls-when-government-made-things-worse.html
				</guid></item><item><title>Expect a Budget Agreement This Summer but Not a Long-Term Solution, says Strahan</title><description>President Barack Obama is pushing for a budget agreement and Congress canceled its July 4 recess, but don¿t expect the outcome to be a budget deal that sets America back on course, says Emory University political science professor and Congressional politics expert Randy Strahan.</description><link>
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/07/dont-expect-a-long-term-budget-agreement.html
				</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/07/dont-expect-a-long-term-budget-agreement.html
				</guid></item><item><title>Are We Witnessing True Revolutions in N. Africa and the Middle East? | Video</title><description>The news media continues to portray the uprisings in the Middle East and North Africa as revolutions. Is this true? Or are they just upheavals? Emory University Middle East History Professor Ken Stein doesn't believe as much change is happening in the region as we want to believe.</description><link>
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/06/revolutions-in-the-middle-east-and-north-africa.html
				</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2011 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/06/revolutions-in-the-middle-east-and-north-africa.html
				</guid></item><item><title>Israel-Palestine Peace Deal Still Far Off, Says Middle East Expert | Video</title><description>There are still many issues to resolve before the Israel-Palestine Conflict ends. Emory University Israeli Studies Professor Ken Stein says he doesn't expect to see a resolution any time soon. He also says it's a bad idea for an American president to try to force an outcome.</description><link>
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/06/israel-palestine-peace-deal-still-far-off.html
				</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2011 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/06/israel-palestine-peace-deal-still-far-off.html
				</guid></item><item><title>Religion, Local Peacebuilding to be Focus of Emory Conference</title><description>Indian social activist Kiran Bedi will give a public talk on "Contemporary Issues and Practical Solutions" as part of Emory University¿s second "Conference on Religion, Conflict and Peacebuilding" on June 19.</description><link>
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/05/religion-local-peacebuilding-to-be-focus-of-emory-conference.html
				</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2011 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/05/religion-local-peacebuilding-to-be-focus-of-emory-conference.html
				</guid></item><item><title>Islam Requires a Secular State, Says Emory's An-Na'im</title><description>As countries in North Africa take steps toward democratic reform, Emory University law professor and Islam and human rights expert Abdullahi An-Na'im discusses the difficulties ahead, including whether Islamists should be shut out of politics and if Islam and secularism can co-exist.</description><link>
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/05/islam-and-the-secular-state.html
				</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2011 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/05/islam-and-the-secular-state.html
				</guid></item><item><title>Video: The Future of Al Qaeda After bin Laden's Death</title><description>Middle East and Islamic studies professor Vince Cornell believes with the death of Osama bin Laden, we're now seeing the beginning of the end for Al Qaeda.</description><link>
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/05/the-future-of-al-qaeda-after-bin-ladens-death_046.html
				</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2011 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">
					http://shared.web.emory.edu/emory/news/releases/2011/05/the-future-of-al-qaeda-after-bin-ladens-death_046.html
				</guid></item></channel></rss>